<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Endless Adventure | Travel Blog &amp; Daily Vlog</title>
    <description>Hi! We&#39;re Eric and Allison. We quit our full-time jobs and sold everything to travel full-time. We make daily vlogs of our travels and adventures around the world!
</description>
    <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://theendlessadventure.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 15:53:35 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 15:53:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Lessons Learned Riding Amtrak From Canada to New York City</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Eric and I recently booked a trip to Montreal but needed to be in Florida for a cruise the following week. So, naturally we figured we should hit up New York on the way down since we’d be on the East Coast anyway. But the flights were expensive and we didn’t have a car, so that left us with one option: Amtrak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a little digging, we found a train route that cost $69/person and figured what the heck! So now here I am at the end of the train ride, giving you the freshest perspective of train travel across the Canadian border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out that day’s vlog for an up close look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TfmJYdkU1ys&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;boarding-is-surprisingly-quick-and-painless&quot;&gt;Boarding is surprisingly quick and painless&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you arrive at the Gare Centrale station in Montreal, you just head inside, get in line at the gate (it was number 19 for us and clearly marked for New York), flash your ticket as you start boarding, then choose whatever seat you want in the car they point you towards. Don’t worry about printing your ticket either, they can scan it from your phone/mobile device on the train. If you do happen to get lost or confused, the staff at the train station all seemed really nice and spoke English, so don’t hesitate to ask for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-a-really-long-day&quot;&gt;It’s a really long day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train departs at 10:20am, but you should arrive about 30 minutes prior to that time since they start the boarding process a little before 10am. It’s scheduled to arrive in NYC a whopping 10 and a half hours later at 8:50pm. So you know going in that it’s going to be a long day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;border-patrol-is-no-joke&quot;&gt;Border Patrol is no joke!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 2 hours into your ride (right inside the New York state line), Border Patrol boards the train to collect papers, inspect passports and question everyone. If you don’t speak English, appear to be on drugs like the guy behind us, or from aren’t the US, prepare to be asked a lot of questions by stern, highly impatient agents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re really lucky, you’ll get called to the cafe car for what I can only assume is interrogation hell. I’m not sure if this is true for all of these routes, but we literally sat still on the tracks for 2 hours during this process, which leads me to my next lesson learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-will-not-arrive-on-time&quot;&gt;You will not arrive on time.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless somehow every single person on the train has their legal documents perfectly in order, someone will get called to that damn cafe car and your schedule will be shot to hell. We didn’t ended up arriving at Penn Station until 9:45pm, making the day a whopping 12 hours of fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, don’t expect to get any sort of updates during the customs stop. You just sit there on the ugliest strip of tracks you’ll see during the day wondering where the agents took that confused, non-English-speaking, hispanic woman with all of her luggage and if she’ll ever return… Thank goodness the wifi’s working and pretty strong during that part of the trip! In case you’re wondering, the confused hispanic lady returned an hour and a half later and got right back on her tablet like nothing had happened. I have so many questions!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;theres-alcohol-in-the-cafe&quot;&gt;There’s alcohol in the cafe!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it’s not being used as an interrogation room, the cafe car sells food and beverages and has surprising nice booths to sit at. If you plan on getting work done on the train, I highly recommend hunkering down in there. You have plenty of room to spread out and there are far less distractions. We packed our own food so we didn’t end up ordering anything to eat, but we did get some cheap wine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The menu actually seemed somewhat decent. Besides the usual pizzas, sandwiches, and hot dogs they had things like quinoa and spinach salad and even a vegan burger, how progressive! Obviously they got major points from us for serving beer, wine, and liquor :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/drunk-on-the-train.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drunk on the train&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;avoid-the-bathrooms-later-in-the-day&quot;&gt;Avoid the bathrooms later in the day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things the conductor announces when you board is “no one’s going to clean up after you unless you’re riding with your mother, and I’m not your mother”. Oh how true this is. The bathrooms were pretty smelly to begin with but by 7/8pm, the toilet paper’s gone, everyone’s apparently forgotten how to flush and aim, and the floor becomes the new trash can. Seriously, so many people left the bathroom with that embarrassing string of toilet paper stuck to their foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously you can’t hold it for the whole journey, but just try to avoid the bathrooms as much as you can after about 4pm. And whatever you do, please don’t touch that seat with any part of your body! If things get too desperate, put those quads to use and employ the hover method!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-cant-get-off-the-train-until-about-6pm&quot;&gt;You can’t get off the train until about 6pm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For smokers and people who require frequent fresh air, this might be a bit of a challenge for you, but there’s only one stop where passengers are allowed to hop off to stretch their legs and smoke. I can’t remember the exact stop, but it was around 6pm. You can ask the conductors (they were all super nice!) but it’s the station where they do the engine swap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important note for this stop: the power goes off for about 15-20 mins while they switch the engine. For the love of everything holy people, DO NOT USE THE BATHROOM DURING THIS TIME! I didn’t think about it until mid-pee (while hovering of course) but no power = no flushing. Needless to say, I, along with about 5 other people after me either didn’t realize or just didn’t care about that fact. I shudder to think what that poor bathroom went through during that break. If you get stir crazy easily, you can always just walk through the train cars until you get to that station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-views-are-awesome&quot;&gt;The views are awesome!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I actually slept most of the way from Montreal to the US border so I can’t really comment on the first couple hours but once you get into New York, the views are amazing! You travel alongside lakes, canals and rivers pretty much the whole time and see all sorts of quaint little towns, forests and wildlife along the way. We’d always heard that upstate New York was beautiful, and it definitely did not disappoint!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/train-view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Train view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-wifi-is-spotty-at-best&quot;&gt;The wifi is spotty at best&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in some spots, completely unusable. Also, it doesn’t kick in until you cross the border, so the first couple hours are perfect for reading, sleeping (like me!), or playing Sudoku until you can’t possibly stand looking at another number in a box ever again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rouses Point is when the wifi kicks in and you can’t miss it - it’s when they stop and let the lovely Border Patrol agents board. Oh and they say there’s no streaming, but we used spotify and Youtube… so I guess it’s more of a request than a rule?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-cheap&quot;&gt;It’s cheap!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For $69/person, you really can’t beat the price if you’re planning on visiting New York or Montreal! Plus, there aren’t security lines, assigned seats, baggage fees, or TSA agents to deal with!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the train is a fun, affordable experience that you should definitely try once, but probably not more than that. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, consider subscribing to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribing to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 11:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/10-lessons-learned-riding-amtrak-from-canada-to-new-york-city.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/10-lessons-learned-riding-amtrak-from-canada-to-new-york-city.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>budget-travel</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Tips to Travel the World for CHEAP!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You ever said you had to be rich to travel the world? Here are a few tips we’ve learned that will help you travel the world for cheap!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the more visual learners among us, we also made a handy video version of these tips!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3Ji1gd0yUP8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-1---get-a-travel-rewards-card&quot;&gt;Tip #1 - Get a travel rewards card!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t use credit cards for years and really debated getting a new one, but honestly it’s been one of the things we’ve ever done for travel!! We’ve had our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.capitalone.com/credit-cards/venture/&quot;&gt;Capital One Venture Card&lt;/a&gt; for a little over a year now and have already gotten over $3000 in free travel! Seriously, why didn’t we do this sooner?!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pay our bills and put all of our purchases (and sometimes friend’s purchases) on our card, which racks up points super fast. So next time you’re out to dinner, pick up the tab and have everyone &lt;a href=&quot;https://venmo.com/&quot;&gt;Venmo&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/home&quot;&gt;PayPal&lt;/a&gt; you for their portion. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-2--book-a-cruise&quot;&gt;Tip #2- Book a cruise!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, seriously! Most people associate cruises with high-priced vacations, but you can actually find really cheap cruises on sites like &lt;a href=&quot;http://cruisesheet.com/&quot;&gt;Cruisesheet.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cruisedirect.com/&quot;&gt;Cruisedirect.com&lt;/a&gt;. As long as you’re somewhat flexible with dates and the general start and end locations, you can find them for as little as $35-40/day. And that includes food, entertainment, and accommodations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you’re a boozehound like we are, you’ll find that the alcohol packages on cruises are absolutely outrageously priced! Never fear, this video will show you the best technique out there for sneaking liquor on a cruise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bry196a99G8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-3---stop-eating-out&quot;&gt;Tip #3 - Stop eating out!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So… this tip sucks. We love eating out and struggle with this one a lot ourselves. But if you’re on the road and eating out for 2-3 meals a day, plus the cost of coffee, tea, beer or whatever other treats you sneak in there, it adds up super fast! Before you know it, you’ve spent $50-100+ on food and drinks alone for just one day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, make a point to run by a grocery store when you first arrive at your destination. There you can snag all the essentials like coffee, booze, and easy ingredients for homemade meals. Heck, with all the money you’ll save, you might just have enough to book your next vacation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-4---do-free-stuff&quot;&gt;Tip #4 - Do free stuff!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big cities and small towns alike typically take a lot of pride in showing off all that the area has to offer. A quick scan of the city’s website or facebook group in addition to a search on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com/&quot;&gt;TripAdvisor&lt;/a&gt; and literally Googling “free things to do” near our location have led us to some of our most memorable and free adventures!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out this vlog of ours where we had an amazing time exploring an abandoned ghost town without spending a dime! We found this one on TripAdvisor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7WXUgzpnna0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-5---travel-to-cheaper-places&quot;&gt;Tip #5 - Travel to cheaper places!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this one’s kind of a no-brainer and we’re not saying to &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; travel to cheap places. But if you spend a week or two in New York, try offsetting the higher prices by going to a more rural area or less expensive country in general like The Philippines or Croatia. That way you can explore all sorts of countries and cities without breaking the bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love looking at &lt;a href=&quot;https://nomadlist.com/&quot;&gt;Nomadlist.com&lt;/a&gt; to compare the living costs of different places around the world. It definitely helps keep us on budget. Check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-6---use-public-transit-and-bikes-say-no-to-uber-and-lyft&quot;&gt;Tip #6 - Use public transit and bikes, say no to Uber and Lyft!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve biked a lot of cities and always agree that it gives us such a better perspective of the area. Since you’re going at a much slower pace, you really get to soak everything in and see the city and neighborhoods up close. Plus, bike rentals typically cost $10 or less per day. Just make sure you pay attention to the time limits! Some rentals allow for free and unlimited check-outs in a 24 hour period as long as you check your bike back in every 30 minutes. If you’re not diligent with your time, you could end up paying a lot more than you bargained for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those not into biking, buses and trains are super affordable forms of transportation that also force you to jump right in and get to know the layout of a city and the people that inhabit it. Public transit might seem overwhelming at first, but take it slow, read the signs and/or maps and before you know it, you’ll be a public transit pro!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another trick we use to cut down on transportation costs is to book Airbnbs or hostels on the outskirts, but still walking distance, from the areas we’re visiting. You typically get a much cheaper rental rate and pay $0 in transit costs because you’re walking! Plus, you get some extra exercise which is pretty much always a good thing. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, because you’re awesome, &lt;a href=&quot;www.airbnb.com/c/abieller?s=8&quot;&gt;here’s $35 off your first AirBnB&lt;/a&gt;. No joke!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully these tips showed you that you can still take that vacation you’ve been dreaming about without having break the bank or make too many compromises. Have any other travel tips or hacks we should know about? Leave us a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, consider subscribing to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribing to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 15:30:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/6-tips-travel-the-world-for-cheap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/6-tips-travel-the-world-for-cheap.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>budget-travel</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>These White Sand Dunes in New Mexico Will Blow Your Mind</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been sledding in the middle of winter and thought, jeez, this sure is super but I wish it was about 60 degrees warmer out so I wasn’t freezing my ass off and on the verge of losing my extremities to frostbite!!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the dunes at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/whsa/index.htm&quot;&gt;White Sand National Monument&lt;/a&gt; outside of Las Cruces, NM, are your dream come true! It’s a national park with literally 275 sq miles of warm, milky-white sand dunes that you can, and are encouraged to, sled down! Sound too good to be true? Well it’s not and for only $5 you can’t afford not to check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PCoXUeY9aKw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-get-there&quot;&gt;How to get there&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The park is located on Hwy 70 W outside of Alamogordo, NM, but we recommend staying in Las Cruces, NM. It’s a much bigger city with lots of cool stuff to do! As always, we recommend grabbing a room or house on &lt;a href=&quot;www.airbnb.ca/c/abieller?s=8&quot;&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt; during your stay! (FYI: if you use that link, you’ll get $20 toward your reservation, even if it’s not for a NM trip!! Seriously. What are you waiting for?! Book something already! You’re welcome, we love you!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-time-to-visit&quot;&gt;Best time to visit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure, if you go in the middle of summer, the temperature in the park might actually be pretty hot. Like 100+ degrees hot. But as long as you get there in the morning or late afternoon and bring plenty of water, you’re good to go! It’s the desert after all, so temperatures fluctuate dramatically from day to night. If your schedule allows, we actually recommend going in early spring or late fall. The temps are best at those times and the crowds are minimal. We went the very first day of March and it was a perfect 77 degrees out. Plus we had the dunes all to ourselves!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-and-eric-jump-dunes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;allison and eric jumping the dunes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-bring&quot;&gt;What to bring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water and lots of it!&lt;/strong&gt; There’s a gift shop when you enter the park that sells food and beverages, but unfortunately there’s no water provided past the gates. And trust us, running up and down those dunes in the sun will make you really thirsty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunglasses and a hat.&lt;/strong&gt; The white sand, much like white snow, is brutal on the eyes. Plus you’re in the desert, and that sun is mean to foreheads, noses and uncovered body parts. And believe me, you won’t want to be reapplying sunscreen when your hands and face are covered in sand. So just buy a cool hat like I did and only worry about finding the biggest dune to sled down instead of your face melting off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-dunes-hat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Allison at the dunes in her hat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The right clothing. In case you haven’t already figured it out, the park is comprised of sand. Never-ending piles of sand. Sand that can and will make its way into your eyes, hair, pants, shoes, pockets, ears, nose, etc. For that reason, I recommend wearing a tighter pair of underoos or pants to help keep the sand out of you know where. Also, only wear flip flops to get to and from the car. The sand is surprisingly cool and super soft, so set those little piggies free for the day. Plus, I don’t know about you, but I’d much rather have to wipe my feet off and shake of my sandals at the end of the day than try to get sand out of my socks and shoes. :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A sled and wax.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a sled, bring it! If you don’t because you’re in the south and typically have no need for a sled, that’s no problem! You can easily buy a used one at the gift shop for around $15. You could also buy a new one for a few bucks more, but we found that the used ones worked just as well as the new ones, especially with the wax… which I also recommend buying or bringing with you. It makes your ride so much faster and smoother!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of about the gift shop sled is that they’ll buy it back from you for a portion of the price. Just make sure you pay attention to the gift shop hours! We got there about 5 mins after it closed and they literally slammed the door in our face and locked it. Rude! So we left NM with 3 brand new and completely useless sleds…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it. You’re officially prepared for the warmest and sunniest sledding of your life!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, consider subscribing to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribing to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/these-white-sand-dunes-new-mexico-will-blow-your-mind.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/these-white-sand-dunes-new-mexico-will-blow-your-mind.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>vlogs</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Ditch the Clutter and Travel Light</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My husband and I recently left our jobs and apartment in San Francisco to travel the world full time. Most people would agree that we’re living the dream, but full disclosure, it’s way more stressful and complicated than it sounds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we made this decision, obviously we were super pumped up. But once that initial excitement subsided, we started thinking about what full-time travel actually entails and the reality of the situation set in: &lt;em&gt;traveling the world means living out of a small suitcase or backpack…and there’s no way in hell your entire wardrobe, shoes, home gym, straightener, lotions, hair products, and cats will fit!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/the-cats.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cats in apartment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you do? First step, &lt;strong&gt;panic!!!&lt;/strong&gt; Next, take a deep breath (or many short ones into a brown paper bag) and focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tame-the-closet&quot;&gt;Tame the Closet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with your closet. If you’re like me, the majority of your shoes and clothing are sitting there waiting for that one perfect beach day, a birthday picnic in the park or the night when Ryan Gosling invites you to the Academy Awards because he finally realized he’s in love with you totally and eternally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically what I’m saying is, a lot of it is expendable!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you go from hundreds of clothing items to just a few? By thinking practically. Traveling means a lot of walking around in new cities and airports so you’ll need comfortable and sturdy shoes that can handle the elements - dirt, rain, city streets, swelling feet, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choosing-your-footwear&quot;&gt;Choosing Your Footwear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people think comfortable = boring, but I disagree! For example, I went with a pair of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nike.com/us/en_us/c/innovation/free&quot;&gt;Nike Frees&lt;/a&gt; which are super lightweight, come in a bunch of different styles, and are perfect for workouts, travel days, hiking, city exploring, and lazy days working in coffee shops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-hike-nike.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Allison hiking in nikes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flip flops are must-haves for showers and pool days, but can also be the perfect footwear for a warm day. In addition, I also recommend a pair of nicer, lightweight shoes (like these &lt;a href=&quot;http://oldnavy.gap.com/browse/product.do?vid=1&amp;amp;pid=597731002&quot;&gt;black flats&lt;/a&gt; for gals or these basic &lt;a href=&quot;http://oldnavy.gap.com/browse/product.do?cid=37844&amp;amp;vid=1&amp;amp;pid=780357012&quot;&gt;boots&lt;/a&gt; for fellas) that can be easily dressed for the occasional nice meal out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on how much space you have, a pair of rain boots is also really nice to have (as I sit here writing on a rainy day in Montreal, wearing my soaking wet tennis shoes). Weight is always a factor, but apparently rain boots are super &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bogsfootwear.ca/shop/style/71287.html&quot;&gt;lightweight&lt;/a&gt; these days! So there you have it - style, comfort, and minimalism all in one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choosing-your-clothing&quot;&gt;Choosing Your Clothing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to clothing, think about the different climates you’ll be in and go from there. Let’s assume you’re like me and traveling indefinitely across all different climates, since that’s the hardest kind of travel to prepare for in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there’s an easy secret: &lt;strong&gt;basics and layers&lt;/strong&gt;. Get a couple pairs of pants and/or jeans, shorts, and skirts that can easily be dressed up or down and don’t wrinkle easily. Match these with the majority of your tops and voila! Your bottom half is literally covered!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I picked out all the bottoms I wanted and then grabbed tops that I could mix easily with them. For both guys and gals, solid and striped tops specifically are great because they can go with anything! If you plan on doing a lot of Instagramming while on the road and are worried about always wearing the same thing, I can assure you that people will notice a patterned top a lot faster than a basic tee. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To maximize warmth and minimize load, invest in a couple long-sleeved thermal tops and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.backcountry.com/Store/catalog/search.jsp?s=u&amp;amp;q=3+in+1+jacket&quot;&gt;3-in-1 jacket&lt;/a&gt; to keep you covered in all climates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choosing-your-accessories-and-toiletries&quot;&gt;Choosing Your Accessories and Toiletries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, now that your clothing’s settled, everything else is a piece of cake! For those who do it all - moisturize, exfoliate, tweeze, style, wax - you might have a hard time at first, but like I mentioned earlier, just think about the necessities. You can always buy things like face masks and extra razor heads on the road, so start out with small quantities and leave your bubble bath at home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that I highly recommend to help cut down on space are two in one shampoos/conditioners and a moisturizer that works for your face and body - I have super combination dry/oily skin and am in love with this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/solutions-Sweet-Almond-Moisturizing-ounce/dp/B0019LVFSU/ref=sr_1_3_a_it?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1459461866&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;keywords=almond+oil&quot;&gt;almond oil&lt;/a&gt; as a head-to-toe moisturizer. Also, I cannot say enough great things about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drbronner.com/DBMS/category/LIQUIDSOAP.html&quot;&gt;Dr. Bronner’s Pure Castille Soap&lt;/a&gt;! It’s literally our body wash, face wash, shaving cream, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; laundry detergent all in one, plus it’s made with ethically-sourced, certified fair trade ingredients! It’s the stuff minimalist and hipster dreams are made of!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re flying a lot and not checking a bag, an easy trick is to buy normal sized bottles of everything and then divide the contents into smaller, travel-approved bottles. Not only are you saving money by buying the regular size, but you also won’t run out of your necessities as quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to your shampoo and soap, things I highly recommend having in your bathroom pack are tweezers, nail clippers with a built in file, ibuprofen, bandaids, a small tube of antibiotic cream, ear plugs and visine for travel days. I know it sounds like a lot, but they’re all really small items that can easily be shoved in a corner, pocket, or small toiletry bag and really pay off while on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width: 65%; margin: 0px auto;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/ally-packed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ally packed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it! After 5 months of living out of a backpack, these are the tips, tricks, and essentials I’ve found that’ll take the stress out of packing without compromising on style and hygiene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have any great packing tips or recommendations? Let us know!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow along on our journey by subscribing to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or by &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribing to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-ditch-the-clutter-and-travel-light.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-ditch-the-clutter-and-travel-light.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>minimalism</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Photos from Driving 10,000 Miles Across the US in 3 Months.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When we left our home in San Francisco, we weren’t sure where the road was going to take us, but we were dying to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we decided officially that we wanted to sell all of our posessions and live a nomadic lifstyle, we wanted to dip our toes in the water a bit. So, we decided to take an epic 3 month roadtrip around the country so we could get a taste of what it was really like to live out of a backpack and to travel full-time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/road-trip-map.png&quot; alt=&quot;route across the usa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our trip took us all around this huge country of ours. We met some amazing people and had experiences that we’ll take with us forever. We shucked oysters with the locals in Mississippi, cooked ribeye steaks with bonifide cowboys in Bandera, TX, snuck into an abandoned ghost town, and peered over the edge of the greatest expanse in the world, the Grand Canyon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/ally-grand-canyon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ally at grand canyon&quot; /&gt;
The Grand Canyon has to be seen to be believed. Peering over the edge and looking 6000 ft down just might change your life. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QQTUyZF_1f0&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/texas-sunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset in texas&quot; /&gt;
We spent a lot of time in Texas and the sunsets never disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-eric-big-bend.png&quot; alt=&quot;Big bend&quot; /&gt;
The beauty and epicness of Big Bend is hard to put into words. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fr3DnW5qyXE&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-sutro-baths-san-francisco.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sutro baths&quot; /&gt;
These once vibrant bath houses in west San Francisco have been reduced to ruins over the years. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=omOho20_RtQ&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/on-the-road.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;empty road&quot; /&gt;
The roads seem to go on forever over in western Texas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dunes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sand dunes&quot; /&gt;
These huge white sand dunes in New Mexico seem to come out of nowhere! Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PCoXUeY9aKw&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/prada-marfa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;prada store&quot; /&gt;
This random Prada store sits outside of Marfa, TX, literally in the middle of the desert. So strange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/beads.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mardi gras beads&quot; /&gt;
The aftermath of mardi gras in Baton Rouge, LA. It was an amazing party, but you wouldn’t believe the mess these people left behind! Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iM4zqlxLzEw&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/stone-mountain.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rock in atlanta&quot; /&gt;
This huge rock sits just outside of Atlanta, GA and offers the most incredible view of the city and surrounding areas. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k7ajq61CuRE&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/nyc-view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;looking out at new york view&quot; /&gt;
The island of Manhattan is so photogenic. This was taken from the base of the Statue of Liberty, which offered some of the best views. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UMWr6azqyOw&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our road trip might be over but the adventure is just beginning! We’re heading over to Europe for the next few months, then we’ll slowly make our way over to southeast Asia. It’s going to be an amazing year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow along on our journey by subscribing to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or by &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribing to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/5-10-photos-driving-5000-miles-across-usa-3-months.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/5-10-photos-driving-5000-miles-across-usa-3-months.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>road-trip</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 5 Best Coffee Shops to Work From in Austin, TX</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Austin, TX is an amazing town that’s known for great music, clean air and amazing barbecue. We’ve visited quite a few times and have slowly developed an affinity for this place. We wanted to see what it would be like to actually live and work there, so Allison and I decided to spend a week there working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t have any specific places in mind when we showed up, but instead wanted to just play it by ear and migrate from coffee shop to coffee shop each day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after a week working remote from Austin, here are the best coffee shops we found:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cenote&quot;&gt;Cenote&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/cenote.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;cenote coffee shop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though we were unable to decipher it’s proper pronunciation, we found Cenote to be a great place to set up camp and get shit done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This place has a great vibe and energy. Like many places in Austin, it was once a house but has since been transformed into a coffee shop, which gives it a nice homey vibe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a bit crowded when we arrived just before noon on a Thursday, but there’s plenty of seating so we didn’t have a hard time finding a spot to hunker down. They also had a small area where you could stand and work if you prefer.
I had a chance to try their latte, and it was super delicious. I only wish I had the time (and the caffeine tolerance) to try their whole menu! They’ve also got a little juice vendor outside on the patio. I didn’t get a chance to try it but they were plenty busy so I’m guessing I missed out on something tasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outlet wise, Cenote had us covered. Everywhere we sat we were able to find an outlet nearby. Once we were juiced up to 100%, we’d step outside for a little while just to change things up a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom line:&lt;/strong&gt; With tons of seating, great coffee and outlets-o-plenty, you’d be missing out big time if you didn’t check out Cenote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wright-brothers-brew-and-brew&quot;&gt;Wright Brothers Brew and Brew&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/wright-brothers.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;wright brothers coffee shop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending some time at Cenote, we decided it was time for a change of scenery, so we walked up a few blocks to Wright Bros Brew &amp;amp; Brew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The outside wasn’t much to look at but when we walked in we were immediately impressed with the overall vibe and decor. There’s a great industrial feel with a sort of rustic look. They’re even attached to a super cool record store, which I highly recommending browsing through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was also happy to find that there were a decent amount of power outlets as well as plenty of seating. They had tall tables as well which are great for standing, if you were so inclined (see what I did there?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But my favorite thing about Brew and Brew was the super simple beer guide. All beers are arranged on a grid, top right is dark and hoppy, bottom left is light and less hoppy. This made it super easy to find something that we liked.
I also had a chance to snag a mocha before beer thirty, which I found pretty tasty. I’d love the chance to sample more of their menu, but my initial impression was a positive one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their food options were fairly light, but surprisingly they allow you to bring in your own food from outside. I actually noticed this same phenomenon at a couple of other places in Austin as well, maybe it’s a trend?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom line:&lt;/strong&gt; Brew and Brew is a legit spot for coffee lovers and hard core remote workers. Inside you’ll find plenty of outlets, tables you can stand at and a great selection of beers. Unfortunately there’s no patio and the outside is a bit lack luster, but the unique decor and positive vibe on the inside make it a great place to get stuff done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-buzzmill&quot;&gt;The Buzzmill&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/buzzmill.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;buzzmill coffee shop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Buzzmill is a great coffee shop, bar and barbecue joint, just across the river off East Riverside Dr. This place has everything a remote worker could need. In fact, we ended up spending the entire day there!
Inside you’ll find a ton of seating and a super chill vibe. The decor really was amazing. I sometimes found myself just admiring the artwork and random items strewn about. There’s even a quiet section where you can focus without loud talking or music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside you’ll find a ton of seating as well as a few power outlets so you can stay juiced up. There are also a couple of food vendors. We tried the barbecue and it was pretty superb. At night, this area transforms into a bar with great drinks and a live band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sound awesome so far? Well I haven’t even gotten to the best part. They have a 3 hour long happy hour from 5–8, and guess what’s on the menu. $1 PBR! You have to be careful though. At that price you might drink enough to be transformed into a true Austin hipster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh, and did I mention it’s open 24 hours? I don’t even know how that’s possible! Seriously, this place has everything. If you’re in Austin, you’ve gotta check out Buzzmill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom line:&lt;/strong&gt; With decent coffee, tons of seating, and a quiet study hall, Buzzmill is a remote workers paradise. Throw in $1 PBR and amazing barbecue in the backyard, what more could you need?
Cenote&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cafe-medici&quot;&gt;Cafe Medici&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/medici.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;cafe medici coffee shop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After spending a few days in east Austin, we headed downtown to find some more great places to work. We eventually found ourselves at Cafe Medici. And while it had a different vibe than the quaint coffee shops of east Austin, it still had a charm all it’s own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inside felt very modern and well put together and there were more than enough tables to go around. I was also very happy to see tons of counter space, which is really important if you’re like me and prefer standing while you work. There’s also an upper level with tons more seating as well as a small patio area out front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had heard great things about their coffee, but at this point in the day we were already wired, so we opted for sparkling water and juice. Next time we’ll definitely have to give the java a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom line:&lt;/strong&gt; Cafe Medici has a super polished interior with tons of seating and plenty of counters for standing. Overall it’s a top notch place for digital nomads to get some work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;juan-pelota&quot;&gt;Juan Pelota&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/juan.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;juan pelota coffee shop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Juan Pelota is a bike / coffee shop hybrid, created and owned by Lance Armstrong. Oh, and if you didn’t already make the connection, the name is an homage to Lance’s missing testicle. True story, I swear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testicles aside, we were really impressed with this coffee shop. Like Brew and Brew, they allow you to bring in outside food. In fact, they even recommended it! Their food selection is sort of sparse, so they advised us to grab something from the grocery store across the street and bring it in. On a side note, the store was a great little place with tons of organic options called Royal Blue Grocery, definitely check it out if you’re in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t say there was a ton of seating, but luckily it wasn’t too crowded so we didn’t have a hard time grabbing a spot. We found some tables in the back that had outlets built into the benches, which is super convenient and a huge plus imo. Other than that, outlets seemed to be fairly sparse. There were also some tables outside, which is always nice for when you’re feeling cooped up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bottom line:&lt;/strong&gt; While “Juan Pelota” may be a reference to Lance Armstrong’s missing testicle, don’t let the name fool you. This is actually a legit place to get some real work done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s my list of the best coffee shops for remote working in Austin, TX. What do you think? Do you agree with my choices? Know of any other great coffee shops I missed out on? Leave me a note or hit me up on Twitter!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@ericbieller/the-5-best-coffee-shops-to-work-remotely-from-in-austin-tx-c1cd235c60e0#.46mn8lg2b&quot;&gt;A version of this article&lt;/a&gt; originally appeared on Medium.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2016 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/remote-working/5-best-coffee-shops-to-work-from-remotely-austin-texas.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/remote-working/5-best-coffee-shops-to-work-from-remotely-austin-texas.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>remote-working</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>remote-working</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Travel Bloggers You Should be Following</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you looking for your daily dose of wanderlust? Well, here are a few of our favorite travel bloggers who will inspire you to drop everything and book a trip immediately!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dangerous-business.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A Dangerous Business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dangerous-business.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a dangerous business travel vlog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amanda teaches you that you don’t need to quit your job to travel the world. Since 2010 she’s been traveling and blogging about her amazing adventures and she didn’t leave her day job or “normal” life to do it. In between travels, she takes time to unwind at home, sleep in her own bed and spend time with her kitty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theblondeabroad.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Blonde Abroad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/The-Blonde-Abroad.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Blonde Abroad Travel Blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kiersten left behind her career in corporate finance to travel full-time. She’s got an impressive 50 countries under her belt as well as some amazing adventures. Head over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://theblondeabroad.com&quot;&gt;her blog&lt;/a&gt; for some amazing travel stories! &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instagram.com/theblondeabroad&quot;&gt;Her Instagram&lt;/a&gt; is also on point but beware, it’ll cause some serious wanderlust!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.noplacetobe.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;No Place to Be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/no-place-to-be.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;no place to be travel blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poi and Kirsty have called many countries home from Thailand to Austria and now Romania, and they’ve traveled to dozens of others. Follow along on their travels and they’ll inspire you to start living life on your own terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://thegofever.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The Go Fever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/the-go-fever.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Go Fever Travel Blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catherine is an amazing writer and travel junkie. She’s visited tons of exotic places across the globe like Belize, Jordan and Croatia, just to name a few. On her blog, she shares travel stories as well as the best travel tips she’s picked up along the way. Definitely a great travel blog to follow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findingtheuniverse.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Finding the Universe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/finding-the-universe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;finding the universe travel blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laurence and Jessica write all about their travels across the world, but their main focus is their photography. Follow their blog for some wanderlust inducing photos and fun travel stories. And be sure to follow them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/lozula/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; for some epic travel photography!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;——&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been following these travel bloggers for a while now and they have been huge inspirations for us in planning our travels and adventures. We definitely hope that they’ll do the same for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/5-travel-bloggers-you-should-be-following.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/5-travel-bloggers-you-should-be-following.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>blogging</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travel Vlog: Exploring the Sutro Bath Ruins in San Francisco</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Who’s up for a swim? Well, back in 1896, the Sutro Baths were the place to be for the water inclined among us. Now, the ruins are all that’s left of this once popular and vibrant bath house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/omOho20_RtQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baths are located out near the northwestern tip of the San Francisco peninsula, nestled at the bottom of a large beach inlet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you first lay eyes on the ruins, it’s from the top looking down. The view is as beautiful as it is bizarre. Looking at pictures of the facility back in it’s hay day, it’s hard to imagine this vibrant glass house enclosing happy kids and families swimming around having the times of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-sutro-baths-san-francisco.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;allison at sutro baths san francisco&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During high tide, ocean water would literally spill over into the baths, filling the pools. During low tide, there was a powerful turbine pump that would send 6,000 gallons a minute into the baths. At the time, it was the world’s largest indoor swimming facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baths were officially closed down in the 60’s. Ironically, the facility burned down in 1966. Luckily it had been officially closed down shortly before catching fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re visiting San Francisco, do yourself a favor and take a trip to the Sutro Baths. The area is free and open to the public and there weren’t many roped off areas so you’re free to explore the bulk of the ruins.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/travel-vlog-exploring-sutro-bath-ruins-san-francisco.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/travel-vlog-exploring-sutro-bath-ruins-san-francisco.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>vlogging</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Become a Travel Vlogger</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So you want to be a travel vlogger, ay? I’m not surprised. I mean, who wouldn’t want to travel to exotic destinations, vlog their adventures and have millions of viewers wanderlust over their travels. It sounds like a dream life, but don’t be fooled, travel vlogging is hard work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is, you don’t have to quit your job and sell all your possessions &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot;&gt;like we did&lt;/a&gt; in order to become a travel vlogger. Don’t get me wrong, minimalism is amazing and a worthy pursuit, but it’s not required in order to live a life of travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where the heck do you even start? What if you have a full time job? What gear do you need?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;incorporate-travel-into-your-life&quot;&gt;Incorporate travel into your life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people talk about “travel”, they are usually referring to expensive excursions thousands of miles away from your home. But there’s no rule that says you have to go far away from your home in order to travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step to a successful travel vlog is finding ways to travel, even to places that are close to home. You can visit parks, check out art galleries, take a train to a nearby city or drive to a neighboring state for a weekend excursion. Just make sure you’re getting out there! The audience wants to see a great story and you don’t have to travel thousands of miles to tell it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since most of us don’t have an unlimited budget, it’s important to keep your travels and activities cheap. Search Google for free things to do in your area or check our Groupon for cheap deals on fun activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;just-start-filming&quot;&gt;Just start filming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any time a vlogger asks us where they should start, we always say the same thing, just start filming. It doesn’t matter if you’re hanging around your house talking about your upcoming travel plans or bringing the camera along while you visit a park with your family. The only way to learn how to vlog is to start making mistakes so you can learn from them. And the only way to do that is to pop the camera out and start filming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me, once you overcome this initial hurdle, vlogging will become easier and easier. Eventually it will be second nature! So grab the camera, get out of the house and start creating videos you crazy creative creature!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-not-about-the-gear&quot;&gt;It’s not about the gear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vlogging is about 10% equipment and 90% story. Don’t waste your money by dumping it into expensive cameras and audio equipment. If people end up watching your vlog, it will be because of the great story you’re telling and the creative ways you tell it, not because your video was shot in 4k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Canon-PowerShot-ELPH-160-Silver/dp/B00RKNMORM/ref=sr_1_5?s=photo&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1457768026&amp;amp;sr=1-5&amp;amp;keywords=canon+powershot&quot;&gt;Here’s a simple little camera&lt;/a&gt; that is great for a beginner vlogger. If you can’t afford to buy a new camera, you can just use your smartphone. The camera on modern smartphones rival most entry level cameras anyways!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst thing you can do is sink a bunch of money into this new hobby only to find out it isn’t for you. Don’t make that mistake! Once you’ve built up some momentum and have gotten the hang of vlogging, having nicer equipment can give the vlog a polished feeling and make it feel more solid. But don’t jump the gun. Better equipment will only make your vlog marginally better. It’s the story that counts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started vlogging on a used Canon G7X, then eventually upgraded to a Sony a6000, which we also bought used. Check out one of our recent vlogs to get an idea of the quality you can produce with it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fr3DnW5qyXE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-do-it-for-the-money&quot;&gt;Don’t do it for the money&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because there is no money. Period. Not for the foreseeable future anyways. It will take a crap ton of blood, sweat, tears and time (a whole lotta time) before you develop a large enough audience to make a decent profit. Even with 100,000 video views, you’ll only make an estimated $100-$300 profit. Getting the picture?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start your travel vlog because you’re passionate about travel and want to inspire others to travel more. Try to have fun with it. If you’re not having fun, then vlogging might not be for you! Maybe try golf?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;connect-with-other-travelers&quot;&gt;Connect with other travelers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing you can do as a beginner travel vlogger is to connect with other travelers. Meeting other like minded people, whether online or in person, will help you feel like you’re not alone in this travel game. They can also be a great source of inspiration and drive you to keep traveling yourself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram and Twitter are great resources for connecting with other travelers. We’ve already met so many great people through these networks! We also make a point to interact with other YouTubers who have travel focused channels. It’s like having a bit of a support group and is a great way to find other YouTubers to collaborate with. Speaking of collaborating, it’s a hugely effective way to grow your subscribers. Keep in mind, though, that this usually only works with channels that have similar subscriber counts as yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully these tips help you get off on the right foot with your travel vlog. The most important thing of all, though, is to make sure you have passion. If you’re not passionate about travel, it will show through in your videos and you’ll likely not be able to keep up with vlogging anyways because you’ll get burnt out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you think travel vlogging might be your calling, don’t be afraid to get out there and start filming. The first step is just turning the camera on and heading out on an adventure! Don’t wait until tomorrow, start vlogging right now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks a lot for reading. I really hope it was helpful! If you’d like to check out our vlog, head over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCEDrRCC0qRtPd5-sSa1hajw&quot;&gt;our YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt;. We’re currently traveling the world and posting daily vlogs of our adventures. We’d love for you to come along with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-become-a-travel-vlogger.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-become-a-travel-vlogger.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>vlogging</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why West Texas Should Be Your Next Vacation Destination</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Teepees, cowboys, unexplainable lights in the sky, and some of the best views of your life are just a few of the amazing things west Texas has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until recently, all I knew about west Texas was that it comprised about half of the state and that El Paso was somewhere out there. I even lived in south Texas for a few years (shout out to the Rio Grande Valley!) and have visited Texas least once a year for the past 10 years and never once made it out past San Antonio. What the west might be missing in big cities, shopping malls or gas stations, it more than makes up for with quirky small towns, beautiful scenery and amazing photo ops!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, if you’re heading to west Texas, you’ll need a car. I recommend flying into San Antonio or Austin and renting a car from there. But before you leave, you should probably spend at least a day in middle Texas drinking wine in the hill country [[link to our pic/post pic?]] and eating some delicious BBQ and Tex-Mex. I could (and probably should) write a whole post on the Austin area because I love it so dang much…but for now, back to west Texas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/wine-country.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;allison and eric drinking wine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so now that you have your car and a full, I repeat a FULL, tank of gas (gas stations are few and far between out there), pop on your shades, hop on I-90, and experience the awesomeness of 80mph speed limits. Oh and make sure you have plenty of daylight when you leave, because you’re not going to want to miss this amazing scenery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/texas-sunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Texas Sunset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bandera&quot;&gt;Bandera&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so Bandera probably isn’t considered true “west Texas”, but it’s definitely a good start for your journey. The self-proclaimed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.banderacowboycapital.com/&quot;&gt;Cowboy Capital of the World&lt;/a&gt;, the freakin world!!, is definitely the most authentic and adorable town. In Bandera, the deer roam freely, the beer is cheap, and the smokey bars are filled with denim-clad cowboys, live music, and line dancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/s/Bandera--TX--United-States?guests=&amp;amp;checkin=&amp;amp;checkout=&amp;amp;ss_id=8s3f81ph&amp;amp;source=bb&amp;amp;s_tag=Ykvqc6ni&quot;&gt;The Airbnb&lt;/a&gt; selection is also on point and super affordable. If you want to a truly authentic experience, go horseback riding at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.juniperhillstables.com/&quot;&gt;Juniper Hill Stables&lt;/a&gt; like we did or spend a day on a dude ranch if you want a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.banderacowboycapital.com/contents.cfm?pg=places_ranches&quot;&gt;more immersive experience&lt;/a&gt; and then head to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.11thstreetcowboybar.com/&quot;&gt;11th Street Cowboy Bar&lt;/a&gt; on a Wednesday night to grill your own meat in the company of some truly fascinating Texans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/horse-trail-ride.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;horse trail ride&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;marfa&quot;&gt;Marfa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If cowboys aren’t really your thing, then your first west Texas stop should definitely be Marfa, TX. The best way to explain Marfa is to imagine an abandoned desert town that’s been taken over by hipsters and filled with random art galleries, delicious food, sketchy bars, and great coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously, this town it’s worth the drive alone! While you’re there, grab lunch at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foodsharkmarfa.com/&quot;&gt;Food Shark&lt;/a&gt; where super famous people like Beyonce and myself have frequented. Then walk through the town (it’s a short and flat walk, I promise) and marvel at all the random museums and galleries. After your stroll, drive about 20 mins down the road to Valentine, TX and take a pic at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prada_Marfa&quot;&gt;Prada Marfa&lt;/a&gt; so you can be as cool as me and Beyoncé. Then head back towards Alpine at sunset to check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visitmarfa.com/lights.php#.VtkgAJMrL-Y&quot;&gt;Marfa lights&lt;/a&gt;. I seriously couldn’t have fabricated a stranger, more perfect town than Marfa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/prada-marfa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;prada marfa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our travel vlog of our day in Marfa to get a good feel for the town :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uKAHpidcv7Q&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan ahead and have a little leeway with your budget, I highly recommend staying in a teepee or trailer at &lt;a href=&quot;http://elcosmico.com/&quot;&gt;Marfa’s El Cosmico&lt;/a&gt; campground - it’ll definitely give you the most authentic experience. Or if you’re like me and can’t seem to plan anything more than a couple weeks in advance, then definitely look for airbnbs in either &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/s/Marfa--TX--United-States?guests=&amp;amp;checkin=&amp;amp;checkout=&amp;amp;ss_id=3sy3sww9&amp;amp;source=bb&amp;amp;s_tag=l19obG27&quot;&gt;Marfa&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/s/alpine--TX--United-States?checkin=&amp;amp;checkout=&amp;amp;guests=&amp;amp;ss_id=0i6k6svk&amp;amp;s_tag=ZEnmtN4i&quot;&gt;Alpine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;big-bend&quot;&gt;Big Bend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a day or two of getting some of the strangest instagram pics around Marfa, it’s time to pack up and head south for some &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/adventures/travel-vlog-hiking-big-bend-the-greatest-view-of-our-lives.html&quot;&gt;mind-blowing views in Big Bend&lt;/a&gt;. I unfortunately only had time for a quick day hike there, but you could easily spend a week or weeks in the area!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a quick day trip, you should definitely check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.texashiking.com/Locations/ShowLocation.aspx?LocationID=1403&quot;&gt;Lost Mine Trail&lt;/a&gt; and just try to keep your jaw from dropping as you climb higher and higher. Pro tip: make sure to climb up one of the huge rocks at the top for the ultimate 360 views!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-cliff-big-bend.png&quot; alt=&quot;Allison cliff big bend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have more time there, definitely check out several hiking trails and kayak, canoe, and/or raft the river. And if you’re super adventurous/masochistic with time and money to burn, you can do up to a 21 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bigbendrivertours.com/7to21day.html&quot;&gt;day guided river tour&lt;/a&gt; covering the entire 231 miles of the river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our epic vlog of our hike to the top of Big Bend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;415&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fr3DnW5qyXE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;terlingua&quot;&gt;Terlingua&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either on your way in or out of Big Bend, you have to stop in Terlingua at least for a day to check out the remains of the Chisos Mining Company. Or if you’re like me and don’t necessarily love camping, it could also be your home base while you’re exploring Big Bend. Literally referred to as &lt;a href=&quot;http://ghosttowntexas.com/&quot;&gt;Ghost Town Texas&lt;/a&gt;, Terlingua is a fascinating glimpse into what old mining towns looked like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part is that unlike most ghost towns I’ve come across, this one is completely open and free, so explore and poke around the ruins to your heart’s desire! But watch out, I hear that some people have decided to go off the grid and have taken up residence in some of the old mining entrances and structures, so it’s probably best to do your exploring in the daylight. Then at sunset, head on over to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thestarlighttheatre.com/&quot;&gt;Starlight Theater&lt;/a&gt; for some yummy and unique grub, live music, and a drink (or several) with the locals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it! The ultimate guide to the least talked about, yet potentially most interesting part of Texas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been out to west Texas? What was your favorite part? We’d love to hear about it! Leave a comment below or shout out to us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/why-west-texas-should-be-your-next-vacation-destination.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/why-west-texas-should-be-your-next-vacation-destination.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
