<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Endless Adventure | Travel Blog &amp; Daily Vlog</title>
    <description>Hi! We&#39;re Eric and Allison. We quit our full-time jobs and sold everything to travel full-time. We make daily vlogs of our travels and feature travel tips, hacks and photography.
</description>
    <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://theendlessadventure.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 16:48:50 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2016 16:48:50 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Find the Perfect Airbnb</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It used to be that when traveling, you had two options: A private but overpriced and sterile hotel room with the potential bonus of bedbugs OR no privacy at all in a cheap, possibly sketchy hostel with the potential bonus of waking up to your bag having been stolen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But those days are officially over! No more questionable stains on your bed sheets or wearing flip flops in the shower!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You now have the option to stay anywhere from homes, studios, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/wishlists/stay-in-a-castle&quot;&gt;castles&lt;/a&gt;, even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/12735111&quot;&gt;this thing&lt;/a&gt;! You can have as much privacy as you want at a price tag that fits your budget. Sound too good to be true? Well it’s not and it’s amazing! Airbnb gives you the charm of living like a local without having to compromise on amenities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AND, with this &lt;a href=&quot;www.airbnb.com/c/abieller&quot;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; you get $30 off your first booking! Discounts and a better vacation? Miracles do happen!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re only staying in an area for few days, you may not need to be super picky with your space. But if you’re like us and doing more long-term stays (like a week or more), being a little picky can make all the difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust us. We’ve stayed in 50+ Airbnbs and have become booking pros!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start your search by using Airbnb’s first round of filters: set your desired location, date and price range and choose a private room vs. entire apt/home. But don’t stop there!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you need wifi? Linens and towels? Free parking? Would you prefer a washing machine and a dishwasher? Want to bring your pet along? Have a specific neighborhood in mind? There’s a filter for all of those too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/airbnb-tips/filters.png&quot; alt=&quot;airbnb filters&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let’s say you’ve added all of your desired filters and have found a few potential candidates.. How do you choose the winner?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;look-through-the-pictures&quot;&gt;Look through the pictures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can typically immediately discard several options based on the decor. Not everyone’s into older buildings with hardwood floors and quirky features like us and that’s okay! Find the places that look most appealing to you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to giving you an overall vibe of the space, pictures can tell you a lot about the listing. For example, that “full bed” listed may actually be an air mattress, futon, or pull out sofa which may not be what you’re looking for. Also, maybe the shower is teeny tiny and you’re 6+ft tall. &lt;em&gt;No bueno.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really examine the pictures to help ensure there won’t be any surprises when you arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;read-the-reviews&quot;&gt;Read the reviews&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since reviews aren’t anonymous, people tend to be a bit nicer with them than they should be. This means sometimes you have to read between the lines. If you notice a lot of people saying things like “The room was great, but the street was a bit noisy - nothing earplugs won’t solve!” or “The apartment was charming, but a bit more cramped than the pictures let on…” it could be an indicator of bigger, potentially deal-breaking issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading reviews is almost always my deciding factor when booking. I’ve looked at quite a few listings that seemed great, but upon reading the reviews I realize that they’re a hard no. Our biggest red flags are low scores on cleanliness and location and multiple last minute cancellations by the host - because nobody likes getting dumped!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s usually easy to spot any major issues right off the bat, but reading the reviews will definitely give you invaluable, first-hand info.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-a-feel-for-public-transportation-options-near-your-airbnb&quot;&gt;Get a feel for public transportation options near your Airbnb&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we started taking this into account, we’d often book a place based more on price than location. While it felt good to save money in booking fees, it sometimes meant that we’d pay the difference and then some in transportation costs. Not to mention the hours we’d waste sitting on trains each way. Plus, if your space is far from public transportation, you’ll either end up lugging your bags much further or having to pay for cabs rides to and from the airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since you won’t know the exact address of your space until you book, try mapping from nearby cross-streets. Having a general idea of how much and how long transportation will be will help you make the most out of your stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;book-in-weekly-increments&quot;&gt;Book in weekly increments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is especially helpful if budget is a big factor. The majority of Airbnbs offer a pretty good discount if you book for a full week and even bigger discounts for the entire month. We’ve personally saved hundreds in booking fees simply by staying 7 days instead of 5-6!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So make sure you try tweaking the dates before you write a place off. Who knows, your ideal Airbnb might suddenly drop down into your price range and you’ll have an extra day or two to put off packing. Winning!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;always-over-communicate&quot;&gt;Always over-communicate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you found what seems like a great listing, but it’s brand new and there aren’t any reviews or pictures of the room. Or maybe you’re arriving late at night and aren’t sure if the host is flexible with check-in times. Reaching out to confirm these details will help put your mind at ease. Plus it’ll potentially give the host a gentle nudge to update their listing for future guests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reasons you should reach out to your host before booking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To coordinate check-in and check-out times (especially when they’re early or late)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you have a member of your party who won’t be staying the entire time to ensure you don’t overpay (since you sometimes pay extra when more than one to two people stay)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To see if there’s public transportation nearby&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To clarify house rules and amenities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, Airbnb is a wonderful tool and a huge reason we’re able to travel so comfortably on a budget. We know that staying in someone’s home may seem awkward at first, but with these tips, you may end up feeling even more at home than you do on your own couch!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are links to some of our most favorite Airbnbs we’ve stayed in from around the world:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/9979938&quot;&gt;Los Angeles, CA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/8442302&quot;&gt;Twentynince Palms, CA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/9131443&quot;&gt;Austin, TX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/7622094&quot;&gt;Dallas, TX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/6166415&quot;&gt;Houson, TX&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/7708619&quot;&gt;Alpine, TX&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/5617722&quot;&gt;Bandera, TX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/7400644&quot;&gt;Las Cruces, NM&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/8761622&quot;&gt;Pensacola, FL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/12130302&quot;&gt;Tampa, FL&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/2918639&quot;&gt;Bay St. Louis, MS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/7195113&quot;&gt;Point Marion, PA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/12986936&quot;&gt;Marseille, France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/6641049&quot;&gt;Bordeaux, France&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/7161074&quot;&gt;Brussels, Belgium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/12214809&quot;&gt;Milan, Italy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/8504194&quot;&gt;Munich, Germany&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/1152798&quot;&gt;Budapest, Hungary&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/3761912&quot;&gt;Prague, Czech Republic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/rooms/2792346&quot;&gt;Mexico City, Mexico&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have any awesome Airbnb tips to share? Let us know in the comments below or reach out to us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;! And if you end up booking an Airbnb for the first time, tell us how it goes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wondering what The Endless Adventure is all about? &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot;&gt;Start here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow along on our Journey! You can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/airbnb/how-to-find-the-perfect-airbnb.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/airbnb/how-to-find-the-perfect-airbnb.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>airbnb</category>
        
        
        <category>airbnb</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why We Fell in Love with Austria, and You Will Too!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Picture this: Snow capped mountain peaks off in the distance with low flying clouds dancing around them. Flowing hills covered in trees, with the occasional patch of the greenest grass showing through. Air that feels cleaner than any you’ve ever breathed. This is Austria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About five years ago, we came across a popular YouTube video. In it, a guy goes flying down a green hillside on a mountain coaster with no brakes. It looked like the experience of a lifetime and quickly jumped to the top of our bucket list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, like many bucket list items, we never thought we’d actually have the opportunity to accomplish it. I mean, when would we ever have to opportunity to travel to Austria and stay near the tiny town of Mieders? That thought took us right back to reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward five years and we’re on a bus traveling from Milan to Innsbruck, a small(ish) town just outside of Mieders, in Austria.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had heard a lot of amazing things about Austria from friends and fellow travelers. When this happens, you always run the risk of the place not living up to the hype. But, luckily, Austria more than delivered.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sun was going down and a storm was rolling in as our bus chugged along the Austrian countryside. We had never seen such a beautiful site. The clouds were wrapping around the mountains with beams of sunlight peaking through any gap they could find while quaint little Austrian villages were resting in the valleys below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Innsbruck after dark, but were beyond excited to see what this town offered in daylight. The next day we woke up and took a casual peek out the window. Our jaws dropped.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:37.5% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BHKkfmJhkpc/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;The view from our Airbnb 😍&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A video posted by The Endless Adventure (@theendlessadventure) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-06-27T16:47:18+00:00&quot;&gt;Jun 27, 2016 at 9:47am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easily the best view we’ve had from any hotel or Airbnb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Innsbruck is straight out of a fairytale. Anywhere you look, mountains are rising into the sky with green valleys leading up to them. Humans often have a way of ruining this sort of beauty with ugly buildings and skyscrapers, but not in Innsbruck. The architecture was beyond charming and was the perfect compliment to the surrounding mountain ranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/austria/innsbruck-buildings.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;innsbruck architecture&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We bussed over to the nearby town of Mieders, determined to mark this alpine mountain coaster off of our bucket list. The ride over was yet another jaw dropping experience. Honestly, the beautify of the Austrian countryside is something you have to see for yourself to really &lt;em&gt;get&lt;/em&gt; it. &lt;strong&gt;This place is beautiful.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, we were both more excited than we could remember. The feeling of walking up to my little coaster cart and strapping in was a surreal one. Life is full of these “oh I’d love to do that but…” and “one day I’ll have to do that…” moments, but this time we were actually doing it. It was a satisfying feeling to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Allison in the car behind me, I grabbed on to the throttle, opened it up… &lt;em&gt;and we were off!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before long we had picked up a good amount of speed. The trees and cows (yes, cows) were blurring past us. We were determined not to touch the brake which is no easy task considering that at every turn you feel like you’re going to go flying off the tracks to your death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were screaming, we were laughing, our adrenaline was pumping. It was a true moment of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_(psychology)&quot;&gt;flow&lt;/a&gt;. The ride ended as quickly as it had begun, but we both felt satisfied. It was the experience of a lifetime and one of those rare moments where you had accomplished something you never thought you would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterwards, we traveled back to Innsbruck and found a place called X that served traditional Austrian dishes. We honestly weren’t sure what we ordered (it was all in German!), but it tasted amazing! Seriously one of the top 10 meals we’ve had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/wpVuiDMbi3I&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we made our way out to the village of Igls for a hike. The trailhead was atop one of the many peaks, so we hopped on the Gondola to get up to it. As the tram began to climb, the nearby mountain tops started to appear. Soon we were above the trees and could see endless valleys and villages below, nestled between the mountain ranges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we arrived up top, we easily found the trailhead and started walking. This was the type of hike where you don’t make it too far, mostly because every 200ft you have to stop and snap photos and pick up your jaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/austria/bench-austria.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;austria bench view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/austria/ally-backpack-hike-austria.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;allison in austria&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Towards the end of the hike we came across a pub. Yep, there was a pub at the top of this mountain. Isn’t Austria awesome?? Unfortunately this was one of the few days where we were taking a break from beer, but sitting up there and taking in the stunning scenery was enough for us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/fnsLqVZdvh8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve noticed that as we travel this world, some places end up just clicking with us. Austria was one of those places. For us, it was like different planet where beauty was waiting at every turn. There was so much to discover and we had only scratched the surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Austria, we’ll meet again soon.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2016 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/why-we-fell-in-love-with-austria-and-you-will-too.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/why-we-fell-in-love-with-austria-and-you-will-too.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>wanderlust</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>These 9 Instagrammers Will Give You Some Serious Wanderlust</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We &lt;em&gt;love&lt;/em&gt; following other travelers on Instagram. In addition to giving us inspiration on where to visit next, some of their photos are just damn cool!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few of our favorite accounts that you should follow for some serious wanderlust and travel inspiration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nomaderhowfar&quot;&gt;Nomaderhowfar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This nomadic, minimalist couple is currently traveling through Australia taking great photos and making fun YouTube videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their photos are always fun and will certainly give you the travel itch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:37.5% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BDw7Rv3qgpz/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Trippy startrail photography I did the other night here in Noosa :D #stars #milkyway #universe #photoskillz #photooftheday #photography #landscape #longexposure #instalike #awesome #moon #earth #space #nasa #noosa #queensland #visitnoosa #visitqueensland #queenslandtourism #australia #travel #backpacking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Hannah &amp;amp; Taran (@nomaderhowfar) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-04-04T04:11:57+00:00&quot;&gt;Apr 3, 2016 at 9:11pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nothing-familiar&quot;&gt;Nothing familiar&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This traveling couple is on a mission to visit every country in the World. Follow them on Instagram and come along for the journey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BDInvwCvycz/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Always Searching for Something.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Brigitte &amp;amp; Jake 🌴 (@nothingfamiliar) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-03-19T12:31:39+00:00&quot;&gt;Mar 19, 2016 at 5:31am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-endless-adventure&quot;&gt;The Endless Adventure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hey, that’s us! We’re currently traveling the world, writing about what we’ve learned and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure&quot;&gt;vlogging the entire thing&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow us on Instagram and you’ll be longing for life on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:38.7962962963% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGd9z53MIA2/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dune Du Pilat is a 2.7 km long mountain of sand with ocean on one side and forest on the other.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by The Endless Adventure (@theendlessadventure) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-06-10T09:02:42+00:00&quot;&gt;Jun 10, 2016 at 2:02am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-blonde-abroad&quot;&gt;The Blonde Abroad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kirsten, a.k.a. The Blonde Abroad, runs an award winning travel blog. Her Instagram is full of colorful, warm photos that’ll have you longing to break out if you comfort zone and start exploring!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:62.4537037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BG4Knfxo5Jz/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Canggu sunsets FTW 🙌🏻💜 ••••••••••••••••••••••••••••••••• Checked into @tuguhotels Canggu -- one of my favorite hotels in Bali! You can&amp;#39;t get much closer to the beach and the sunsets here are always epic! ••••••••••••••••••••••••••••••••• Thanks to the incredibly talented (and colorful) @katgaskin for the jump shot 😘 #bali #travel #sunset #wanderlust&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Kiersten • The Blonde Abroad (@theblondeabroad) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-06-20T13:14:51+00:00&quot;&gt;Jun 20, 2016 at 6:14am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;two-scots-abroad&quot;&gt;Two Scots Abroad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As their name suggests, Gemma &amp;amp; Craig are two scots wandering the world. We love following along on their adventures which often include epic scenery and colorful landscapes. Follow them and you’ll be booking a plane ticket in no time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BG2GDdpFz65/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;• THIS IS BOSNIA • Not sure what your preconceived ideas of Bosnia and Herzegovina are but I&amp;#39;m here to build on them! One of the most beautiful countries I&amp;#39;ve visited in the past 18 months on this career break, check my grid - I&amp;#39;ve touched base in some pretty outstanding photogenic cities and places! Don&amp;#39;t forget to check out my 3 live posts on BiH at Two Scots Abroad 🚀 Q☝🏼️Where are you this weekend? Heading over to catch up with team #WanderingWisely - are you in the gang? Feature happening this week, getting tagging 📸&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Gemma I Two Scots Abroad (@twoscotsabroad) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-06-19T17:56:30+00:00&quot;&gt;Jun 19, 2016 at 10:56am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;just-2-guys-creative&quot;&gt;Just 2 guys creative&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gabriel &amp;amp; Will are traveling the world together making stunning videos and snapping epic photos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their Instagram includes fun travel photos as well as wanderlust inducing video clips, often with amazing drone footage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGked3PCz1H/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Super Shot Sunday time!! Remember you can find the full clip on our youtube page! Link 👉 bio 😍😍&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A video posted by Gabriel Ng &amp;amp; Will Good (@just2guyscreative) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-06-12T21:43:29+00:00&quot;&gt;Jun 12, 2016 at 2:43pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;roamwildandfree&quot;&gt;Roamwildandfree&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Becca &amp;amp; Alex are traveling and living a nomadic lifestyle with their hairless pup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They post tons of amazing scenery and landscape shots. They’re a huge inspiration to us when we are deciding where to travel to next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:62.5% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGxJ9K6v7Er/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;H A P P Y W E E K E N D!!!!!! @miolasurf #miola #dametraveler #outdoorbella #sheisnotlost #radgirlslife&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Becca &amp;amp; Alex Foss (@roamwildandfree) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-06-17T19:54:23+00:00&quot;&gt;Jun 17, 2016 at 12:54pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whilst-were-young&quot;&gt;Whilst we’re young&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are two travelers who are “beating the shit out if life”. They make vlogs of their travels and post inspiring and fun photos on their Instagram. Definitely a must follow for any traveler or wannabe traveler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:37.4537037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGg7q1stQDx/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Turtles where you at?! 🐢 - #whilstwereyoung #bali #girlsLOVEtravel #gilit #snorkling #backpackers #backpacking #travel #traveling #instatravel #instagood #trip #girl #holiday #photooftheday #potd #fun #travelling #tourism #tourist #travelvloggers #videoblog #diving #bikini #kingingit #goproselfie #straythecourse #beach&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Whilst We&amp;#39;re Young (@whilstwereyoung) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-06-11T12:41:42+00:00&quot;&gt;Jun 11, 2016 at 5:41am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;nomadiclindsey&quot;&gt;Nomadiclindsey&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lindsey Chen posts epic photos of her travels around the world. We love her Instagram because her photos are bright, colorful and they show off her amazing fashion sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:41.1001236094% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BGak4YTiQeE/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Kyoto, you beauty 🗻 #daimonjiyama #views #datviewdoe #kyoto #japan #traveljapan #wanderlust #ladiesgoneglobal #airheadsflock #dametraveler #passionpassport #wearetravelgirls #sharetravelpics #sheisnotlost #sidewalkerdaily #darlingescapes #vscocam #vsco #createandexplore #createexploretakeover #creatorclass #streetdreamsmag #killeverygram #lifewelltravelled #moodygrams #killeverygram #京都&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A photo posted by Lindsey Chen (@nomadiclindsey) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-06-09T01:27:08+00:00&quot;&gt;Jun 8, 2016 at 6:27pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Got a favorite travel Instagrammer that didn’t make the list? Leave us a comment below or reach out to us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/these-nine-instagrammers-will-give-you-some-serious-wanderlust.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/these-nine-instagrammers-will-give-you-some-serious-wanderlust.html</guid>
        
        <category>instagram</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Day in Milan ON THE CHEAP!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you’re traveling full-time like us or just going on a two week vacation, cost is usually a factor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently visited Milan, Italy and were determined to spend a day seeing the sights and eating well without spending boatloads of money. As it turns out, you can have a lot of fun in Milan without spending much at all!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s our guide to spending one day in Milan on the cheap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rent-a-bike-with-bikemi&quot;&gt;Rent a bike with BikeMI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/one-day-in-milan/bike.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;allison on milan bike&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Milan has an amazing bike sharing program. There are literally hundreds of bike stations all over the city so you’re almost always a block away from one. They have classic pedal powered bikes as well as electric bikes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before heading to the station, grab a daily subscription from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bikemi.com/en/stations-map.aspx&quot;&gt;BikeMI&lt;/a&gt;. The first 30 minutes of your bike rental is free, and only .5EUR after that. So it’s super cheap and well worth it! Not to mention, it’s an amazing way to see the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total cost:&lt;/strong&gt; €4.50&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;breakfast-at-pav&quot;&gt;Breakfast at Pavé&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/one-day-in-milan/pastry.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pastry from pavé&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are tons of bakeries throughout Milan. You seriously can’t walk a few blocks without smelling the amazing aroma of baked pastries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re near the northern part of the city, we recommend &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.pavemilano.com/en/&quot;&gt;Pavé&lt;/a&gt;, which is a quaint little place in North Milan that has a great atmosphere, a friendly staff and, of course, delicious coffee and pastries!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total cost:&lt;/strong&gt; €4.00&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bike-to-the-milan-cathedral&quot;&gt;Bike to the Milan Cathedral&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/one-day-in-milan/church.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;milan cathedral&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.duomomilano.it/en/&quot;&gt;Milan Cathedral&lt;/a&gt; is huge and absolutely stunning. It sits in the middle of Piazza del Duomo, which is a huge square that’s buzzing with people, street performers and about a thousand pigeons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tickets to go inside the Cathedral are only 2EUR. For that price, you can’t miss it! But if you’re coming on a weekend or during the summer months, be prepared to wait in a long line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.it/maps/place/Duomo+di+Milano/@45.4640976,9.1897378,17z/data=!4m12!1m6!3m5!1s0x4786c6aec34636a1:0xab7f4e27101a2e13!2sDuomo+di+Milano!8m2!3d45.4640976!4d9.1919265!3m4!1s0x4786c6aec34636a1:0xab7f4e27101a2e13!8m2!3d45.4640976!4d9.1919265&quot;&gt;Milan Cathedral on Google Maps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total cost:&lt;/strong&gt; €2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lunch-at-luini&quot;&gt;Lunch at Luini&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/one-day-in-milan/calzone.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;eating panzerotti&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right near the cathedral you’ll find a popular little place called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.luini.it/eng/storia.html&quot;&gt;Luini&lt;/a&gt;. They have the most amazing panzerotti which, if you’re not familiar with that term, are little pastry filled with sweet or savory goodness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We opted to try the Spinach / Ricotta as well as the Onion / Olive / Marinara, both of which completely blew us away. If we lived in Milan we’d be eating these all the time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.it/maps/place/Panzerotti+Luini/@45.4658276,9.1893658,17z/data=!4m12!1m6!3m5!1s0x4786c6ae420941a1:0x7679be1e2c775e23!2sPanzerotti+Luini!8m2!3d45.4658276!4d9.1915545!3m4!1s0x4786c6ae420941a1:0x7679be1e2c775e23!8m2!3d45.4658276!4d9.1915545&quot;&gt;Luini on Google Maps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total cost:&lt;/strong&gt; €2.5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;back-on-the-bike-to-see-the-sforza-castle&quot;&gt;Back on the bike to see the Sforza Castle&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/one-day-in-milan/castle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sforza castle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hop back on your bikes and make the short journey over to the Sforza Castle. This huge mass of brick was originally built in the 15th century and it straight out of storybook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we visited, there were hundreds of birds constantly swarming the castle, which made it all the more epic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Entrance is free and there’s a large park in the back. After a leisurely stroll through the castle, head out the back entrance and explore the park. It’s a great place to snap some nice Instagrams and, of course, do some great people watching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.it/maps/place/Sforzesco+Castle/@45.4704762,9.1771438,17z/data=!4m12!1m6!3m5!1s0x4786fcb60ea97b3d:0x6556dd66c472c29b!2sSforzesco+Castle!8m2!3d45.4704762!4d9.1793325!3m4!1s0x4786fcb60ea97b3d:0x6556dd66c472c29b!8m2!3d45.4704762!4d9.1793325&quot;&gt;Sforza Castle on Google Maps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total cost:&lt;/strong&gt; FREE&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;have-an-appertivo&quot;&gt;Have an Appertivo!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Italy is known for appertivo. If you’re not familiar with this concept, it’s basically a meal before the meal, meant to stimulate your appetite. For a flat price, you’re given a drink (usually a cocktail or a beer) and unlimited access to a buffet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 8PM, these appertivo restaurants are packed, and this is just the warm up for dinner around 10PM!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The quality of the food varies, but we were really impressed with the Appertivo at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mayamilano.it/maya_milano.html&quot;&gt;Maya&lt;/a&gt; which is near Navigli. For 10EUR we had unlimited access to their constantly changing buffet and 1 premium cocktail each. Needless to say, we were stuffed and opted out of the 10PM dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.it/maps/place/Maya/@45.447977,9.1750913,17z/data=!4m12!1m6!3m5!1s0x4786c3f7c162316b:0xc4c78c5a109ced71!2sMaya!8m2!3d45.447977!4d9.17728!3m4!1s0x4786c3f7c162316b:0xc4c78c5a109ced71!8m2!3d45.447977!4d9.17728&quot;&gt;Maya on Google Maps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total cost:&lt;/strong&gt; €10&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-a-stroll-along-the-canal&quot;&gt;Take a stroll along the canal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/one-day-in-milan/canal.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;milan canal&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a canal that runs through Navigili with tons of shops, street vendors and amazing restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After your appertivo, take a leisurely stroll along the canal. The water is clear and you can see all the way to the bottom. As the sun sets you can get some great Instagram of the canal from atop one of the many bridges that crosses it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total per person cost:&lt;/strong&gt; €23&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it! With this guide, you can spend a day in Milan, Italy and have a lot of fun without breaking the bank. You’ll see the sights, eat well and have an amazing time touring the city by bike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2016 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-guides/a-day-in-milan-on-the-cheap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-guides/a-day-in-milan-on-the-cheap.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>travel-guides</category>
        
        <category>city-guides</category>
        
        <category>budget-travel</category>
        
        
        <category>travel-guides</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Surefire Ways to Get Traffic to Your New YouTube Vlog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you a fellow aspiring YouTuber? Creating great content but having a hard time getting your videos in front of potential subscribers? Well, we feel your pain!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been traveling the world and vlogging our adventures for the last 8 months. Since we began, we’ve learned a lot about how to drive traffic to your YouTube channel when you don’t have a huge social presence or a large following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But first, a disclaimer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your content has to be good. Naturally, when your channel is your baby, it can be hard to tell if what you’re producing isn’t very good. Try asking for feedback from all of your friends and family members before pushing your content out to the masses. Try to ask them to provide objective feedback. This may be impossible, but it’s better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If there’s room for improvement, wait to promote your videos until you’ve reached a higher level of quality.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t promote our YouTube channel until we had already made almost 30 vlogs!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer over&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, here are 10 techniques you can use to drive traffic to your new YouTube vlog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;post-on-reddit&quot;&gt;Post on Reddit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many subreddits are where content goes to die a horrible death, we’ve been able to generate quality traffic and subscribes from a few of them. Here are some subreddits where you can post your new vlog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/vlog&quot;&gt;/r/vlog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NewTubers&quot;&gt;/r/NewTubers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/vlogging&quot;&gt;/r/vlogging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/vlogger&quot;&gt;/r/vlogger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/vlogs&quot;&gt;/r/vlogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media platforms like Twitter can be tricky to break into, but I still think it’s worth trying. Even if you only have 50 followers, you should still post your vlogs on Twitter. You never know when a follower might click, watch and subscribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t stop at posting vlogs. Posting the same content all the time will cause people to eventually ignore your posts. Also try to post meaningful content that’s in your niche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And make sure you take some time to reach out to others. Reply to their tweets, retweet them, post their blog content. The more you share, the more people are likely to share your content and follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook is pretty similar to Twitter. You want to post your vlogs consistently, but you don’t want to &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; post vlogs. Work on posting useful content within your niche. Before you’ll know it you’ll have a handful of likes and the snowball effect will begin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;instagram&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram can be a bit trickier, but is nevertheless a great platform for generating YouTube views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, always be &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/instagram-hashtags/&quot;&gt;hashtagging your photos&lt;/a&gt;  so you can squeeze as much social juice out of each post as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you post a new vlog, post a screenshot from the video or the thumbnail and push users to check it out. There’s a caveat though. Instagram doesn’t allow you to include links within posts. Instead, put LINK IN BIO after your photo comment and make sure your bio links to your YouTube channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/instagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;promote vlog on instagram&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For bonus points, use &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitly.com/&quot;&gt;bit.ly&lt;/a&gt; to track your bio link and see how many people actually click it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title-and-thumbnail-your-video-properly&quot;&gt;Title and thumbnail your video properly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A proper title and an interesting thumbnail can go a long way in driving eyeballs to your videos. Watch time is the most important factor in determining a video’s quality, but a proper title, description and tags still help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple trick you can use is to type relevant keywords into the YouTube search bar and see what it auto suggest. Presumably these are popular phrases people are searching for. So, if you include these phrases in your video title, it may do better in search results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/search-results.png&quot; alt=&quot;youtube search results&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also try to title your videos similar to other similar and semi-popular YouTube videos. Keyword here is &lt;em&gt;similar&lt;/em&gt; - not the same! This may increase the potential that your video shows up as a recommended video alongside these other videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/related-videos.png&quot; alt=&quot;related youtube videos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comment-on-popular-youtubers-videos&quot;&gt;Comment on popular YouTubers’ videos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s true that the comments section on YouTube is often full of trolls, morons and other generally stupid people. BUT, it is still possible to have a normal discussion about the videos you’re watching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our videos are travel related, we’ll often engage in discussions on channels like funforlouis or mrbenbrown. We’ve found that if you add to the conversation in a meaningful way, other commenters might click your username and view your channel. And if they find it interesting, they might even subscribe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been able to generate consistent subscribers and views this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to make sure you’re interacting on channels that are relevant to yours. This just means it’s more likely their viewers might &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; be interested in your channel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/popular-comments.png&quot; alt=&quot;popular youtuber comments&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comment-on-smaller-youtubers-videos&quot;&gt;Comment on smaller YouTubers’ videos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on smaller YouTubers is also a great way to generate views and subscribers. But the key here is quality over quantity. Always leave positive or helpful comments and &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; ask the YouTuber to view or subscribe to your channel. Trust me, if you leave a meaningful comment and have interesting content of your own, they’ll find their way to your channel page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding smaller YouTubers is easy. Just search “first youtube video” or “first vlog” on Twitter. You can also view the subreddits I mentioned above to find smaller YouTubers to interact with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/smaller-youtuber-comments.png&quot; alt=&quot;smaller youtube comments&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;post-in-yttalk-forum&quot;&gt;Post in yttalk forum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://yttalk.com&quot;&gt;Yttalk&lt;/a&gt; forums are full of other YouTubers of all channel sizes. And in addition to being a great place to find help with your channel and feedback on your videos, it’s also a great way to find potential viewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of your fellow YouTubers are YouTube viewers themselves. So the more you interact on the forums, the more likely it is that they will click your channel and possibly subscribe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;post-on-empirekred&quot;&gt;Post on empire.kred&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://empire.kred/&quot;&gt;Empire.kred&lt;/a&gt; is a place where you can post your content and push other influencers to engage with it. Based on your social media influence, you’re given a stock value in eaves (which is their digital currency). Other influencers can buy “stock” in you, which in turn puts eaves in your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eaves can be used to create missions which are basically tasks that you give to other influencers, i.e. watch my latest video, view this tweet, view this photo, etc. But the catch is you can’t specifically ask for engagement, i.e. likes, comments, shares. Instead, it’s up to the user to decide for themselves how they’d like to engage with your content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone accomplishes your mission, they are paid a sum in eaves that you decide when you post the mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like that you aren’t specifically allowed to ask someone to subscribe to your channel in order to accomplish a mission. Presumably, this means if someone from Empire.Kred subscribes, it’s because they are interested in your channel and want to see more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/empire-kred.png&quot; alt=&quot;empire kred&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interact-with-every-single-comment-you-receive&quot;&gt;Interact with every single comment you receive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to YouTube success is building a community. As your community grows, more and more people will return to your videos and interact with them via likes, shares and comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to respond to all of your video comments as quickly as possible. This shows your viewers that there’s a real person on the other end and will make them much more likely to engage with your other videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had some viewers that have been commenting on our videos since the very beginning. If we hadn’t consistently responded to their comments, they might not have become a regular viewer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/youtube-comment.png&quot; alt=&quot;youtube-comment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it, 10 surefire ways to get traffic to your new YouTube vlog. When you’re starting out on YouTube, it can be daunting trying to gain an initial user base. The key is to start small. Set a goal of 10 subscribers, then 50, then 100, then 500. If you’re consistently producing interesting content and using the techniques above, you’ll see consistent growth to your YouTube channel guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve found this article helpful, I hope you’ll consider sharing it with your network. And if you have any tips of your own to add, leave a comment below or reach out to us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/vlogging/ten-surefire-ways-get-traffic-new-youtube-vlog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/vlogging/ten-surefire-ways-get-traffic-new-youtube-vlog.html</guid>
        
        <category>vlogging</category>
        
        
        <category>vlogging</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Almost Got Pickpocketed in Berlin and How You Can Avoid It</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We recently had a scary moment in Berlin’s Großer Tiergarten. We were taking pictures in a somewhat secluded area of the garden when a man came up asking for donations for a deaf charity. He had a clipboard with a formal looking sign up sheet and everything. We politely declined the request and turned to walk away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so at this point you may be thinking “what heartless jerks refusing to donate to a deaf charity!! Only savages would decline donating to such a cause!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, I’d probably be thinking something similar, &lt;strong&gt;but&lt;/strong&gt; just a couples days prior to the event, we’d taken a walking tour during which our guide told us about a popular scam where people pretend to collect money for the deaf and mute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-scam-goes-something-like-this&quot;&gt;The scam goes something like this&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh hey would you like to donate to a deaf charity?”&lt;br /&gt;
“Oh, maybe! Tell me more about this charity?”&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;someone bumps into you while you’re distracted&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
“Oh, sorry sir!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boom, you’ve been pickpocketed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s actually a popular scam across Europe that you can read about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.corporatetravelsafety.com/safety-tips/deaf-mute-scams-in-europe/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back to our encounter. The deaf charity donation request was our first tip-off. The next red flag moment came after we politely declined. The man became increasingly more persistent and aggressive with his tone and proceeded to walk after us. But what was most terrifying about the encounter was that as we turned back to assess the situation, we realized that three other men with clipboards had started rushing towards us and were all yelling at us in German.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started walking away faster and eventually started running as they quickened their pace. Luckily after a few moments of us running and them yelling, they finally relented and walked off down another empty path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were extremely lucky that we had been given a heads up about the scam. Especially because that day we had our laptops, cell phones, camera, and GoPro on us, plus a little spending money and a credit card. Had we realized what was happening a moment later or had the men continued to chase us, it could have been extremely devastating to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents, concerned friends, and seasoned travelers alike will all tell you to stay safe when you start traveling. And at first, the newness of travel will automatically keep you on higher alert. But after a while, you get pretty used to life on the road and tend to let your guard down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t say this to make you paranoid or scared to go out and explore a new city, we just want you to travel smart. Especially when it’s obvious you’re a tourist - aka you’re not speaking their language, you’re carrying a camera and/or backpack, you have google maps pulled up, etc…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-how-do-you-avoid-situations-like-this&quot;&gt;So, how do you avoid situations like this?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, sadly there’s no fool-proof solution. But there are a lot of things you can do to reduce your odds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take a moment to scan your surroundings, especially in touristy areas.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’re using a camera, use a wrist or neck strap so it’s always connected to you. (Bonus point: this will also save you from accidentally dropping your camera! Win-win!)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As tempting as it can be, don’t ever put your phone, wallet or any other valuables in your back pockets or the mesh side pockets of your backpack. Just don’t do it!!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Invest in a purse that has multiple barriers to entry with clasps, drawstrings, zippers and/or buckles. And &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; wear your purse across your chest and to the front. Think you’ll look silly? Well guess again, because it’s actually &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whowhatwear.co.uk/how-to-wear-cross-body-bag-purse-fashion-winter-2014/&quot;&gt;cool&lt;/a&gt;  and practical!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Always do a quick google search before you go to a new city to familiarize yourself with common scams in the area. Travel blogs and tourism sites are great resources to help you figure out things to watch out for on your travels.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be wary of beggars. I know that sounds heartless, but pickpockets and thieves are smart and have been known to use children, the elderly and pretty women to lure you in. Instead of giving your money in person, go online later and donate to the charity. If you’re feeling super compelled to help a person out, give them some food or a care package while keeping your money safely hidden away.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Try to avoid using physical maps to navigate around a new city. Not only does this scream tourist, but it also leaves you extremely vulnerable. Instead, try to get a handle on your route ahead of time or step into a coffee shop to get your bearings.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Get travelers insurance! Okay, so this isn’t a way to prevent pickpocketing, but it is a way to ease your mind should something happen.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you had a close encounter like ours? What’s the most valuable travel lesson you’ve ever learned? Let us know in the comments section below or shout out to us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/pick-pocketed-in-berlin-how-to-avoid-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/pick-pocketed-in-berlin-how-to-avoid-it.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travel Vlog: The Most Famous Statue in Brussels</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Brussels is a beautiful city with stunning architecture and a unique past. And, for some reason, they are obsessed with a statue of a peeing baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re currently traveling through Europe and every time we land in a new city, the first thing we do is book a free walking tour. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neweuropetours.eu/&quot;&gt;Sandeman’s&lt;/a&gt; hosts free walking tours all throughout Europe and it’s an amazing way to get to know a new city. Once you’ve learned about a city’s history, you always feel a bit more connected to it. It forces you to appreciate it more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our walking tour took us all over the streets of Brussels. We even saw the most famous statue in brussels (and apparently the 3rd most famous statue in the world?), called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manneken_Pis&quot;&gt;Manneken Pis&lt;/a&gt;. In spite of being (purportedly) world famous, we hadn’t ever heard of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t say we wer underwhelmed by it, more so just confused. It’s basically exactly what it sounds like. A statue of a peeing baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gd-OsV-4dLY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall we had an amazing day getting to know Brussels a little bit better. Between the waffles, rich history and peeing baby statue, there’s a lot to like about this place :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/the-most-famous-statue-in-brussels.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/the-most-famous-statue-in-brussels.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>vlogs</category>
        
        <category>vlogging</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Cellphone Plan for Americans Traveling in Europe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the first questions we asked ourselves when we decided we were going to travel fulltime was “How the heck do we get cellphone coverage when we travel to a new country every month!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re only traveling for a short period of time, this post isn’t for you. But if you’re making travel a lifestyle (or at least traveling for long periods of time) then you’ll find this helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chronic travelers have a few options when it comes to overseas data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;buy-a-sim-card-in-every-country-you-visit&quot;&gt;Buy a sim card in every country you visit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can work well if you’re going to be spending a lot of time in a single country. You can usually get 2-5GB of data for around $30-$50, and that will usually last 2-4 weeks if you’re data conscious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought about giving this strategy a try, but ultimately decided it wouldn’t work for us. The main reason being that we planned on moving around quite a bit, never spending more than a few weeks in single country. We didn’t really want sim cards piling up with unused data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-wi-fi&quot;&gt;Use wi-fi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We actually did this for the first months of traveling, mainly because we hadn’t yet figured out what the heck to do about cell phone coverage. This strategy works, but damn is it annoying. We were constantly searching for wi-fi and trying to leech off of restaurants and hotels. We just weren’t able to stay connected enough throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-a-european-cell-phone-plan&quot;&gt;Get a European cell phone plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bit of research, I found a company called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gosim.com/&quot;&gt;Go Sim&lt;/a&gt; which offered sim cards specifically for data while traveling in European countries. In fact, it actually works in a whopping 100 countries! It sounded too good to be true! Well, it sort of was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1GB of data will cost you around 110 EUR. We had budgeted around $100 USD &lt;em&gt;total&lt;/em&gt; for our monthly data costs, so that just wasn’t going to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a bunch of other companies like Go Sim, but we just couldn’t find one that offered data for a low enough cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;t-mobile-international-plan&quot;&gt;T-mobile international plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we decided to see what the more well known carriers could offer. AT&amp;amp;T’s international plans were a joke, so we pulled up &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.t-mobile.com/&quot;&gt;T-mobile&lt;/a&gt; to see if they have any good plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out they have a “Simple Choice” plan which gives you unlimited data (switches to 2G once you run out of your monthly allotment) in 140 countries. 140! And they even had a special offer running, 6 GB of monthly highs-peed data for $50 per line. That put us right at the $100 mark for 2 lines, hooray!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best of all, there’s no contract. So if we ever want to cancel and go back to AT&amp;amp;T (God forbid) we can do that in an instant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ordered our sim package, popped them in our unlocked phones, activated them online and BAM, we we’re back in the beautiful world of data. We’ve been on this plan for around 2 months and really don’t have many complaints. Naturally, the speeds can be a bit slow depending on which country you’re in, but it’s better than nothing and &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better than worrying about buying a new sim card each time we land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I definitely understand that this cell phone plan isn’t for every traveler, and you should definitely do your research before starting any contracts! But if you travel to a new country every 1-3 weeks, it really is the perfect plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/best-cellphone-plan-for-americans-in-europe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/best-cellphone-plan-for-americans-in-europe.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>9 Travel Tips You Probably Haven&#39;t Heard Before</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of travel tip posts out there, but they’re usually about picking the right luggage and the proper tshirt rolling technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, packing guides can be helpful (I mean heck, &lt;a href=&quot;http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-ditch-the-clutter-and-travel-light.html&quot;&gt;I even wrote one&lt;/a&gt;). But since we started traveling full-time, there have been a bunch of things we had to learn the hard way. Things that weren’t listed on most of the guides we read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we made a list from our own experiences in hopes they’ll help you avoid embarrassing tourist moments and give you a bit more confidence on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;double-check-liquid-restrictions-at-airports&quot;&gt;Double check liquid restrictions at airports&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used to think the TSA (Transportation Security Administration) was hardcore with their liquids policy, but boy were we terribly mistaken!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As full time travelers, we never know what amenities our next Airbnb will have, so we’re constantly carrying a billion travel-sized bottles of shampoos, body wash, contact solution, hair gel, toothpaste, lotions, hairspray… you get the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d recently taken flights from Barcelona and Dubrovnik without any issues though, so imagine our surprise when the security agents in Copenhagen’s airport started freaking out as soon as our carry ons went into the scanners. They stopped the entire line and had us open our severely over-stuffed bags to show them all the liquids we were “hiding”. Talk about a stressful tourist moment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, not only are you supposed to take all of your liquids completely out of your carry on luggage in Copenhagen’s airport, but you’re also supposed to stuff them all into one (and only one!) impossibly small plastic baggie. (We’ve since found that it’s the same flying out of Berlin, but they weren’t as strict.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/bag.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pic of plastic baggie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, we ended up throwing away about half of our supplies, most of which were new, not-cheap items :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesson learned: &lt;strong&gt;always double check the airport security policies before getting to the front of the line.&lt;/strong&gt; You can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/youreurope/citizens/travel/safety/air-security/index_en.htm&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to make sure you’re complying with all of the EU’s travel policies and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tsa.gov/travel/security-screening&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; for when you’re flying in the US. If you still have questions, I’m sure an extra friendly airport attendant will be only mildly annoyed if you ask for clarification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and one last thing: &lt;strong&gt;always make sure to check your airline’s carry on policies!&lt;/strong&gt; Though we’ve yet to see these policies heavily enforced, a lot of European budget airlines have stricter size and weight limits than in the states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;check-for-major-events-and-holidays-happening-during-your-stay&quot;&gt;Check for major events and holidays happening during your stay&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not once, but twice now we’ve arrived in a new city excited for a fun day of exploring only to find it’s a national holiday and everything’s closed. Bummer! While it’s interesting to experience holidays in other cities and countries, it can also mean that trains, grocery stores, and museums may have restricted hours or closures during your stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holidays and festivals may also be the reason you’re having a hard time booking an affordable hotel or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.airbnb.com/c/abieller&quot;&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt; during your stay. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timeanddate.com/calendar/info.html&quot;&gt;timeanddate.com&lt;/a&gt; to see if there are any major holidays falling during your stay. And a quick peek at the city’s website or facebook pageshould give you a list of any festivals or big events in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-a-free-walking-tour&quot;&gt;Take a free walking tour!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were recently turned on to the amazingness of free walking tours and we can’t recommend them enough!! The people who lead them work on tips so basically it’s up to you to decide how much the tour is worth. And they are seriously the most excited people we’ve ever encountered. It’s a great way to get a feel for a new city, meet fellow travelers, and get some exercise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our favorite tour company is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neweuropetours.eu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sandemans&lt;/a&gt;. Definitely check their website to see if they have a free walking tour in the city you’re visiting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Your guide will usually offer a free map. Snatch that baby up and have them mark all the cool places you should go while you’re in town!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/guide.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tour guide&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wait-a-day-before-making-assumptions-about-a-new-city&quot;&gt;Wait a day before making assumptions about a new city&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While travel days are typically super exciting, they’re almost always really stressful - especially when you’re traveling to a new country. You arrive stale and jetlagged, have to deal with the nightmare that is customs, and then have to navigate a new public transportation system, often in a foreign language, using a foreign currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, you’re probably not the happiest of camper by this point and are a lot more inclined to project that negativity on the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently made this mistake when we arrived to a cold and rainy Berlin, exhausted from carrying our bags all day. And unbeknownst to us, it was a holiday so nothing around us was open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of doing something fun, we just had a dreary night in our little apartment eating Chinese food, watching Saving Private Ryan and second guessing our choice to visit Berlin. (In retrospect, we agree that those were probably the weirdest choices for someone’s first night in Berlin…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we woke up refreshed and determined to have a better day. We ended up finding an awesome coffee shop to work from… okay maybe Berlin isn’t so bad, we thought. Then we happened upon an even more awesome lunch spot… 2 for 2 - we’re starting to warm up to you, Berlin! Finally, we ended the evening at a really cool bar with super cheap beers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out Berlin wasn’t the problem - our attitudes were the problem!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We let our emotions dictate our experience instead of appreciating where we were. Since that first day, we’ve fallen more in love with Berlin each day and are having a blast exploring the history and culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Berlin is intense and badass and cool and we’re sorry we were mad at you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-sure-you-take-waterproof-shoes&quot;&gt;Make sure you take waterproof shoes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tip may sound a bit silly, but spending your day (or days) walking around with wet socks and soaked shoes is not very fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year we visited New York City thinking it would be springtime weather, but apparently the city still thought it was winter. It was rainy with near freezing temperatures the entire week! Within 5 minutes of leaving our Airbnb my shoes were completely soaked through and my toes were frozen. No bueno!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do yourself a favor and either take some waterproof shoes or, for all you DIYers, do like this crazy Russian dude and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lifehack.org/articles/lifehack/how-make-your-shoes-waterproof.html&quot;&gt;coat your shoes in wax&lt;/a&gt; to keep your toesies and shoes happy and dry on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the less scrappy approach and just bought some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.de/Dr-Martens-Unisex-Erwachsene-Bootsschuhe-Erwachsene/dp/B000BNWOWS/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1464018103&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=dr+martens&quot;&gt;badass leather boots&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/boots.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pic of me in the rain wearing my boots&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;always-look-up-public-transportation-options-in-advance&quot;&gt;Always look up public transportation options in advance.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public transportation has hands down caused the most frustration during our travels. It’s really pretty mind boggling how every city can have such different processes and signage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some have zone systems that can be almost impossible to decipher. Others have aboveground lines and underground lines which can get really confusing when you’re standing next to a station and keep “missing” the train only to find out it’s underneath you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some systems, like the one in Berlin, require you to validate your card in a separate machine. And if you forget (or in our case have no idea that’s a thing), you’ll definitely be handed a ticked by the conductor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you stay in a city for a while, you may never get a great handle on their system. But having a general understanding of the system in advance goes a long way. At least knowing how to get from the airport to your hotel will save you tons of stress and ensure you’re not waiting around at the train station instead of exploring a new city!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-train-station.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;waiting at train station&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learn-the-basics-of-the-language&quot;&gt;Learn the basics of the language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going to a country where they speak a foreign language is stressful. But if you learn just a few basic phrases, you’ll be amazed at how much more at ease you’ll feel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to say “hello”, “I would like one, please” and “thank you” will ensure that you’re at least able to order confidently at any restaurant or coffee shop! Also, being able to say “excuse me” if you need to ask someone a question or sneak by someone (it happens more often than you think!) is extremely useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning everyday phrases will not only let the locals know you’re trying to meet them halfway, but it’ll also dramatically lessens your stress levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are the phrases that have come in most handy for us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hello&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sorry!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Excuse me&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much does this cost?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where is the restroom?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One (two, three) please&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thank you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;calculate-the-full-cost-of-staying-in-the-city-vs-outside-the-city&quot;&gt;Calculate the full cost of staying in the city vs outside the city&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying outside of the city center can be a great way to save big while you’re traveling. But one thing we’ve learned is that the savings don’t always outweigh the transportation time and costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently stayed in a neighborhood about 30 minutes outside of Copenhagen because everything in the city was pretty expensive. What we didn’t take into account was the $11 USD we’d have to pay to get to and from the city &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the hour or more we’d waste commuting every day. We had 5 people staying in the house, which means we were paying $55 extra each day. That ended up being more than the amount we saved in rental fees!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a pretty painful and expensive lesson to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But since you took my advice and googled the public transportation at your upcoming destination, you already have a good guess as to how much you’ll be spending to get around!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;always-carry-snacks&quot;&gt;Always carry snacks!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You never know when your flight will be delayed or when you’ll miss your train because you can’t punch the buttons on the damn ticket machine fast enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always having a piece of fruit or some nuts tucked away requires little planning and will keep your evil, hangry side at bay. Snack bars are also a great option - just make sure it’s high in protein and not sugar so it sustains you for a while. We love &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicbar.com/&quot;&gt;Epic Meal Bars&lt;/a&gt;, but sadly they are not always available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Always carry around at least a small bottle of water. For some reason water is not always free or readily available when you’re traveling. We specifically bought day bags which have little pouches on the outside, perfect for a water bottle and super handy too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-tips/nine-travel-tips-probably-havent-heard-before.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-tips/nine-travel-tips-probably-havent-heard-before.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Most Incredible Places To Visit In Dubai</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dubai is one of the most modern and newest cities in the world. In recent years, Dubai has gained popularity as one of the top destinations for travelers. Can you believe that just over 40 years ago it was all desert and sand dunes? It is quite hard to imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Dubai aims to be the biggest and best city on earth. Their goal is to make the impossible, possible. I feel so lucky to have visited this magical city and excited to share the most incredible places to visit in Dubai!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;burj-khalifa&quot;&gt;Burj Khalifa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dubai has created the world’s tallest structure, The Burj Khalifa, which stands at 829.8 m. The 124th observation deck is quite a place to experience! The best time to visit is during sunset and night time to catch the beautiful skyline views. Another record-breaking attraction in Dubai is the Dubai Fountain located below the Burj Khalifa, which is currently the largest choreographed fountain in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;burj-al-arab&quot;&gt;Burj Al Arab&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Burj Al Arab is one of the tallest hotels in the world. It is a luxurious 5 star hotel and also one of the most expensive hotels in the world. If you’re a budget traveler, you can visit the hotel without having to spend a night by making reservations at one of their restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One unbelievable thing here is the view from the top of the Skyview Bar! On a clear day you will be lucky to see The Palm, known as the man-made islands. A visit to the Burj Al Arab will also allow you access to an incredible private beach, which I enjoyed spending my time in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj al arab&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dubai-desert-safari&quot;&gt;Dubai Desert Safari&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A day trip into the desert was one of the highlights during my visit in Dubai. Here you will find the most incredible sunset! Take a day tour with a tour company to experience dune bashing, sandboarding, and camel rides. You can also experience more of the culture during a sunset dinner and show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-dubai-miracle-garden&quot;&gt;The Dubai Miracle Garden&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dubai Miracle Garden is one of the most beautiful flower gardens I have visited! It really does feel like a miracle when you walk through the garden. It’s not open year round though so make sure you check &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dubaimiraclegarden.com/visitors-guide/timing-rates/&quot;&gt;the schedule&lt;/a&gt; in advance. Also, since Dubai gets fairly hot I suggest visiting early morning. I was one of the first visitors there and had the place practically to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dubai-aquarium--mall&quot;&gt;Dubai Aquarium &amp;amp; Mall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As one of the largest malls in the world, the Dubai Mall will surprise you with how many things there are to do. There is a ton of shopping, endless restaurants, a cinema complex, and an ice-skating rink. And did you know that the Dubai Aquarium is also one of the largest suspended aquariums in the world? If you’re brave enough, you can even dive in and swim with the sharks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sheikh-zayed-grand-mosque&quot;&gt;Sheikh Zayed Grand Mosque&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sheikh Zayed Grand Mosque isn’t in Dubai, but it’s so breathtaking that I’m including it anyways! The Grand Mosque is located in Abu Dhabi, the capital city of the United Arab Emirates, and is less than two hours from Dubai. I was amazed by this incredible structure, which is all white and beautifully crafted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sacred mosque is very strict so I advise that you prepare before your visit. Women must cover their head, wrists, and ankles. Men are not allowed to wear tank tops or shorts, so dress accordingly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I entered the mosque, I was so impressed with the carpet. It’s actually the world’s largest hand knotted carpet! The UAE is definitely known for the largest, biggest, and tallest things. While touring inside, make sure to look up to see incredible 24 carat gold chandeliers hanging from the ceiling! If only I could have taken it home as a souvenir :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As one of the top destinations in the world, Dubai is a place you will want to visit once in your life. I truly felt like I was morphed into the future from visiting all the surreal and incredible places in Dubai.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Adventurers: &lt;em&gt;Thanks so much to Christine for sharing these amazing places in Dubai! Be sure and head over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://tourdelust.com/&quot;&gt;her blog&lt;/a&gt; for some wanderlust inducing travel guides and stories.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-tips/six-most-incredible-places-visit-in-dubai.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-tips/six-most-incredible-places-visit-in-dubai.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
