<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Endless Adventure | Travel Vlogs &amp; Blogs</title>
    <description>Hi! We&#39;re Eric and Allison Bieller. We quit our jobs and sold everything to travel full-time. We make daily vlogs of our travels and adventures around the world!
</description>
    <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://theendlessadventure.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 17:12:55 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 17:12:55 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>5 Travel Bloggers You Should be Following</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you looking for your daily dose of wanderlust? Well, here are a few of our favorite travel vloggers who will inspire you to drop everything and book a trip immediately!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-dangerous-businesshttpwwwdangerous-businesscom&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dangerous-business.com&quot;&gt;A Dangerous Business&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dangerous-business.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;a dangerous business travel vlog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amanda teaches you that you don’t need to quit your job to travel the world. Since 2010 she’s been traveling and blogging about her amazing adventures and she didn’t leave her day job or “normal” life to do it. In between travels, she takes time to unwind at home, sleep in her own bed and spend time with her kitty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;no-place-to-behttpwwwnoplacetobecom&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.noplacetobe.com&quot;&gt;No Place to Be&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/no-place-to-be.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;no place to be travel blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poi and Kirsty have called many countries home from Thailand to Austria and now Romania, and they’ve traveled to dozens of others. Follow along on their travels and they’ll inspire you to start living life on your own terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-blonde-abroadhttptheblondeabroadcom&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://theblondeabroad.com&quot;&gt;The Blonde Abroad&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/The-Blonde-Abroad.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Blonde Abroad Travel Blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kiersten left behind her career in corporate finance to travel full-time. She’s got an impressive 50 countries under her belt as well as some amazing adventures. Head over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://theblondeabroad.com&quot;&gt;her blog&lt;/a&gt; for some amazing travel stories! &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.instagram.com/theblondeabroad&quot;&gt;Her Instagram&lt;/a&gt; is also on point but beware, it’ll cause some serious wanderlust!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-go-feverthegofevercom&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;thegofever.com&quot;&gt;The Go Fever&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/the-go-fever.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Go Fever Travel Blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catherine is an amazing write and travel junkie. She’s visited tons of exotic places across the globe like Belize, Jordan and Croatia, just to name a few. On her blog, she shares travel stories as well as the best travel tips she’s picked up along the way. Definitely a great travel blog to follow!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;finding-the-universehttpwwwfindingtheuniversecom&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.findingtheuniverse.com&quot;&gt;Finding the Universe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/finding-the-universe.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;finding the universe travel blog&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Laurence and Jessica write all about their travels across the world, but their main focus is their photography. Follow their blog for some wanderlust inducing photos and fun travel stories. And be sure to follow them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/lozula/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt; for some epic travel photography!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;——&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been following these travel bloggers for a while now and they have been huge inspirations for us in planning our travels and adventures. We definitely hope that they’ll do the same for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2016 08:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/5-travel-bloggers-you-should-be-following.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/5-travel-bloggers-you-should-be-following.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>blogging</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travel Vlog: Exploring the Sutro Bath Ruins in San Francisco</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Who’s up for a swim? Well, back in 1896, the Sutro Baths were the place to be for the water inclined among us. Now, the ruins are all that’s left of this once popular and vibrant bath house.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/omOho20_RtQ&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baths are located out near the northwestern tip of the San Francisco peninsula, nestled at the bottom of a large beach inlet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you first lay eyes on the ruins, it’s from the top looking down. The view is as beautiful as it is bizarre. Looking at pictures of the facility back in it’s hay day, it’s hard to imagine this vibrant glass house enclosing happy kids and families swimming around having the times of their lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-sutro-baths-san-francisco.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;allison at sutro baths san francisco&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During high tide, ocean water would literally spill over into the baths, filling the pools. During low tide, there was a powerful turbine pump that would send 6,000 gallons a minute into the baths. At the time, it was the world’s largest indoor swimming facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The baths were officially closed down in the 60’s. Ironically, the facility burned down in 1966. Luckily it had been officially closed down shortly before catching fire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re visiting San Francisco, do yourself a favor and take a trip to the Sutro Baths. The area is free and open to the public and there weren’t many roped off areas so you’re free to explore the bulk of the ruins.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Mar 2016 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/travel-vlog-exploring-sutro-bath-ruins-san-francisco.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/travel-vlog-exploring-sutro-bath-ruins-san-francisco.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>vlogging</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Become a Travel Vlogger</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So you want to be a travel vlogger, ay? I’m not surprised. I mean, who wouldn’t want to travel to exotic destinations, vlog their adventures and have millions of viewers wanderlust over their travels. It sounds like a dream life, but don’t be fooled, travel vlogging is hard work!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The good news is, you don’t have to quit your job and sell all your possessions &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot;&gt;like we did&lt;/a&gt; in order to become a travel vlogger. Don’t get me wrong, minimalism is amazing and a worthy pursuit, but it’s not required in order to live a life of travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where the heck do you even start? What if you have a full time job? What gear do you need?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;incorporate-travel-into-your-life&quot;&gt;Incorporate travel into your life&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When people talk about “travel”, they are usually referring to expensive excursions thousands of miles away from your home. But there’s no rule that says you have to go far away from your home in order to travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first step to a successful travel vlog is finding ways to travel, even to places that are close to home. You can visit parks, check out art galleries, take a train to a nearby city or drive to a neighboring state for a weekend excursion. Just make sure you’re getting out there! The audience wants to see a great story and you don’t have to travel thousands of miles to tell it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since most of us don’t have an unlimited budget, it’s important to keep your travels and activities cheap. Search Google for free things to do in your area or check our Groupon for cheap deals on fun activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;just-start-filming&quot;&gt;Just start filming&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any time a vlogger asks us where they should start, we always say the same thing, just start filming. It doesn’t matter if you’re hanging around your house talking about your upcoming travel plans or bringing the camera along while you visit a park with your family. The only way to learn how to vlog is to start making mistakes so you can learn from them. And the only way to do that is to pop the camera out and start filming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust me, once you overcome this initial hurdle, vlogging will become easier and easier. Eventually it will be second nature! So grab the camera, get out of the house and start creating videos you crazy creative creature!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-not-about-the-gear&quot;&gt;It’s not about the gear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vlogging is about 10% equipment and 90% story. Don’t waste your money by dumping it into expensive cameras and audio equipment. If people end up watching your vlog, it will be because of the great story you’re telling and the creative ways you tell it, not because your video was shot in 4k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Canon-PowerShot-ELPH-160-Silver/dp/B00RKNMORM/ref=sr_1_5?s=photo&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1457768026&amp;amp;sr=1-5&amp;amp;keywords=canon+powershot&quot;&gt;Here’s a simple little camera&lt;/a&gt; that is great for a beginner vlogger. If you can’t afford to buy a new camera, you can just use your smartphone. The camera on modern smartphones rival most entry level cameras anyways!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst thing you can do is sink a bunch of money into this new hobby only to find out it isn’t for you. Don’t make that mistake! Once you’ve built up some momentum and have gotten the hang of vlogging, having nicer equipment can give the vlog a polished feeling and make it feel more solid. But don’t jump the gun. Better equipment will only make your vlog marginally better. It’s the story that counts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started vlogging on a used Canon G7X, then eventually upgraded to a Sony a6000, which we also bought used. Check out one of our recent vlogs to get an idea of the quality you can produce with it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fr3DnW5qyXE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-do-it-for-the-money&quot;&gt;Don’t do it for the money&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because there is no money. Period. Not for the foreseeable future anyways. It will take a crap ton of blood, sweat, tears and time (a whole lotta time) before you develop a large enough audience to make a decent profit. Even with 100,000 video views, you’ll only make an estimated $100-$300 profit. Getting the picture?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start your travel vlog because you’re passionate about travel and want to inspire others to travel more. Try to have fun with it. If you’re not having fun, then vlogging might not be for you! Maybe try golf?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;connect-with-other-travelers&quot;&gt;Connect with other travelers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing you can do as a beginner travel vlogger is to connect with other travelers. Meeting other like minded people, whether online or in person, will help you feel like you’re not alone in this travel game. They can also be a great source of inspiration and drive you to keep traveling yourself!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram and Twitter are great resources for connecting with other travelers. We’ve already met so many great people through these networks! We also make a point to interact with other YouTubers who have travel focused channels. It’s like having a bit of a support group and is a great way to find other YouTubers to collaborate with. Speaking of collaborating, it’s a hugely effective way to grow your subscribers. Keep in mind, though, that this usually only works with channels that have similar subscriber counts as yours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully these tips help you get off on the right foot with your travel vlog. The most important thing of all, though, is to make sure you have passion. If you’re not passionate about travel, it will show through in your videos and you’ll likely not be able to keep up with vlogging anyways because you’ll get burnt out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if you think travel vlogging might be your calling, don’t be afraid to get out there and start filming. The first step is just turning the camera on and heading out on an adventure! Don’t wait until tomorrow, start vlogging right now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks a lot for reading. I really hope it was helpful! If you’d like to check out our vlog, head over to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCEDrRCC0qRtPd5-sSa1hajw&quot;&gt;our YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt;. We’re currently traveling the world and posting daily vlogs of our adventures. We’d love for you to come along with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2016 06:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-become-a-travel-vlogger.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-become-a-travel-vlogger.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>vlogging</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why West Texas Should Be Your Next Vacation Destination</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Teepees, cowboys, unexplainable lights in the sky, and some of the best views of your life are just a few of the amazing things west Texas has to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until recently, all I knew about west Texas was that it comprised about half of the state and that El Paso was somewhere out there. I even lived in south Texas for a few years (shout out to the Rio Grande Valley!) and have visited Texas least once a year for the past 10 years and never once made it out past San Antonio. What the west might be missing in big cities, shopping malls or gas stations, it more than makes up for with quirky small towns, beautiful scenery and amazing photo ops!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, if you’re heading to west Texas, you’ll need a car. I recommend flying into San Antonio or Austin and renting a car from there. But before you leave, you should probably spend at least a day in middle Texas drinking wine in the hill country [[link to our pic/post pic?]] and eating some delicious BBQ and Tex-Mex. I could (and probably should) write a whole post on the Austin area because I love it so dang much…but for now, back to west Texas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/wine-country.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;allison and eric drinking wine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so now that you have your car and a full, I repeat a FULL, tank of gas (gas stations are few and far between out there), pop on your shades, hop on I-90, and experience the awesomeness of 80mph speed limits. Oh and make sure you have plenty of daylight when you leave, because you’re not going to want to miss this amazing scenery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/texas-sunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Texas Sunset&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bandera&quot;&gt;Bandera&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so Bandera probably isn’t considered true “west Texas”, but it’s definitely a good start for your journey. The self-proclaimed &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.banderacowboycapital.com/&quot;&gt;Cowboy Capital of the World&lt;/a&gt;, the freakin world!!, is definitely the most authentic and adorable town. In Bandera, the deer roam freely, the beer is cheap, and the smokey bars are filled with denim-clad cowboys, live music, and line dancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/s/Bandera--TX--United-States?guests=&amp;amp;checkin=&amp;amp;checkout=&amp;amp;ss_id=8s3f81ph&amp;amp;source=bb&amp;amp;s_tag=Ykvqc6ni&quot;&gt;The Airbnb&lt;/a&gt; selection is also on point and super affordable. If you want to a truly authentic experience, go horseback riding at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.juniperhillstables.com/&quot;&gt;Juniper Hill Stables&lt;/a&gt; like we did or spend a day on a dude ranch if you want a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.banderacowboycapital.com/contents.cfm?pg=places_ranches&quot;&gt;more immersive experience&lt;/a&gt; and then head to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.11thstreetcowboybar.com/&quot;&gt;11th Street Cowboy Bar&lt;/a&gt; on a Wednesday night to grill your own meat in the company of some truly fascinating Texans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/horse-trail-ride.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;horse trail ride&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;marfa&quot;&gt;Marfa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If cowboys aren’t really your thing, then your first west Texas stop should definitely be Marfa, TX. The best way to explain Marfa is to imagine an abandoned desert town that’s been taken over by hipsters and filled with random art galleries, delicious food, sketchy bars, and great coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Seriously, this town it’s worth the drive alone! While you’re there, grab lunch at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.foodsharkmarfa.com/&quot;&gt;Food Shark&lt;/a&gt; where super famous people like Beyonce and myself have frequented. Then walk through the town (it’s a short and flat walk, I promise) and marvel at all the random museums and galleries. After your stroll, drive about 20 mins down the road to Valentine, TX and take a pic at &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Prada_Marfa&quot;&gt;Prada Marfa&lt;/a&gt; so you can be as cool as me and Beyoncé. Then head back towards Alpine at sunset to check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.visitmarfa.com/lights.php#.VtkgAJMrL-Y&quot;&gt;Marfa lights&lt;/a&gt;. I seriously couldn’t have fabricated a stranger, more perfect town than Marfa!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/prada-marfa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;prada marfa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our travel vlog of our day in Marfa to get a good feel for the town :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/uKAHpidcv7Q&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you plan ahead and have a little leeway with your budget, I highly recommend staying in a teepee or trailer at &lt;a href=&quot;http://elcosmico.com/&quot;&gt;Marfa’s El Cosmico&lt;/a&gt; campground - it’ll definitely give you the most authentic experience. Or if you’re like me and can’t seem to plan anything more than a couple weeks in advance, then definitely look for airbnbs in either &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/s/Marfa--TX--United-States?guests=&amp;amp;checkin=&amp;amp;checkout=&amp;amp;ss_id=3sy3sww9&amp;amp;source=bb&amp;amp;s_tag=l19obG27&quot;&gt;Marfa&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.airbnb.com/s/alpine--TX--United-States?checkin=&amp;amp;checkout=&amp;amp;guests=&amp;amp;ss_id=0i6k6svk&amp;amp;s_tag=ZEnmtN4i&quot;&gt;Alpine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;big-bend&quot;&gt;Big Bend&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a day or two of getting some of the strangest instagram pics around Marfa, it’s time to pack up and head south for some &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/adventures/travel-vlog-hiking-big-bend-the-greatest-view-of-our-lives.html&quot;&gt;mind-blowing views in Big Bend&lt;/a&gt;. I unfortunately only had time for a quick day hike there, but you could easily spend a week or weeks in the area!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a quick day trip, you should definitely check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.texashiking.com/Locations/ShowLocation.aspx?LocationID=1403&quot;&gt;Lost Mine Trail&lt;/a&gt; and just try to keep your jaw from dropping as you climb higher and higher. Pro tip: make sure to climb up one of the huge rocks at the top for the ultimate 360 views!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-cliff-big-bend.png&quot; alt=&quot;Allison cliff big bend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have more time there, definitely check out several hiking trails and kayak, canoe, and/or raft the river. And if you’re super adventurous/masochistic with time and money to burn, you can do up to a 21 &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bigbendrivertours.com/7to21day.html&quot;&gt;day guided river tour&lt;/a&gt; covering the entire 231 miles of the river.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out our epic vlog of our hike to the top of Big Bend:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;415&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fr3DnW5qyXE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;terlingua&quot;&gt;Terlingua&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either on your way in or out of Big Bend, you have to stop in Terlingua at least for a day to check out the remains of the Chisos Mining Company. Or if you’re like me and don’t necessarily love camping, it could also be your home base while you’re exploring Big Bend. Literally referred to as &lt;a href=&quot;http://ghosttowntexas.com/&quot;&gt;Ghost Town Texas&lt;/a&gt;, Terlingua is a fascinating glimpse into what old mining towns looked like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part is that unlike most ghost towns I’ve come across, this one is completely open and free, so explore and poke around the ruins to your heart’s desire! But watch out, I hear that some people have decided to go off the grid and have taken up residence in some of the old mining entrances and structures, so it’s probably best to do your exploring in the daylight. Then at sunset, head on over to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thestarlighttheatre.com/&quot;&gt;Starlight Theater&lt;/a&gt; for some yummy and unique grub, live music, and a drink (or several) with the locals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it! The ultimate guide to the least talked about, yet potentially most interesting part of Texas!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been out to west Texas? What was your favorite part? We’d love to hear about it! Leave a comment below or shout out to us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/why-west-texas-should-be-your-next-vacation-destination.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/why-west-texas-should-be-your-next-vacation-destination.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travel Vlog: Hiking Big Bend - The Greatest View of Our Lives</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An amazing view can change the way you see not only the world, but yourself. It can challenge your perception by showing you how small you truly are. It allows you to see our planet from a different angle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today we hiked the Lost Mines Trail at Big Bend National Park in southwest Texas. This land is as beautiful as it is desolate. It’s so massive that most of the time there isn’t another group of humans in site. It’s one place on Earth where it’s easy to feel alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d like a front row seat to our journey, check it out in our daily travel vlog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Fr3DnW5qyXE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we even got out of the car, our jaws had already dropped multiple times. The size of the cliffs and vastness of the canyons was hard for us to really understand. So mostly we just stared with our eyes wide, muttering things like “holy cow” and “where are we?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-view-big-bend.png&quot; alt=&quot;allison enjoying view at big bend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my wife Allison, the hike wasn’t much of a challenge. That’s no surprise when you consider that she works out hard for an hour a day six days a week. I, on the other hand, am still feeling the pain of the hike in both my back and my legs as I write this three days later. I should probably start exercising more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a mile into the hike, the trees opened up and we were greeted with an epic view of the road we had driven in on. It twisted and turned through the valleys until it disappeared into the distant mountains. Needless to say, we once again had to pick up our jaws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just then, a group of hikers crossed our paths and one of them muttered “You ain’t seen nothin yet”. And they were right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-cliff-big-bend.png&quot; alt=&quot;allison enjoying view at big bend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next mile was a cactus strewn, loose rock covered trek. It seemed that every quarter mile we stumbled upon a view that made the previous one seem like nothing special. We passed marker 18, then 19, slowly working our way to 24, which promised the greatest view of all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived at the top, silence fell over the group. When you’re faced with this level of beauty, there isn’t really much you can say. You quickly realize that words will only take away from the experience. From here, you could see all the way into Mexico. It wasn’t a harsh divide. Instead, the two lands blended together as the mountains faded off into the hazy distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-eric-big-bend.png&quot; alt=&quot;allison and eric at big bend&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spent over an hour at the top - it wasn’t nearly enough time. But life, with its pressing commitments and deadlines, has a way of pulling at you, no matter how peaceful you may feel in the current moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We took one last gaze over the huge expanse that is Big Bend, then we made a reluctant yet well paced march back to the bottom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An amazing view can change you. It can even be habit forming. After leaving Big Bend, we felt a craving for nature and adventure like never before. There’s something intoxicating about being that high up surrounded by such beauty and such certain death - one wrong step and splaaaat!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Endless Adventure has only just begun, but this day will be a tough one to top. But we’re up for the challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks a lot for reading. If you enjoyed this post, I hope you’ll consider subscribing for more articles just like this one. You can also keep up with our daily adventures on our YouTube Vlog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll see you on the road.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/adventures/travel-vlog-hiking-big-bend-the-greatest-view-of-our-lives.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/adventures/travel-vlog-hiking-big-bend-the-greatest-view-of-our-lives.html</guid>
        
        <category>vlogging</category>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        
        <category>adventures</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Check out These 6 Fun and FREE Things to Do in Daytona Beach</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you’re traveling to new places, budget is always a huge factor. We recently spent a week in Daytona, Florida and we were determined to stretch our budget as far as possible. We managed to have a ton of fun every day without spending an arm and a leg!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out these fun and free activities to do in Daytona, Florida:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stroll-through-dunlawton-sugar-mill-gardenshttpdunlawtonsugarmillgardensorgindexhtml&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://dunlawtonsugarmillgardens.org/index.html&quot;&gt;Stroll through Dunlawton Sugar Mill Gardens&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had to check this place out because the pictures online just looked amazing. We weren’t let down! We arrived and were instantly enamored with the beauty of the place. The walking paths are lined with foliage and vegetation, not to mention curious squirrels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://theendlessadventure.co/images/uploads/sugar-mill.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sugar mill gardens&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This place has an interesting history. There are a bunch of random dinosaur statues that are apparently remnants of a short lived amusement park called Bongoland. You can also take a stroll through the remains of the old sugar mill factory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The garden wasn’t very crowded when we visited. Just a few passers by. This was in January which is probably the off season, but we found it super relaxing and very photogenic. Definitely a must see spot if you’re visiting the Daytona Beach area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We paid a visit to the gardens in a recent vlog episode:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/keej3nX1TEM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tour-the-angel-and-phellps-chocolate-factoryhttpangellandphelpscomtourshtml&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://angellandphelps.com/tours.html&quot;&gt;Tour the Angel and Phellps Chocolate Factory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all had a bit of a sweet tooth, so we decided to take a tour of the Angel and Phellps Chocolate Factory in Daytona, Florida. As soon as we walked in, they handed free samples to us. I tried a fudge bar that was literally called “Amazing”. And let me tell you, as the name implies, it was amazing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We showed up around 2pm on a Wednesday and the place was rather crowded. Which isn’t much of a surprise considering that the tour is free and at the end they give out free chocolate! The tour gave us a fun, behind the scenes look at how they make all of their chocolate goodies from chocolate covered cherries, to chocolates in the shape of fish and seashells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the tour, you are able to pick a couple samples to try. I highly recommend the chocolate covered potato chips. They were so good it was stupid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;walk-the-daytona-beach-boardwalkhttpwwwdaytonabeachboardwalkcom&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.daytonabeachboardwalk.com/&quot;&gt;Walk the Daytona Beach Boardwalk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we were staying just down the road, we had to check out the Daytona Beach Boardwalk. Here you’ll find the usual boardwalk amenities: Huge hot dogs, rides, and crowds of tourists. We actually traveled here in the off season so it was manageable, but I’d hate to see how busy this place gets in the summer months!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The beach was great. Aside from almost being run over by minivans and jeeps (yep, you’re allowed to drive on the beach here. Weird right?). The sand was white and packed down, great if you’re looking to take a jog. The ocean breeze was light and cool. For the middle of January we all found it to be very refreshing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Boardwalk is definitely a must-go. So next time you’re in Daytona, why not grab hot dog, hop on the ferris wheel and chill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;explore-the-ponce-de-leon-lighthousehttpponceinletorg&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ponceinlet.org/&quot;&gt;Explore the Ponce de leon Lighthouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During our time in Florida, we were always on the hunt for epic views and photo ops. The Ponce De Leon Lighthouse did not let us down. This 175 foot tall lighthouse overlooks the Ponce Inlet beach. The views from the top were just amazing. We got lucky here too as we didn’t find it to be too crowded, but I can imagine how busy it might get&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://theendlessadventure.co/images/uploads/lighthouse-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ponce de leon lighthouse&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately it isn’t actually free to go up to the top, but at $6.95 for adults, it’s pretty cheap and worth the price, so we decided to include it anyways!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you’re visiting Daytona Beach, make sure you take time to visit the Ponce Lighthouse. It’s likely to be a highlight of your trip!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also visited the Ponce de Leon Lighthouse in a recent vlog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/keej3nX1TEM&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;visit-the-north-peninsula-sate-recreation-areahttpswwwfloridastateparksorgparknorth-peninsula&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.floridastateparks.org/park/north-peninsula&quot;&gt;Visit the North Peninsula Sate Recreation Area&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you’ve had your fill of tours and tourists, take a secluded and peaceful hike through the North Peninsula State Park. Parking is free and cars aren’t allowed on the beach, so you won’t have to worry about sharing the road. Plus there aren’t any tacky condos in sight which was probably our favorite part! Just pretty walking trails, sun-bathers, turtles, and blue herons. We also hear it’s a bird-watchers paradise, so if that’s your thing, make sure to bring your binoculars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;check-out-the-casements---john-d-rockefellers-summer-homehttpwwwthecasementsnet&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thecasements.net/&quot;&gt;Check out The Casements - John D. Rockefeller’s Summer Home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Casements was purchased in 1918 for &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_D._Rockefeller&quot;&gt;John D. Rockefeller&lt;/a&gt; and it served as his winter getaway during his retirement years. He ultimately passed away there in 1937.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While quite interesting, the Casements is a bit of an anomaly. After Rockefeller passed, it served as a girls’ preparatory school for 20 years. After which it fell into disrepair after it was ravaged by fires and severe weather. It was ultimately bought by the city of Ormund Beach and is now restores and serves as a cultural community center.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a price of free, it’s definitely worth checking out. And while much of the original substance of the house is long gone, there are enough pictures inside and interesting stories to read to make it a worthwhile visit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2016 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/six-fun-free-things-to-do-in-daytona-beach-florida.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/six-fun-free-things-to-do-in-daytona-beach-florida.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The 5 Best Vlogging Cameras for YouTube Beginners</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting out as a vlogger on YouTube is hard enough without having to stress over which camera to buy. There are a dizzying amount of DSLR, Mirrorless and Point-and-Shoot cameras on the market. So how do you decide which one is the best camera for a new vlogger?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we’ve been vlogging full-time on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCEDrRCC0qRtPd5-sSa1hajw&quot;&gt;our YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt; for a good while now and we’ve learned that there are specific things that matter most when searching for the right vlogging camera:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Price&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Size / Weight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Form Factor (swivel screen, touchscreen, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Features&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Quality (supporting at least 1080p)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In that order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most beginner vloggers are budget conscious, so price usually rules out higher end camera right out of the gate. And, honestly, you hit the point of diminishing returns pretty quickly here, or the point at which you spend a lot more money, but don’t see that big of an increase in camera quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily for you, cameras have been fairly commoditized and you can get a very good, affordable camera for a reasonable price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, based on the criteria I mentioned above, here are the best vlogging cameras for YouTube beginners, organized from cheapest to most expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;canon-powershot-s120&quot;&gt;Canon PowerShot S120&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This camera draws a line where decent vlogging camera start (in my humble opinion anyways!) With a price tag of around $399, it might still be a bit high for some vloggers budgets. But, if you check out used cameras on Amazon, you can easily get this camera for around $300.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://theendlessadventure.co/images/uploads/s120.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;canon powershot s120&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Super light and small&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1080p video&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tested: used by tons of vloggers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intuitive touchscreen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autofocus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Image stabilization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed lens. No switching, mixing and matching glass.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No swivel screen. This isn’t a &lt;em&gt;must&lt;/em&gt; for vloggers, but it helps a lot to be able to see what’s in the shot (and to make sure your hair is perfect before you hit record :)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No viewfinder, just the LCD screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With such a short list of cons, the Canon S120 is a really great camera for vloggers, especially when you’re just starting out on YouTube.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Canon-PowerShot-Digital-Optical-Full-HD/dp/B00EFILNV8&quot;&gt;Price it on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;canon-powershot-g7x&quot;&gt;Canon PowerShot G7X&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the camera we chose when we first started vlogging, and I think we made a great choice! It’s an all-around better camera than the S120, but it’s a bit more expensive at around $599. Here’s the breakdown:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://theendlessadventure.co/images/uploads/g7x.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;canon powershot g7x&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Super light and small&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1080p video&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swivel screen, tilts up 180 degrees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tested: this is a seriously popular camera with even the biggest vloggers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Intuitive touchscreen&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autofocus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Image stabilization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed lens. No switching, mixing and matching glass.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus ring make an awful clicky sound. Honestly I just steered clear of it altogether&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No viewfinder, LCD screen only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really can’t say enough good stuff about this camera. It’s super lightweight and versitile and the flip-up screen is just perfect for vloggers. And touch auto-focus ensures that you’re always focused on the right thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Canon-PowerShot-G7-Digital-Camera/dp/B00NEWYE12/ref=sr_1_1?s=photo&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1453953315&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=canon+g7x&quot;&gt;Price it on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sony-a6000&quot;&gt;Sony a6000&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently switched from the Canon G7X to the a6000. Now that isn’t to say that the a6000 is a better camera for vlogging than the G7X. It all depends on what you’re looking for. Personally, I wanted to be able to change lens and put a legit zoom lens on the body. I also wanted a more cinematic look at 24fps, where the G7X only does 30fps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This camera is even cheaper than some point-and-shoot cameras at around $698.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://theendlessadventure.co/images/uploads/a6000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sony a6000&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;24fps for a more cinematic feel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small and light when compared to higher end mirrorless cameras like the Sony A7r&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amazing autofocus. Seriously, works very well&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Screen tilts up and down. Note, it doesn’t swivel 180 degrees like the Canon G7X&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interchangeable lenses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heavy and bulky when compared to S120, G7x and RX100&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No in-body stabilization, but you can get a cheap lens that has this&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No swivel camera. Just means you might think you’re recording when you’re not or you might think something is in the shot when it’s not. I thought this would be a huge issue but it hasn’t really been so far&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No touchscreen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Sony-Mirrorless-Digital-Camera-16-50mm/dp/B00I8BICB2/ref=sr_1_4?s=photo&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1453953399&amp;amp;sr=1-4&amp;amp;keywords=sony+a6000&quot;&gt;Price it on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sony-nex-5rkb&quot;&gt;Sony NEX-5RK/B&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a really great camera by Sony. It’s light and has an intuitive physical design, which makes it a great camera for YouTube vloggers. It’s a bit more expensive than some Point-and-Shoot cameras on this list, but only by a bit, selling for around $777.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://theendlessadventure.co/images/uploads/nex.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;nex&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small and light&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swivel screen, tilts up 180 degrees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interchangeable lenses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autofocus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Image Stabilization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Touchscreen (though it’s resistive not capacitive, just means it’s a tad less responsive)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No viewfinder, LCD screen only&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Sony-NEX-5RK-Mirrorless-Digital-18-55mm/dp/B0090QXG92/ref=sr_1_1?s=photo&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1453953342&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=NEX-5RK%2FB&quot;&gt;Price it on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sony-rx100-iv&quot;&gt;Sony RX100 IV&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This camera is pretty much the king of the Point-and-Shoots. It’s about as popular among vloggers as the Canon G7X. And for good reason! It’s design and functionality is extremely comparable. The price, however, isn’t. The Mark IV sells for around $948.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://theendlessadventure.co/images/uploads/rx100.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;sony rx100 IV&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pros&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Super light and small&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1080p video&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Swivel screen, tilts up 180 degrees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tested: this is a seriously popular camera with even the biggest vloggers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Autofocus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Image stabilization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Retractable viewfinder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4k movie recording&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slow-motion movie recording&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cons&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fixed lens. No switching, mixing and matching glass.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No touchscreen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Sony-Cyber-shot-DSC-RX100-Digital-Camera/dp/B00ZDWGM34/ref=sr_1_2?s=photo&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1453953364&amp;amp;sr=1-2&amp;amp;keywords=sony+rx100&quot;&gt;Price it on Amazon&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s our breakdown of the best vlogging cameras for beginning YouTube vloggers. Keep in mind this is our own personal opinions. It’s up to you to figure out what works for you and to do the research to find the right one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks a lot for reading. If you found this helpful, we hope you consider &lt;a class=&quot;twitter-share-button&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/tweet?text=The 5 Best Vlogging Cameras for YouTube Beginners via @the_endless_a http://bit.ly/1nzJ6IU&quot; data-size=&quot;large&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;sharing it on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. If you have any questions or comments, you can leave those below or shoot us a message on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Happy vlogging!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2016 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/vlogging/five-best-vlogging-cameras-for-youtube-beginners.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/vlogging/five-best-vlogging-cameras-for-youtube-beginners.html</guid>
        
        <category>vlogging</category>
        
        
        <category>vlogging</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Tips to Make Your Next Road Trip Not Suck</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Road trips always sound adventurous and exciting, but in reality, if you’re covering a lot ground in a short amount of time, they can get pretty tedious. Add in bad weather, the horrible songs your friend keeps playing, and the mountain of trash and random souvenirs you pick up along the way which inevitably ends up between your legs, suddenly a road trip can easily turn into a one-way trip to hell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve spent countless hours on the road traveling from place to place. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=NUkvUX43zVk&quot;&gt;We often vlog our time on the road&lt;/a&gt; so that others can learn from our mistakes and, hopefully, be entertained :) So we know a thing or two about road tripping!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are some eseential road trip tricks we’ve picked up:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pack-a-few-games&quot;&gt;1. Pack a few games&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest way to pass the time is to play games! I’m not talking about lame stuff like I-spy or rock, paper, scissors (unless you’re into that!) but ones that are actually fun. When we said goodbye and set off on our adventure, our friends got us some pretty awesome games that so far have provided hours of entertainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;would-you-ratherhttpwwwamazoncomwould-rather-picture-card-gamedpb00wrftd4krefsr18ieutf8qid1451498114sr8-8keywordswouldyourather-and-story-cubeshttpwwwamazoncomgamewright-318-rorys-story-cubesdpb003eik136refsr13ieutf8qid1451498146sr8-3keywordsstorydice&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Would-Rather-Picture-Card-Game/dp/B00WRFTD4K/ref=sr_1_8?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1451498114&amp;amp;sr=8-8&amp;amp;keywords=would+you+rather&quot;&gt;Would You Rather&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Gamewright-318-Rorys-Story-Cubes/dp/B003EIK136/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1451498146&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;keywords=story+dice&quot;&gt;Story Cubes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This game definitely proved to be the biggest crowd pleaser. But be warned, it can be pretty gross and induce quite a bit of laughter :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cards&quot;&gt;Cards&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also got a pack of card games with minature playing cards and childhood goodies like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Imperial-Kids-Oversize-Card-Bundle/dp/B00YCQ63EK/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1451498367&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=card+game+bundle+go+fish+old+maid&quot;&gt;old maid and go fish&lt;/a&gt;. They really helped to pass the time. But be advised though! The card games are definitely more for passengers. Drivers, keep your eyes on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;phone-apps--websites&quot;&gt;Phone apps / websites&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t want to lug around dice and cards? Not a problem! You can download apps like &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/app/family-car-games/id315706203?mt=8&quot;&gt;Family Car Games&lt;/a&gt; which has 100 games you can play using only your noggin. You can find tons of trivia questions and brain teasers on the web to keep you both sharp and entertained. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.buzzfeed.com/kjh2110/10-logic-puzzles-you-wont-be-able-to-solve#.qw1JAB9gY&quot;&gt;These logic puzzles&lt;/a&gt; in particular had us stumped for many miles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;podcasts-and-audiobooks&quot;&gt;2. Podcasts and audiobooks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never got around to obsessively listening to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://serialpodcast.org/&quot;&gt;Serial podcast&lt;/a&gt;? Well, your trip across the country is the perfect time to binge it! If you’re traveling alone or with a group that can actually agree on what to listen to, audiobooks are a great way to keep you focused and entertained. But seriously, even if you’re not going on a road trip, you should listen to Serial anyways!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Road trips are also for sneaking in books you may not have been able to and/or were too embarrassed to make time for in your non-road trip life. Heck, if you’re going to be in the car for hours, might as well finally figure out what 50 Shades of Grey is all about, am I right ladies??&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;spotify&quot;&gt;3. Spotify&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you’re into mixtapes or burning CDs, Spotify is a must-have for trips. The premium version is only $9.99 which allows you to play whatever songs you want offline and COMMERCIAL FREE!!! So long pesky ads! It’s just you and your fave music. Aaaah sweet serenity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;chargers&quot;&gt;4. Chargers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I’ve recommended a lot of things that likely require you to use your phone or laptop, so you might be thinking “sure that all sounds great, but what do you do when your electronics die miss smarty pants?” Well nowadays, if you don’t already have a future-car with outlets and usb ports, you can easily transport your car into the 21st century with adapters. We picked up &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Upgraded-Version-BESTEK-Inverter-Charging/dp/B00EY6RJKA/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1453774583&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;keywords=car+outlet+adapter&quot;&gt;this little beauty&lt;/a&gt; which has both an outlet and usb port that plugs directly into your lighter. It’s been a lifesaver!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;waze&quot;&gt;5. Waze&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This app was recently listed in USA Today’s article &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.usatoday.com/story/tech/2015/12/29/10-most-essential-cant-live-without-apps/77994238/&quot;&gt;10 Most Essential, Can’t Live Without Apps&lt;/a&gt; and for good reason! Unlike Google and Apple maps, Waze relies on other commuters to report problems like temporary road closures, large accidents, heavy traffic, cops parked on the side of the road and it will automatically reroute you if the traffic delays are severe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to all the helpful crowd-sourced into, it also has a fun gaming component. For example, you can chat with other nearby users (hello love connection?) and gain points by reporting problems and driving through fruit…that sounds weird, but get the app and it’ll all make sense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waze has saved us so much money (no more speeding tickets!) and time (trafic alerts FTW!) that it’s become one of the most important elements of our travel arsenal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;limit-the-liquids-but-drink-plenty-of-water&quot;&gt;6. Limit the liquids (but drink plenty of water)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While sitting in your car for hours at a time might take a toll on your nerves, nothing sends me into a fury like stopping every 30 minutes because your car mates can’t figure out that starting your road trip with a gallon of coffee is a ridiculous idea. Now I’m not saying don’t drink any liquids or skip the caffeine, but you can avoid excessive stops by setting size limits on things like sodas and coffees or just sticking with water instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean let’s face it, no matter how much caffeine you have, you’re still going to be nodding off in the backseat an hour or two into the drive, so why not do your bladder and car mates a favor and get the 16oz instead of the 32oz!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so I know I literally just told you to limit the liquids, but seriously, you should always have water in the car! Odds are you’re not listening to my advice and still downing extra high levels of coffee and energy drinks, and not keeping up with your diet, but these can all be recipes for dehydration. Or worse you could get a flat tire, realize you forgot to replace the spare and be stranded for hours in the middle of nowhere until the tow-truck finally arrives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Either way, do yourself a favor and keep some water handy to keep you feeling good and hydrated all day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bring-snacks&quot;&gt;7. Bring snacks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on how many people are in the car, you may not have much extra space for goodies. But when someone inevitably gets hangry and the next exit is 30 miles away, you’ll be so happy you bought that bunch of bananas, or better yet, carrots and hummus, yum!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And while we’re talking about snacks, we can’t stress enough how important it is to grab somewhat healthy treats. Don’t get me wrong, I love munching on chips and candy, but when you’re literally sitting for an entire day with minimal activity, eating fast food, and likely not keeping up with your fruit and veggie intake, your body will thank you for eating peanut butter and an apple instead of a big gulp and a milky way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stop-strategically&quot;&gt;8. Stop strategically&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting in an uncomfortable seat in a cramped car and only stopping at rest stops really takes a toll on the body both mentally and physically. We’ve learned that a nice way to break up the drive is to find one or two really cool places along your route to stop and take a break. Whether it’s a cool restaurant, coffee shop, or the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.roadsideamerica.com/story/4031&quot;&gt;world’s largest pecan&lt;/a&gt; (yes, we stopped here), finding an interesting place to break during the day not only gives you something to look forward to but also gets you up and moving. By using a combination of Yelp and simply googling things like “interesting places along I-95”, we were able to find all kinds of neat restaurants, towns, and activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dress-comfy&quot;&gt;9. Dress comfy!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably a given, but wearing restricting clothing is definitely not the best idea for long days in the car. We’re not saying wear your pjs and slippers the whole time, but maybe wear comfortable leggings instead of tights or a cotton t-shirt instead of a button down. Also, consider bringing a small blanket and pillow. Nothing’s more annoying than silently freezing for hours or waking up to a crick in your neck from sleeping against the window!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://theendlessadventure.co/images/uploads/sleeping-in-car.png&quot; alt=&quot;neck hurting&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;stay-fresh-all-day&quot;&gt;10. Stay fresh (all day)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hygiene is probably not top of mind for most people when they think about car trips, but trust us, staying fresh makes all the difference. When possible, brush your teeth at rest stops, grab some disposable teeth and body wipes to use throughout the day and sprinkle a little dry shampoo in your hair. Even if you don’t mind being a disgusting mess at the end of the day, there are few things more offensive than 8-hour-old coffee breath and dried drool (excuse me while I barf)! Please at least make an effort stay clean for the rest of us!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it! Our best tips for making sure you have a great road trip and not a 10 hour long suck fest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have any road trip tips of your own? How about horror stories of road trips gone wrong? We want to hear about it! Leave us a comment below or &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_adventure&quot;&gt;reach out to us on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time, happy road tripping!&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/ten-tips-make-your-road-trip-not-suck.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/ten-tips-make-your-road-trip-not-suck.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>road-trip</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>December 2015 Financial Update - Let the Adventure Begin!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Our adventure has officially begun! Needless to say, we’re scared as heck. We’ve traded in our steady paychecks and permanent home for a life of travel and adventure. We have no idea where this year is going to take us and that definitely makes us nervous. But we’re also more excited than we’ve ever been about what the future holds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The decision to live a more nomadic lifestyle wasn’t one we made overnight. Thinking back, it all started around 2011 when we both took a trip to Paris. It was our first time exploring Europe and it was like a new world opened up to us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That trip made us realize that the world is huge and there’s so much out there that we haven’t experience. We also noticed that when we’re traveling we both just seem happier and much more productive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the dream of long term travel became less of a choice and more like something we &lt;em&gt;had&lt;/em&gt; to do. We knew we’d regret it if we didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But how the heck do we make this work?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overcoming-the-biggest-issue-with-longterm-travel&quot;&gt;Overcoming the biggest issue with longterm travel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest issue with longterm travel is figuring out how to make it work financially. Most of us can’t just drop everything and go travel the world. And the thought of not having a steady paycheck is scary!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used this as an excuse for a long time. The way we overcame it was by asking ourselves “What’s the worst that can happen?”. Since I’m a designer / developer, the worst case scenario is money gets a bit tight and I have to work a bit more. That doesn’t sound so bad!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Allison can work on getting some small remote contracts while we’re on the road or maybe do some paid content writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even if things got &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; bad, we could always head back to Missouri and live with our parents for a bit while we sorted things out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So what are we so afraid of?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long term travel is also tough when you have debt hanging over your head. We always seem to have at least a few thousand dollars lingering on a credit card. But we decided earlier this year that we were going to get it all paid off and never go into debt again. I’m happy to say that we managed to get it all paid off around October of last year (2015)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once our debt was paid off, we wanted to save up some money so we could have a bit of a safety net during our travels. So we set a lofty goal of saving up $10,000 by January 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way we spend, I honestly didn’t think this would be possible. But here’s how we did it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We sold most of our expensive items on craigslist (phones, cameras, monitors, etc..)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We stopped eating out and drinking so much. It’s amazing how quickly this all adds up!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We sublet our $1600/mo apartment for two months while we lived for free with a friend.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s funny, it seemed so much easier to save up money than it was to pay off debt. Currently all of our extra funds are sitting in a Betterment account. If you haven’t heard of Betterment, check it out. It’s an amazing service for investing your money without all the headache that comes along with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Saving up this money was hugely important because it helped to ease our minds before starting this journey. No matter what happens, we have that safety net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sticking-to-a-budget&quot;&gt;Sticking to a budget&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we decided that we were going to give the nomadic lifestyle a try, the first thing we did was create a hypothetical budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In San Francisco, we live on around $7,000 a month. We could probably make that same sort of money working remotely full-time, but the idea is to work less and spend more time having fun right?! So we shot for a budget of $3,000 per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here’s how we broke it down:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rent:&lt;/strong&gt; $1,000/mo $33/day&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Travel:&lt;/strong&gt; $500/mo $17/day&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Food:&lt;/strong&gt; $1,370/mo $46/day&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Cell Phones:&lt;/strong&gt; $100/mo $50/day&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Misc Expenses:&lt;/strong&gt; $30/mo&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honestly, this is probably a bit ambitious. It’s really more of a starting point. We’ll shoot for $3,000 a month, but I’m sure we’ll be adjusting this at the end of January.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We decided to put this budget to the test by taking a little trip to New York earlier in December. We quickly realized that the biggest issues is going to be food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breakfast is pretty easy, we’ll just need to make sure to hit up a market nearby market and grab the basics. Lunch and dinner are tougher since it’s unlikely that we’re going to pack sandwiches every day and head back to the AirBNB by 7pm to make dinner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So our food budget will likely need to be adjusted. We probably need to set aside specific days of the week that we eat out. That way we can control the spending a little bit. We’ll keep you posted on how this goes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;going-forward&quot;&gt;Going forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each month, we plan on releasing an update like this to share how things went from a financial perspective. Did we spend too much? Did we have to alter our budget? Are we flat broke?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making this thing work financially is going to be tough, but not impossible! Our hope is that this sort of transparency will inspire others to make the leap to a nomadic lifestyle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions at all feel free to hit us up on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Also be sure to &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/1Nnl2kq&quot;&gt;subscribe to our daily vlog&lt;/a&gt; so you can follow along on the adventure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading. Until next time, always be wandering.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 05:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/finances/financial-update-december-2015-let-the-adventure-begin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/finances/financial-update-december-2015-let-the-adventure-begin.html</guid>
        
        <category>adventure</category>
        
        <category>finances</category>
        
        
        <category>finances</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
