<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Endless Adventure | Travel Blog &amp; Daily Vlog</title>
    <description>Hi! We&#39;re Eric and Allison. We quit our full-time jobs and sold everything to travel full-time. We make daily vlogs of our travels and feature travel tips, hacks and photography.
</description>
    <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://theendlessadventure.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 12:55:36 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 12:55:36 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Surefire Ways to Get Traffic to Your New YouTube Vlog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you a fellow aspiring YouTuber? Creating great content but having a hard time getting your videos in front of potential subscribers? Well, we feel your pain!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been traveling the world and vlogging our adventures for the last 8 months. Since we began, we’ve learned a lot about how to drive traffic to your YouTube channel when you don’t have a huge social presence or a large following.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But first, a disclaimer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your content has to be good. Naturally, when your channel is your baby, it can be hard to tell if what you’re producing isn’t very good. Try asking for feedback from all of your friends and family members before pushing your content out to the masses. Try to ask them to provide objective feedback. This may be impossible, but it’s better than nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If there’s room for improvement, wait to promote your videos until you’ve reached a higher level of quality.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t promote our YouTube channel until we had already made almost 30 vlogs!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disclaimer over&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without further ado, here are 10 techniques you can use to drive traffic to your new YouTube vlog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;post-on-reddit&quot;&gt;Post on Reddit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While many subreddits are where content goes to die a horrible death, we’ve been able to generate quality traffic and subscribes from a few of them. Here are some subreddits where you can post your new vlog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/vlog&quot;&gt;/r/vlog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/NewTubers&quot;&gt;/r/NewTubers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/vlogging&quot;&gt;/r/vlogging&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/vlogger&quot;&gt;/r/vlogger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/vlogs&quot;&gt;/r/vlogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;twitter&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social media platforms like Twitter can be tricky to break into, but I still think it’s worth trying. Even if you only have 50 followers, you should still post your vlogs on Twitter. You never know when a follower might click, watch and subscribe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t stop at posting vlogs. Posting the same content all the time will cause people to eventually ignore your posts. Also try to post meaningful content that’s in your niche.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And make sure you take some time to reach out to others. Reply to their tweets, retweet them, post their blog content. The more you share, the more people are likely to share your content and follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;facebook&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Facebook is pretty similar to Twitter. You want to post your vlogs consistently, but you don’t want to &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; post vlogs. Work on posting useful content within your niche. Before you’ll know it you’ll have a handful of likes and the snowball effect will begin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;instagram&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instagram can be a bit trickier, but is nevertheless a great platform for generating YouTube views.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, always be &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.socialmediaexaminer.com/instagram-hashtags/&quot;&gt;hashtagging your photos&lt;/a&gt;  so you can squeeze as much social juice out of each post as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you post a new vlog, post a screenshot from the video or the thumbnail and push users to check it out. There’s a caveat though. Instagram doesn’t allow you to include links within posts. Instead, put LINK IN BIO after your photo comment and make sure your bio links to your YouTube channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/instagram.png&quot; alt=&quot;promote vlog on instagram&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For bonus points, use &lt;a href=&quot;https://bitly.com/&quot;&gt;bit.ly&lt;/a&gt; to track your bio link and see how many people actually click it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title-and-thumbnail-your-video-properly&quot;&gt;Title and thumbnail your video properly&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A proper title and an interesting thumbnail can go a long way in driving eyeballs to your videos. Watch time is the most important factor in determining a video’s quality, but a proper title, description and tags still help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A simple trick you can use is to type relevant keywords into the YouTube search bar and see what it auto suggest. Presumably these are popular phrases people are searching for. So, if you include these phrases in your video title, it may do better in search results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/search-results.png&quot; alt=&quot;youtube search results&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also try to title your videos similar to other similar and semi-popular YouTube videos. Keyword here is &lt;em&gt;similar&lt;/em&gt; - not the same! This may increase the potential that your video shows up as a recommended video alongside these other videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/related-videos.png&quot; alt=&quot;related youtube videos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comment-on-popular-youtubers-videos&quot;&gt;Comment on popular YouTubers’ videos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s true that the comments section on YouTube is often full of trolls, morons and other generally stupid people. BUT, it is still possible to have a normal discussion about the videos you’re watching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since our videos are travel related, we’ll often engage in discussions on channels like funforlouis or mrbenbrown. We’ve found that if you add to the conversation in a meaningful way, other commenters might click your username and view your channel. And if they find it interesting, they might even subscribe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve been able to generate consistent subscribers and views this way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s important to make sure you’re interacting on channels that are relevant to yours. This just means it’s more likely their viewers might &lt;em&gt;also&lt;/em&gt; be interested in your channel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/popular-comments.png&quot; alt=&quot;popular youtuber comments&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;comment-on-smaller-youtubers-videos&quot;&gt;Comment on smaller YouTubers’ videos&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Commenting on smaller YouTubers is also a great way to generate views and subscribers. But the key here is quality over quantity. Always leave positive or helpful comments and &lt;em&gt;never&lt;/em&gt; ask the YouTuber to view or subscribe to your channel. Trust me, if you leave a meaningful comment and have interesting content of your own, they’ll find their way to your channel page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding smaller YouTubers is easy. Just search “first youtube video” or “first vlog” on Twitter. You can also view the subreddits I mentioned above to find smaller YouTubers to interact with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/smaller-youtuber-comments.png&quot; alt=&quot;smaller youtube comments&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;post-in-yttalk-forum&quot;&gt;Post in yttalk forum&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;yttalk.com&quot;&gt;Yttalk&lt;/a&gt; forums are full of other YouTubers of all channel sizes. And in addition to being a great place to find help with your channel and feedback on your videos, it’s also a great way to find potential viewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of your fellow YouTubers are YouTube viewers themselves. So the more you interact on the forums, the more likely it is that they will click your channel and possibly subscribe!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;post-on-empirekred&quot;&gt;Post on empire.kred&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://empire.kred/&quot;&gt;Empire.kred&lt;/a&gt; is a place where you can post your content and push other influencers to engage with it. Based on your social media influence, you’re given a stock value in eaves (which is their digital currency). Other influencers can buy “stock” in you, which in turn puts eaves in your pocket.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eaves can be used to create missions which are basically tasks that you give to other influencers, i.e. watch my latest video, view this tweet, view this photo, etc. But the catch is you can’t specifically ask for engagement, i.e. likes, comments, shares. Instead, it’s up to the user to decide for themselves how they’d like to engage with your content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When someone accomplishes your mission, they are paid a sum in eaves that you decide when you post the mission.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like that you aren’t specifically allowed to ask someone to subscribe to your channel in order to accomplish a mission. Presumably, this means if someone from Empire.Kred subscribes, it’s because they are interested in your channel and want to see more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/empire-kred.png&quot; alt=&quot;empire kred&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interact-with-every-single-comment-you-receive&quot;&gt;Interact with every single comment you receive&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to YouTube success is building a community. As your community grows, more and more people will return to your videos and interact with them via likes, shares and comments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try to respond to all of your video comments as quickly as possible. This shows your viewers that there’s a real person on the other end and will make them much more likely to engage with your other videos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve had some viewers that have been commenting on our videos since the very beginning. If we hadn’t consistently responded to their comments, they might not have become a regular viewer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/youtube-vlog-traffic/youtube-comment.png&quot; alt=&quot;youtube-comment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it, 10 surefire ways to get traffic to your new YouTube vlog. When you’re starting out on YouTube, it can be daunting trying to gain an initial user base. The key is to start small. Set a goal of 10 subscribers, then 50, then 100, then 500. If you’re consistently producing interesting content and using the techniques above, you’ll see consistent growth to your YouTube channel guaranteed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve found this article helpful, I hope you’ll consider sharing it with your network. And if you have any tips of your own to add, leave a comment below or reach out to us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2016 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/vlogging/ten-surefire-ways-get-traffic-new-youtube-vlog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/vlogging/ten-surefire-ways-get-traffic-new-youtube-vlog.html</guid>
        
        <category>vlogging</category>
        
        
        <category>vlogging</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How We Almost Got Pickpocketed in Berlin and How You Can Avoid It</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We recently had a scary moment in Berlin’s Großer Tiergarten. We were taking pictures in a somewhat secluded area of the garden when a man came up asking for donations for a deaf charity. He had a clipboard with a formal looking sign up sheet and everything. We politely declined the request and turned to walk away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so at this point you may be thinking “what heartless jerks refusing to donate to a deaf charity!! Only savages would decline donating to such a cause!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normally, I’d probably be thinking something similar, &lt;strong&gt;but&lt;/strong&gt; just a couples days prior to the event, we’d taken a walking tour during which our guide told us about a popular scam where people pretend to collect money for the deaf and mute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-scam-goes-something-like-this&quot;&gt;The scam goes something like this&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Oh hey would you like to donate to a deaf charity?”&lt;br /&gt;
“Oh, maybe! Tell me more about this charity?”&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;someone bumps into you while you’re distracted&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
“Oh, sorry sir!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boom, you’ve been pickpocketed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s actually a popular scam across Europe that you can read about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.corporatetravelsafety.com/safety-tips/deaf-mute-scams-in-europe/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So back to our encounter. The deaf charity donation request was our first tip-off. The next red flag moment came after we politely declined. The man became increasingly more persistent and aggressive with his tone and proceeded to walk after us. But what was most terrifying about the encounter was that as we turned back to assess the situation, we realized that three other men with clipboards had started rushing towards us and were all yelling at us in German.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started walking away faster and eventually started running as they quickened their pace. Luckily after a few moments of us running and them yelling, they finally relented and walked off down another empty path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were extremely lucky that we had been given a heads up about the scam. Especially because that day we had our laptops, cell phones, camera, and GoPro on us, plus a little spending money and a credit card. Had we realized what was happening a moment later or had the men continued to chase us, it could have been extremely devastating to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parents, concerned friends, and seasoned travelers alike will all tell you to stay safe when you start traveling. And at first, the newness of travel will automatically keep you on higher alert. But after a while, you get pretty used to life on the road and tend to let your guard down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t say this to make you paranoid or scared to go out and explore a new city, we just want you to travel smart. Especially when it’s obvious you’re a tourist - aka you’re not speaking their language, you’re carrying a camera and/or backpack, you have google maps pulled up, etc…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-how-do-you-avoid-situations-like-this&quot;&gt;So, how do you avoid situations like this?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, sadly there’s no fool-proof solution. But there are a lot of things you can do to reduce your odds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take a moment to scan your surroundings, especially in touristy areas.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If you’re using a camera, use a wrist or neck strap so it’s always connected to you. (Bonus point: this will also save you from accidentally dropping your camera! Win-win!)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;As tempting as it can be, don’t ever put your phone, wallet or any other valuables in your back pockets or the mesh side pockets of your backpack. Just don’t do it!!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Invest in a purse that has multiple barriers to entry with clasps, drawstrings, zippers and/or buckles. And &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; wear your purse across your chest and to the front. Think you’ll look silly? Well guess again, because it’s actually &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.whowhatwear.co.uk/how-to-wear-cross-body-bag-purse-fashion-winter-2014/&quot;&gt;cool&lt;/a&gt;  and practical!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Always do a quick google search before you go to a new city to familiarize yourself with common scams in the area. Travel blogs and tourism sites are great resources to help you figure out things to watch out for on your travels.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Be wary of beggars. I know that sounds heartless, but pickpockets and thieves are smart and have been known to use children, the elderly and pretty women to lure you in. Instead of giving your money in person, go online later and donate to the charity. If you’re feeling super compelled to help a person out, give them some food or a care package while keeping your money safely hidden away.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Try to avoid using physical maps to navigate around a new city. Not only does this scream tourist, but it also leaves you extremely vulnerable. Instead, try to get a handle on your route ahead of time or step into a coffee shop to get your bearings.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Get travelers insurance! Okay, so this isn’t a way to prevent pickpocketing, but it is a way to ease your mind should something happen.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have you had a close encounter like ours? What’s the most valuable travel lesson you’ve ever learned? Let us know in the comments section below or shout out to us on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/pick-pocketed-in-berlin-how-to-avoid-it.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/pick-pocketed-in-berlin-how-to-avoid-it.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Our 7 MUST HAVE Travel Items</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When you’re packing for a trip, obvious things come to mind: clothing, shoes, passport, cell phone, travel-sized shampoo… But once you get on the road, there are some not-so-obvious items that can make all the difference!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some of the items we don’t travel without.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;toothbrush-holder&quot;&gt;Toothbrush Holder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our smallest, but probably favorite travel item is our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Evriholder-FLP-TH-2PK-FlippIt-Toothbrush-Holders/dp/B003FO0O4U/ref=sr_1_2?s=home-garden&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1464789998&amp;amp;sr=1-2&amp;amp;keywords=suction+cup+toothbrush+cover&quot;&gt;suction cup toothbrush covers&lt;/a&gt;! These awesome little guys act as a holder and cover so you can easily and sanitarily store your toothbrush both at your Airbnb and in your bag. The suction cup means no more laying your toothbrush on yucky sinks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you do a little digging, you can find them in all sorts of styles and colors :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;day-pack&quot;&gt;Day Pack&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We might be living out of our big backpacks, but having a smaller day pack is a lifesaver! Trust us, you definitely don’t want to lug around your big bag when you’re just out for a day hike, doing some sightseeing or getting a little work done at a coffee shop. Instead, bring a small, lightweight travel bag!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From our experience it’s best to grab one with a built-in laptop sleeve and mesh side pockets to store water bottles and train tickets!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t put valuables in the side pockets though! There’s nothing more enticing to pickpockets than a big shiny phone staring them in the face. We actually &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fwTj1ibOIcs&quot;&gt;had a close call with this in Berlin&lt;/a&gt; :o&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;portable-charging-brick&quot;&gt;Portable Charging Brick&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we’re out and about, we’re constantly pulling up train schedules, translating menus with Google Translate, looking up yummy bars and coffee shops and keeping up with social media. Basically what that means is our cell phones rarely last the entire day. And take it from us, you don’t want to be out in a foreign city at 3am with no cell phone!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why we highly recommend investing in a portable usb charger. We love the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1Pkvc9Q&quot;&gt;Moonstone charger&lt;/a&gt; in particular because you can charge multiple devices at a time and it has awesome charging power. The carry case is a bit bulky so if you’re traveling long-term, you might want to look for a smaller one (or just ditch the case!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;beats-audio-headphones&quot;&gt;Beats audio headphones&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we started traveling, we both had large, over-ear headphones. While they were great at canceling out noise on airplanes and in coffee shops, we quickly realized that they just weren’t practical with our limited bag space. We started searching for smalle headphones and found these &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1WYUmgI&quot;&gt;Beats Audio In-Ear Headphones&lt;/a&gt; and haven’t turned back!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They give you the base and noise cancellations of over-ear headphones but take up literally no space! They also come with several earpiece sizes so you’ll always have a perfect fit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dr-bronners-soap&quot;&gt;Dr. Bronner’s Soap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve mentioned &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1WYUpJr&quot;&gt;Dr. Bronner’s Magic (yes, magic!) Soap&lt;/a&gt; before and will likely keep on mentioning it because it’s one of our favorite toiletry items! It literally does it all - well, at least &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.businessinsider.com/14-uses-for-dr-bronners-soaps-2013-11?IR=T&quot;&gt;14 things&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It comes in all sorts of shapes, sizes and fragrances and we use it as our body wash, shaving gel, face wash, and laundry detergent. It’s a great space-saver, plus it’s organic! Just maybe don’t pay too much mind to the writings on the label… Dr Bronner was an eccentric man, to say the least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;passport-holder&quot;&gt;Passport holder&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traveling means you’ll want to have easy access to important documents like your passport and boarding pass. But you don’t want to have those items in your purse or pocket or any other place that’s easy to pickpocket, leave behind, or for it to fall out of. So, while it may not look that cool or fashionable, a passport holder actually comes in really handy if you wear it correctly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wearing it across your chest and under your shirt or jacket will keep it out of sight, while still giving you quick access to the documents you need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;camera-clip&quot;&gt;Camera clip&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iphone cameras have come a long way, but most travelers still opt to bring along a nicer camera to really capture their adventures. Sure, you could strap it on with the classic neck strap, but if you want to really go hands free and be a bit more discreet, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://amzn.to/1qyH7Ui&quot;&gt;CapturePRO Camera Clip&lt;/a&gt; is an amazing investment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It hooks easily to your belt or bag strap and securely locks your camera in place. We’ve been using it with our A6000 for months now and absolutely love it! It’s super solid and well built. That camera isn’t going anywhere!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are definitely tons of must-have travel items out there, but these are the ones that have come in super handy for us on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your must have travel items? Leave a comment and let us know or shoot us a message on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/our-seven-must-have-travel-items.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/our-seven-must-have-travel-items.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Travel Vlog: The Most Famous Statue in Brussels</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Brussels is a beautiful city with stunning architecture and a unique past. And, for some reason, they are obsessed with a statue of a peeing baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re currently traveling through Europe and every time we land in a new city, the first thing we do is book a free walking tour. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neweuropetours.eu/&quot;&gt;Sandeman’s&lt;/a&gt; hosts free walking tours all throughout Europe and it’s an amazing way to get to know a new city. Once you’ve learned about a city’s history, you always feel a bit more connected to it. It forces you to appreciate it more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our walking tour took us all over the streets of Brussels. We even saw the most famous statue in brussels (and apparently the 3rd most famous statue in the world?), called the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manneken_Pis&quot;&gt;Manneken Pis&lt;/a&gt;. In spite of being (purportedly) world famous, we hadn’t ever heard of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wouldn’t say we wer underwhelmed by it, more so just confused. It’s basically exactly what it sounds like. A statue of a peeing baby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/gd-OsV-4dLY&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall we had an amazing day getting to know Brussels a little bit better. Between the waffles, rich history and peeing baby statue, there’s a lot to like about this place :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/the-most-famous-statue-in-brussels.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/the-most-famous-statue-in-brussels.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>vlogs</category>
        
        <category>vlogging</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Best Cellphone Plan for Americans Traveling in Europe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the first questions we asked ourselves when we decided we were going to travel fulltime was “How the heck do we get cellphone coverage when we travel to a new country every month!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re only traveling for a short period of time, this post isn’t for you. But if you’re making travel a lifestyle (or at least traveling for long periods of time) then you’ll find this helpful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chronic travelers have a few options when it comes to overseas data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;buy-a-sim-card-in-every-country-you-visit&quot;&gt;Buy a sim card in every country you visit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can work well if you’re going to be spending a lot of time in a single country. You can usually get 2-5GB of data for around $30-$50, and that will usually last 2-4 weeks if you’re data conscious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We thought about giving this strategy a try, but ultimately decided it wouldn’t work for us. The main reason being that we planned on moving around quite a bit, never spending more than a few weeks in single country. We didn’t really want sim cards piling up with unused data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;use-wi-fi&quot;&gt;Use wi-fi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We actually did this for the first months of traveling, mainly because we hadn’t yet figured out what the heck to do about cell phone coverage. This strategy works, but damn is it annoying. We were constantly searching for wi-fi and trying to leech off of restaurants and hotels. We just weren’t able to stay connected enough throughout the day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;get-a-european-cell-phone-plan&quot;&gt;Get a European cell phone plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a bit of research, I found a company called &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.gosim.com/&quot;&gt;Go Sim&lt;/a&gt; which offered sim cards specifically for data while traveling in European countries. In fact, it actually works in a whopping 100 countries! It sounded too good to be true! Well, it sort of was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1GB of data will cost you around 110 EUR. We had budgeted around $100 USD &lt;em&gt;total&lt;/em&gt; for our monthly data costs, so that just wasn’t going to work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a bunch of other companies like Go Sim, but we just couldn’t find one that offered data for a low enough cost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;t-mobile-international-plan&quot;&gt;T-mobile international plan&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we decided to see what the more well known carriers could offer. AT&amp;amp;T’s international plans were a joke, so we pulled up &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.t-mobile.com/&quot;&gt;T-mobile&lt;/a&gt; to see if they have any good plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out they have a “Simple Choice” plan which gives you unlimited data (switches to 2G once you run out of your monthly allotment) in 140 countries. 140! And they even had a special offer running, 6 GB of monthly highs-peed data for $50 per line. That put us right at the $100 mark for 2 lines, hooray!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Best of all, there’s no contract. So if we ever want to cancel and go back to AT&amp;amp;T (God forbid) we can do that in an instant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ordered our sim package, popped them in our unlocked phones, activated them online and BAM, we we’re back in the beautiful world of data. We’ve been on this plan for around 2 months and really don’t have many complaints. Naturally, the speeds can be a bit slow depending on which country you’re in, but it’s better than nothing and &lt;em&gt;much&lt;/em&gt; better than worrying about buying a new sim card each time we land.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I definitely understand that this cell phone plan isn’t for every traveler, and you should definitely do your research before starting any contracts! But if you travel to a new country every 1-3 weeks, it really is the perfect plan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 16:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/best-cellphone-plan-for-americans-in-europe.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/best-cellphone-plan-for-americans-in-europe.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>9 Travel Tips You Probably Haven&#39;t Heard Before</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of travel tip posts out there, but they’re usually about picking the right luggage and the proper tshirt rolling technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t get me wrong, packing guides can be helpful (I mean heck, &lt;a href=&quot;http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-ditch-the-clutter-and-travel-light.html&quot;&gt;I even wrote one&lt;/a&gt;). But since we started traveling full-time, there have been a bunch of things we had to learn the hard way. Things that weren’t listed on most of the guides we read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we made a list from our own experiences in hopes they’ll help you avoid embarrassing tourist moments and give you a bit more confidence on the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;double-check-liquid-restrictions-at-airports&quot;&gt;Double check liquid restrictions at airports&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We used to think the TSA (Transportation Security Administration) was hardcore with their liquids policy, but boy were we terribly mistaken!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As full time travelers, we never know what amenities our next Airbnb will have, so we’re constantly carrying a billion travel-sized bottles of shampoos, body wash, contact solution, hair gel, toothpaste, lotions, hairspray… you get the picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’d recently taken flights from Barcelona and Dubrovnik without any issues though, so imagine our surprise when the security agents in Copenhagen’s airport started freaking out as soon as our carry ons went into the scanners. They stopped the entire line and had us open our severely over-stuffed bags to show them all the liquids we were “hiding”. Talk about a stressful tourist moment!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out, not only are you supposed to take all of your liquids completely out of your carry on luggage in Copenhagen’s airport, but you’re also supposed to stuff them all into one (and only one!) impossibly small plastic baggie. (We’ve since found that it’s the same flying out of Berlin, but they weren’t as strict.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/bag.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pic of plastic baggie&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, we ended up throwing away about half of our supplies, most of which were new, not-cheap items :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lesson learned: &lt;strong&gt;always double check the airport security policies before getting to the front of the line.&lt;/strong&gt; You can use &lt;a href=&quot;http://europa.eu/youreurope/citizens/travel/safety/air-security/index_en.htm&quot;&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt; to make sure you’re complying with all of the EU’s travel policies and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tsa.gov/travel/security-screening&quot;&gt;this one&lt;/a&gt; for when you’re flying in the US. If you still have questions, I’m sure an extra friendly airport attendant will be only mildly annoyed if you ask for clarification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and one last thing: &lt;strong&gt;always make sure to check your airline’s carry on policies!&lt;/strong&gt; Though we’ve yet to see these policies heavily enforced, a lot of European budget airlines have stricter size and weight limits than in the states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;check-for-major-events-and-holidays-happening-during-your-stay&quot;&gt;Check for major events and holidays happening during your stay&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not once, but twice now we’ve arrived in a new city excited for a fun day of exploring only to find it’s a national holiday and everything’s closed. Bummer! While it’s interesting to experience holidays in other cities and countries, it can also mean that trains, grocery stores, and museums may have restricted hours or closures during your stay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Holidays and festivals may also be the reason you’re having a hard time booking an affordable hotel or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.airbnb.com/c/abieller&quot;&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt; during your stay. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timeanddate.com/calendar/info.html&quot;&gt;timeanddate.com&lt;/a&gt; to see if there are any major holidays falling during your stay. And a quick peek at the city’s website or facebook pageshould give you a list of any festivals or big events in the area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;take-a-free-walking-tour&quot;&gt;Take a free walking tour!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were recently turned on to the amazingness of free walking tours and we can’t recommend them enough!! The people who lead them work on tips so basically it’s up to you to decide how much the tour is worth. And they are seriously the most excited people we’ve ever encountered. It’s a great way to get a feel for a new city, meet fellow travelers, and get some exercise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our favorite tour company is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.neweuropetours.eu/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Sandemans&lt;/a&gt;. Definitely check their website to see if they have a free walking tour in the city you’re visiting!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pro tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Your guide will usually offer a free map. Snatch that baby up and have them mark all the cool places you should go while you’re in town!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/guide.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;tour guide&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wait-a-day-before-making-assumptions-about-a-new-city&quot;&gt;Wait a day before making assumptions about a new city&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While travel days are typically super exciting, they’re almost always really stressful - especially when you’re traveling to a new country. You arrive stale and jetlagged, have to deal with the nightmare that is customs, and then have to navigate a new public transportation system, often in a foreign language, using a foreign currency.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, you’re probably not the happiest of camper by this point and are a lot more inclined to project that negativity on the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently made this mistake when we arrived to a cold and rainy Berlin, exhausted from carrying our bags all day. And unbeknownst to us, it was a holiday so nothing around us was open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of doing something fun, we just had a dreary night in our little apartment eating Chinese food, watching Saving Private Ryan and second guessing our choice to visit Berlin. (In retrospect, we agree that those were probably the weirdest choices for someone’s first night in Berlin…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we woke up refreshed and determined to have a better day. We ended up finding an awesome coffee shop to work from… okay maybe Berlin isn’t so bad, we thought. Then we happened upon an even more awesome lunch spot… 2 for 2 - we’re starting to warm up to you, Berlin! Finally, we ended the evening at a really cool bar with super cheap beers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out Berlin wasn’t the problem - our attitudes were the problem!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We let our emotions dictate our experience instead of appreciating where we were. Since that first day, we’ve fallen more in love with Berlin each day and are having a blast exploring the history and culture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lesson learned:&lt;/strong&gt; Berlin is intense and badass and cool and we’re sorry we were mad at you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;make-sure-you-take-waterproof-shoes&quot;&gt;Make sure you take waterproof shoes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tip may sound a bit silly, but spending your day (or days) walking around with wet socks and soaked shoes is not very fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the year we visited New York City thinking it would be springtime weather, but apparently the city still thought it was winter. It was rainy with near freezing temperatures the entire week! Within 5 minutes of leaving our Airbnb my shoes were completely soaked through and my toes were frozen. No bueno!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do yourself a favor and either take some waterproof shoes or, for all you DIYers, do like this crazy Russian dude and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lifehack.org/articles/lifehack/how-make-your-shoes-waterproof.html&quot;&gt;coat your shoes in wax&lt;/a&gt; to keep your toesies and shoes happy and dry on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took the less scrappy approach and just bought some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.de/Dr-Martens-Unisex-Erwachsene-Bootsschuhe-Erwachsene/dp/B000BNWOWS/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1464018103&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;amp;keywords=dr+martens&quot;&gt;badass leather boots&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/boots.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pic of me in the rain wearing my boots&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;always-look-up-public-transportation-options-in-advance&quot;&gt;Always look up public transportation options in advance.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public transportation has hands down caused the most frustration during our travels. It’s really pretty mind boggling how every city can have such different processes and signage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some have zone systems that can be almost impossible to decipher. Others have aboveground lines and underground lines which can get really confusing when you’re standing next to a station and keep “missing” the train only to find out it’s underneath you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some systems, like the one in Berlin, require you to validate your card in a separate machine. And if you forget (or in our case have no idea that’s a thing), you’ll definitely be handed a ticked by the conductor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you stay in a city for a while, you may never get a great handle on their system. But having a general understanding of the system in advance goes a long way. At least knowing how to get from the airport to your hotel will save you tons of stress and ensure you’re not waiting around at the train station instead of exploring a new city!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-train-station.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;waiting at train station&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;learn-the-basics-of-the-language&quot;&gt;Learn the basics of the language&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going to a country where they speak a foreign language is stressful. But if you learn just a few basic phrases, you’ll be amazed at how much more at ease you’ll feel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to say “hello”, “I would like one, please” and “thank you” will ensure that you’re at least able to order confidently at any restaurant or coffee shop! Also, being able to say “excuse me” if you need to ask someone a question or sneak by someone (it happens more often than you think!) is extremely useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning everyday phrases will not only let the locals know you’re trying to meet them halfway, but it’ll also dramatically lessens your stress levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are the phrases that have come in most handy for us:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hello&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sorry!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Excuse me&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How much does this cost?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Where is the restroom?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;One (two, three) please&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thank you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;calculate-the-full-cost-of-staying-in-the-city-vs-outside-the-city&quot;&gt;Calculate the full cost of staying in the city vs outside the city&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying outside of the city center can be a great way to save big while you’re traveling. But one thing we’ve learned is that the savings don’t always outweigh the transportation time and costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recently stayed in a neighborhood about 30 minutes outside of Copenhagen because everything in the city was pretty expensive. What we didn’t take into account was the $11 USD we’d have to pay to get to and from the city &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the hour or more we’d waste commuting every day. We had 5 people staying in the house, which means we were paying $55 extra each day. That ended up being more than the amount we saved in rental fees!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a pretty painful and expensive lesson to learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But since you took my advice and googled the public transportation at your upcoming destination, you already have a good guess as to how much you’ll be spending to get around!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;always-carry-snacks&quot;&gt;Always carry snacks!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You never know when your flight will be delayed or when you’ll miss your train because you can’t punch the buttons on the damn ticket machine fast enough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always having a piece of fruit or some nuts tucked away requires little planning and will keep your evil, hangry side at bay. Snack bars are also a great option - just make sure it’s high in protein and not sugar so it sustains you for a while. We love &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epicbar.com/&quot;&gt;Epic Meal Bars&lt;/a&gt;, but sadly they are not always available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bonus Tip:&lt;/strong&gt; Always carry around at least a small bottle of water. For some reason water is not always free or readily available when you’re traveling. We specifically bought day bags which have little pouches on the outside, perfect for a water bottle and super handy too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-tips/nine-travel-tips-probably-havent-heard-before.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-tips/nine-travel-tips-probably-havent-heard-before.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Most Incredible Places To Visit In Dubai</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dubai is one of the most modern and newest cities in the world. In recent years, Dubai has gained popularity as one of the top destinations for travelers. Can you believe that just over 40 years ago it was all desert and sand dunes? It is quite hard to imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Dubai aims to be the biggest and best city on earth. Their goal is to make the impossible, possible. I feel so lucky to have visited this magical city and excited to share the most incredible places to visit in Dubai!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;burj-khalifa&quot;&gt;Burj Khalifa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dubai has created the world’s tallest structure, The Burj Khalifa, which stands at 829.8 m. The 124th observation deck is quite a place to experience! The best time to visit is during sunset and night time to catch the beautiful skyline views. Another record-breaking attraction in Dubai is the Dubai Fountain located below the Burj Khalifa, which is currently the largest choreographed fountain in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;burj-al-arab&quot;&gt;Burj Al Arab&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Burj Al Arab is one of the tallest hotels in the world. It is a luxurious 5 star hotel and also one of the most expensive hotels in the world. If you’re a budget traveler, you can visit the hotel without having to spend a night by making reservations at one of their restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One unbelievable thing here is the view from the top of the Skyview Bar! On a clear day you will be lucky to see The Palm, known as the man-made islands. A visit to the Burj Al Arab will also allow you access to an incredible private beach, which I enjoyed spending my time in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj al arab&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dubai-desert-safari&quot;&gt;Dubai Desert Safari&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A day trip into the desert was one of the highlights during my visit in Dubai. Here you will find the most incredible sunset! Take a day tour with a tour company to experience dune bashing, sandboarding, and camel rides. You can also experience more of the culture during a sunset dinner and show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-dubai-miracle-garden&quot;&gt;The Dubai Miracle Garden&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dubai Miracle Garden is one of the most beautiful flower gardens I have visited! It really does feel like a miracle when you walk through the garden. It’s not open year round though so make sure you check &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dubaimiraclegarden.com/visitors-guide/timing-rates/&quot;&gt;the schedule&lt;/a&gt; in advance. Also, since Dubai gets fairly hot I suggest visiting early morning. I was one of the first visitors there and had the place practically to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dubai-aquarium--mall&quot;&gt;Dubai Aquarium &amp;amp; Mall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As one of the largest malls in the world, the Dubai Mall will surprise you with how many things there are to do. There is a ton of shopping, endless restaurants, a cinema complex, and an ice-skating rink. And did you know that the Dubai Aquarium is also one of the largest suspended aquariums in the world? If you’re brave enough, you can even dive in and swim with the sharks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sheikh-zayed-grand-mosque&quot;&gt;Sheikh Zayed Grand Mosque&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sheikh Zayed Grand Mosque isn’t in Dubai, but it’s so breathtaking that I’m including it anyways! The Grand Mosque is located in Abu Dhabi, the capital city of the United Arab Emirates, and is less than two hours from Dubai. I was amazed by this incredible structure, which is all white and beautifully crafted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sacred mosque is very strict so I advise that you prepare before your visit. Women must cover their head, wrists, and ankles. Men are not allowed to wear tank tops or shorts, so dress accordingly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I entered the mosque, I was so impressed with the carpet. It’s actually the world’s largest hand knotted carpet! The UAE is definitely known for the largest, biggest, and tallest things. While touring inside, make sure to look up to see incredible 24 carat gold chandeliers hanging from the ceiling! If only I could have taken it home as a souvenir :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As one of the top destinations in the world, Dubai is a place you will want to visit once in your life. I truly felt like I was morphed into the future from visiting all the surreal and incredible places in Dubai.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Adventurers: &lt;em&gt;Thanks so much to Christine for sharing these amazing places in Dubai! Be sure and head over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://tourdelust.com/&quot;&gt;her blog&lt;/a&gt; for some wanderlust inducing travel guides and stories.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-tips/six-most-incredible-places-visit-in-dubai.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-tips/six-most-incredible-places-visit-in-dubai.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Foods You HAVE to Eat While Visiting Berlin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since we left our home and possessions behind 8 months ago, we’ve traveled to some amazing places and tried all manner of cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an awesome week in Copenhagen, we decided to fly south to Berlin and spend 2 weeks really getting to know the city. Part of getting to know the city is getting to know their cuisine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to try the dishes Berlin was known for. But, instead of just googling it, we decided to ask the locals! Most everyone we came in contact with we’d ask what quintessential Berling food do &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; think we should try?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were given a bunch of amazing suggestions, but settled on the following three since they came the most highly recommended and, let’s face it, they sound delicious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2aUg7mjzbg8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;currywurst-at-curry-36&quot;&gt;Currywurst at Curry 36&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name would imply, Currywurst is a sausage doused in a sort of curry sauce, typically served with a side of fried. And while you can find Currywurst all over Berlin, Curry 36 seemed to be &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to go for the best Berlin curry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And it did not disappoint!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/currywurst.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;currywurst from curry 36&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be advised, this is not a dish for the calorie sensitive. Sure, every bite was a delicious cornucopia of flavor. &lt;em&gt;That sauce knocked our socks off!&lt;/em&gt; But, when it was all over, we couldn’t help but feel deliciously bad about what we had just done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/currywurst-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;more currywurst from curry 36&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dish reminded us a bit of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poutine&quot;&gt;Poutine&lt;/a&gt; - a famous dish from Quebec made of fries, gravy and cheese curds. Mostly because, while it tastes absolutely amazing, it should definitely be more of an occasional treat than a regular meal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;berliner-doughnuts&quot;&gt;Berliner Doughnuts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know a city is badass when it has a pasty named after it! The Berliner (or Pfannkuchen) is similar to a doughnut, but with no hole in the center, typically filled with marmalade or jam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/berliner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;berliner doughnut&quot; /&gt;
Ours were filled with Plum jam, which caught us a little off guard. We had never had plum jam in a doughnut before (actually, I don’t think we’ve ever had plum jam!), so the taste wasn’t quite what we were expecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/berliner-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;plum filling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, it was still delicious! It had a sort of apple butter taste to it and the bread was moist and fluffy. No doubt this is a taste that would grow on us if we lived in the city! Sadly, the calories would likely grow on us too :o&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in Berlin, you’ve definitely got to give these unique little pastries a try. But we recommend getting two or three, each with different jams inside so you can find the one you like the most!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;schnitzel-at-scheers-schnitzel&quot;&gt;Schnitzel at Scheers Schnitzel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Schnitzel may be hard to pronounce, it’s easy to devour! We found a quaint, unassuming little schnitzel place under a bridge in East Berlin called Scheers Schnitzel (try saying that 5 times fast!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not familiar with it, a schnitzel is meat, thinned by pounding with a meat tenderizer, coated with flour, beaten eggs and bread crumbs, and then fried. Yep, it’s just as delicious as it sounds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/schnitzel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;scheers schnitzel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glance, we expected this hunk of meat to be dry and tough. To our surprise, we were able to cut through it like butter and it was actually perfectly moist! It was also a lot thinner than we thought it would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dish took us back to our travels through Texas, where on multiple occasions we indulged ourselves with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chicken_fried_steak&quot;&gt;chicken fried steak&lt;/a&gt;. Schnitzel felt like it’s slightly healthier - or at least thinner - cousin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this was an amazing dish to end the day on. If you’re in Berlin, you can’t leave without trying the Schnitzel at Scheers Schnitzel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there any other must-try Berlin foods that should have made the list? Let us know in the comments section below or &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;hit us up on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-guides/3-foods-you-have-to-eat-while-visiting-berlin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-guides/3-foods-you-have-to-eat-while-visiting-berlin.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-guides</category>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        
        <category>travel-guides</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>9 Things You Need to Know Before Taking Your First Cruise</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thinking of booking your first cruise? Well we just finished a Royal Caribbean cruise that took us from Flordia, all the way across the Atlantic over the course of 14 days! Needless to say, we learned a hell of a lot about what &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; do and what &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully after reading this list, you’ll be much better prepared for your swashbuckling days at sea than we were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;repositioning-cruises-are-cheap&quot;&gt;Repositioning cruises are cheap!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our cruise was one-way from Tampa, FL, to Barcelona, Spain. It took 14 days (with 8 continuous days at sea and 4 port days) and included food, entertainment and lodging, all for under $45/day. That’s only $630 total! We couldn’t have flown to Barcelona for that cheap!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only drawback to booking these cruises it that they typically run in the off season (early spring or fall) and can be too long for some people. But, if you plan on traveling for a while, these cruises are extremely affordable when you factor in the length and distance traveled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-of-year-and-destination-determine-the-clientele&quot;&gt;Time of year and destination determine the clientele.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always thought cruises were just drunken pool parties surrounded by buffets and endless ocean. While those cruises exist, if it’s during the school year or if the cruise is longer than a few days or a week, it’s way more likely to just be you and 2,000 senior citizens - which is exactly what happened on our transatlantic trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If nonstop partying is what you’re looking for, just make sure to stick with shorter cruises and/or go during peak months. I will say one thing about our mostly senior-citizen cruise though, they sure know how to cut a rug! Plus I didn’t feel so bad getting into my swimsuit after eating at the buffet :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out that day’s vlog to see our reaction to the clientel and the first day of our cruise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7n_LLJZNXLE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-foods-actually-pretty-darn-good&quot;&gt;The food’s actually pretty darn good.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, at least it is at first! By the 14th day of the exact same breakfast buffet, we were ready to never have runny eggs, bland coffee and flavorless fried potatoes ever again! Luckily, the lunch and dinner buffets were much more exciting and surprisingly tasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and if your cruise offers a sit down dinner option at no extra charge, definitely sign up for it! We had amazing 3 course dinners every night and those alone were worth the price of the cruise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:37.4537037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BEmja8BMILj/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A photo posted by The Endless Adventure (@theendlessadventure)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-04-25T00:02:28+00:00&quot;&gt;Apr 24, 2016 at 5:02pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;We basically ate like kings for 14 days!&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-prepared-to-spend-a-lot-more-money-than-your-original-booking-fee&quot;&gt;Be prepared to spend a lot more money than your original booking fee.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any drinks other than water, black coffee, tea, and juice cost money. So if you want a latte or a soda, be prepared to pay extra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a mandatory 18% gratuity added to any bar purchase. VATs (value added taxes) can also pop up - in our case, once we got into Spanish waters, there was an additional 10% VAT tacked on to any fine dining or bar purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also an extra $13/day gratuity added to our overall bill which ended up being quite an expensive surprise! Luckily you can opt out of the daily gratuity charge, but you may want to save up at least a little cash so you can tip your waiters and room attendant at the end of the cruise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moral here is make sure to read ALL of the fine print on your cruise material. It saved us loads of money!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bring-dramamine&quot;&gt;Bring dramamine!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get car or motion sick, you’ll almost definitely be affected by the ship’s rocking. And, if you’re really lucky like us, you’ll have 30 mph winds and 15ft waves to toss the boat around and really make your equilibrium freak the eff out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get prescription sea sickness patches from your doctor that supposedly work wonders, but be aware that insurance doesn’t typically cover them! You should have seen my face when I walked in to pick mine up and the pharmacist said “that’ll be $198”. Sadly, they don’t have any cheaper, over the counter patches. But dramamine and/or the off-brand version, bonine, worked really well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But careful though, dramamine can make you super sleepy! I was essentially a zombie by the second day, so in an act of desperation, I bought these goofy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Sea-band-Original-Wristband-Adults-Pair/dp/B00DKEPFV2/ref=sr_1_3_s_it?s=hpc&amp;amp;rps=1&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1462310292&amp;amp;sr=1-3&amp;amp;keywords=sea+band&amp;amp;refinements=p_85%3A2470955011&quot;&gt;sea bands&lt;/a&gt; when we got to our first port.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my surprise, they actually worked! Apparently there’s a pressure point on your wrist that they push against which somehow magically cures your nausea!!? Whatever voodoo magic it was, I’ll take it! I might have looked a bit silly wearing them, but at least I wasn’t dying in my room anymore!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/seabands.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sea bands&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drink-packages-arent-worth-it-on-long-cruises---sneak-on-booze-instead&quot;&gt;Drink packages aren’t worth it on long cruises - sneak on booze instead!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most cruises offer various daily drink packages ranging from unlimited cheap beer and wine to unlimited premium cocktails, beers and wine. While it may be enticing to sign up for these, just keep in mind that you can’t purchase just one day at a time. You actually have to purchase the package for every remaining day of the cruise. In our case, if we’d signed up for just the basic drink package, it would have been an extra $650, which was more than we spent on our tickets!! If you’re only spending a few days at sea, it may be worth it, but we just couldn’t justify it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did end up buying their cheapest beer every now and then (which was a pretty good deal at 750 mL of Fosters for $7.67 including tip and tax!), but one of the best things we did for our wallets was sneak on our own liquor! &lt;a href=&quot;http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-drink-for-free-on-a-cruise.html&quot;&gt;Here’s how we did it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-plan-on-having-reliable-wifi&quot;&gt;Don’t plan on having reliable wifi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so this &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2015/10/15/cruise-ships-tech-wifi/&quot;&gt;isn’t necessarily true&lt;/a&gt; of all cruises nowadays, but for us, most of the time we were lucky if we could get our email to load!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of ships have upgraded their internet and we hear it’s much faster and more reliable. Just make sure to double check especially if you’re hoping to get some legitimate work done onboard. Also, some internet packages are really expensive, so you may want to hold off and chill out at an internet cafe on your port days instead of buying the ship’s package or paying their high daily rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plan-out-your-port-days-in-advance-to-make-the-most-of-your-time-on-shore&quot;&gt;Plan out your port days in advance to make the most of your time on shore.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’re super fancy and signed up for excursions through your cruise, in which case, ignore this tip. If you’re more thrifty (read: poor) like us, you’ll be your own tour guide. It’s certainly the more affordable option, but just make sure you research your port destinations ahead of time so you’re not wasting your morning scouring tripadvisor last-minute or walking aimlessly down random streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little preparation will ensure you get to see some cool sights and still make it back to your ship on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:37.4537037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BEq5gYWsIKY/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A photo posted by The Endless Adventure (@theendlessadventure)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-04-26T16:32:25+00:00&quot;&gt;Apr 26, 2016 at 9:32am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;We researched this amazing overlook in Funchal, Portugal before heading out for the day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bring-nice-clothes&quot;&gt;Bring nice clothes!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our cruise had 3 formal nights during our two-week cruise - 3!! And you better believe we were those assholes running around in smart-casual (another dinner attire theme) while everyone else was in their floor length dresses and tuxes. Don’t offend the old people on your cruise like we did - throw a suit jacket or LBD in your bag just in case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There you have it!&lt;/strong&gt; We really hope that these tips help you when taking your first cruise. We definitely wish we would have known some of these things going in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cruised with Royal Caribbean, but we realize these details can vary a bit based on your cruise line. If you’re a cruise veteran, we’d love to know if you’ve had different experiences or if you have any tips of your own that you think we should have included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us know in the comments below or strike up a conversation on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, consider subscribing to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribing to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/9-things-you-need-to-know-before-your-first-cruise.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/9-things-you-need-to-know-before-your-first-cruise.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>budget-travel</category>
        
        <category>cruises</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Financial Update: Are We Broke Yet?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve officially been traveling full-time for the last 6 months. Has it been that long already!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we started this journey, we promised to be as transparent as possible about our finances. We haven’t been doing great job of that, mostly because we’re struggling to figure out how we should go about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, rather than over thinking it, we’ve decided to write a quick update on our financial situation. If you want to see EXACTLY what we’re spending and EXACTLY what we’re making, this post is for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travel-is-expensive&quot;&gt;Travel is expensive!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we had anticipated, the most difficult part of full-time travel is making it work financially. Traveling the world is expensive! Between currency conversion fees, plane tickets, gas prices, 3 meals a day each and the occasional beer (okay maybe the more-than-occasional beer), our bank account has been dwindling fast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this leads us to the question: &lt;strong&gt;Are we broke yet?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, before starting this journey, we had saved up &lt;strong&gt;~$10k&lt;/strong&gt;, but the goal was never to live off of that money. It was meant to be more of a safety net. And I’m happy to say that we still haven’t had to dig into this fund yet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March, however, we actually came very close to dipping into our savings. Up until then I had a contract job that was paying enough for us to live, while only having to work a few hours a day. The contract ended but I was still making a little money mentoring UI design students online, around &lt;strong&gt;$700&lt;/strong&gt; per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, before that payment came in, our bank account had officially hit zero. This was a bit of a reality check for us. It’s pretty scary not knowing how you’re going to afford to live next month!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But luckily I was able to secure a new contract job within about a week. I’ve also taken on some guest blogging gigs and have been able to make around &lt;strong&gt;$1000&lt;/strong&gt; in the last month with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might not be consistent work, but it’s at least enough to keep us going for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-our-spending-under-control&quot;&gt;Getting our spending under control&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t emphasize how much of a challenge this has been. When you’re traveling in a new place, there’s nothing like going out for drinks at a local pub or trying out a local restaurant. Trouble is, if you do that enough it starts to rack up quickly. Pretty soon you’re staring at your bank account wondering what the hell happened!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On some days we’ve easily spent &lt;strong&gt;$100&lt;/strong&gt; just on food and entertainment alone! While it makes for a great time, it’s just not sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/are-we-broke-yet/cc.png&quot; alt=&quot;our credit card account&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Our credit card statement after just one day of spending!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we’re trying our best to be conscious of every dollar we spend. We’ve also been stopping at grocery stores when we first arrive in a new city. This way we can stock up on a few meals and have no more excuses for eating out 3 times a day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;housing-costs&quot;&gt;Housing costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 16th of April, we boarded a 15 day, transatlantic cruise. Luckily we booked this well in advance (back in December), so it almost felt like we were staying for free for two weeks! We also had free meals on board and had snuck on our own booze, so we spent hardly anything those two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But reality set back in when we landed in Barcelona, Spain on May 1st. Honestly, at this point we were glad to never eat the ship buffet again or have to sleep in our tiny cabin! But it also meant that we had to start buying our meals again and paying for housing. What a drag!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve actually been doing pretty well in this department. Here’s the breakdown of our months AirBnB costs since we arrived in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dubrovnik, Croatia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
4 nights - $134&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copenhagen, Denmark&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
8 nights - $418&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Berlin, Germany&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
14 nights - $455&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This puts us at &lt;strong&gt;$1,007&lt;/strong&gt; spent in 26 days. Our initial budget was &lt;strong&gt;$1000&lt;/strong&gt;, which we knew was being a bit conservative. But it doesn’t look like we’ll break the budget by too much. I think for the next 30 days we’ll adjust this to maybe &lt;strong&gt;$1,250&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, housing costs fluctuate heavily depending on what country you’re visiting. Copenhagen was pretty pricy, but we stayed out of town and roomed with a few friends which brought the cost down. And don’t ask me how we got such a killer price in Berlin. I think we just got lucky on that one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, our best AirBnB deal came last month when we booked a week in Montreal for only &lt;strong&gt;$15&lt;/strong&gt; a night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-money-is-coming-in&quot;&gt;How much money is coming in&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I’m doing a mix of contract jobs, writing blog posts and mentoring, the money isn’t too steady. But here’s what we’re expecting to bring in over the next 30 days:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guest blog posts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
$1000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short term contract job&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
$1020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ongoing contract job&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
$2000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online mentoring&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
$700&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s $4,720 for the next 30 days. After tax it will round out to about $3,540. Not too bad!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This at least means we’re covered for the 30 days. But the reality is that this work isn’t stable. So we’re still trying as hard as we can to budget properly and be conscious of every penny we spend so that we can stretch this money as far as it can go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this moment we have &lt;strong&gt;$1000&lt;/strong&gt; in our bank account and &lt;strong&gt;$0&lt;/strong&gt; on our credit card. We’re currently in Berlin, Germany and have our AirBnB paid for up until the 29th. We’re not sure where we’ll go after this but we’ll definitely try to keep the theme of cheap housing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s what our finances look like at the current moment. If you have any questions or feel like we missed any details, don’t hesitate to contact us via &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#099;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#100;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#117;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/finances/are-we-broke-yet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/finances/are-we-broke-yet.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>finances</category>
        
        <category>budget-travel</category>
        
        
        <category>finances</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
