<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Endless Adventure | Travel Blog &amp; Daily Vlog</title>
    <description>Hi! We&#39;re Eric and Allison. We quit our full-time jobs and sold everything to travel full-time. We make daily vlogs of our travels and adventures around the world!
</description>
    <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://theendlessadventure.co/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 13:40:52 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 13:40:52 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Most Incredible Places To Visit In Dubai</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Dubai is one of the most modern and newest cities in the world. In recent years, Dubai has gained popularity as one of the top destinations for travelers. Can you believe that just over 40 years ago it was all desert and sand dunes? It is quite hard to imagine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, Dubai aims to be the biggest and best city on earth. Their goal is to make the impossible, possible. I feel so lucky to have visited this magical city and excited to share the most incredible places to visit in Dubai!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;burj-khalifa&quot;&gt;Burj Khalifa&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dubai has created the world’s tallest structure, The Burj Khalifa, which stands at 829.8 m. The 124th observation deck is quite a place to experience! The best time to visit is during sunset and night time to catch the beautiful skyline views. Another record-breaking attraction in Dubai is the Dubai Fountain located below the Burj Khalifa, which is currently the largest choreographed fountain in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;burj-al-arab&quot;&gt;Burj Al Arab&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Burj Al Arab is one of the tallest hotels in the world. It is a luxurious 5 star hotel and also one of the most expensive hotels in the world. If you’re a budget traveler, you can visit the hotel without having to spend a night by making reservations at one of their restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One unbelievable thing here is the view from the top of the Skyview Bar! On a clear day you will be lucky to see The Palm, known as the man-made islands. A visit to the Burj Al Arab will also allow you access to an incredible private beach, which I enjoyed spending my time in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image02.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj al arab&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dubai-desert-safari&quot;&gt;Dubai Desert Safari&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A day trip into the desert was one of the highlights during my visit in Dubai. Here you will find the most incredible sunset! Take a day tour with a tour company to experience dune bashing, sandboarding, and camel rides. You can also experience more of the culture during a sunset dinner and show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image04.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-dubai-miracle-garden&quot;&gt;The Dubai Miracle Garden&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dubai Miracle Garden is one of the most beautiful flower gardens I have visited! It really does feel like a miracle when you walk through the garden. It’s not open year round though so make sure you check &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dubaimiraclegarden.com/visitors-guide/timing-rates/&quot;&gt;the schedule&lt;/a&gt; in advance. Also, since Dubai gets fairly hot I suggest visiting early morning. I was one of the first visitors there and had the place practically to myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image03.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dubai-aquarium--mall&quot;&gt;Dubai Aquarium &amp;amp; Mall&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As one of the largest malls in the world, the Dubai Mall will surprise you with how many things there are to do. There is a ton of shopping, endless restaurants, a cinema complex, and an ice-skating rink. And did you know that the Dubai Aquarium is also one of the largest suspended aquariums in the world? If you’re brave enough, you can even dive in and swim with the sharks!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image05.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sheikh-zayed-grand-mosque&quot;&gt;Sheikh Zayed Grand Mosque&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sheikh Zayed Grand Mosque isn’t in Dubai, but it’s so breathtaking that I’m including it anyways! The Grand Mosque is located in Abu Dhabi, the capital city of the United Arab Emirates, and is less than two hours from Dubai. I was amazed by this incredible structure, which is all white and beautifully crafted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sacred mosque is very strict so I advise that you prepare before your visit. Women must cover their head, wrists, and ankles. Men are not allowed to wear tank tops or shorts, so dress accordingly!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I entered the mosque, I was so impressed with the carpet. It’s actually the world’s largest hand knotted carpet! The UAE is definitely known for the largest, biggest, and tallest things. While touring inside, make sure to look up to see incredible 24 carat gold chandeliers hanging from the ceiling! If only I could have taken it home as a souvenir :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dubai/image00.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;burj khalifa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As one of the top destinations in the world, Dubai is a place you will want to visit once in your life. I truly felt like I was morphed into the future from visiting all the surreal and incredible places in Dubai.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the Adventurers: &lt;em&gt;Thanks so much to Christine for sharing these amazing places in Dubai! Be sure and head over to &lt;a href=&quot;http://tourdelust.com/&quot;&gt;her blog&lt;/a&gt; for some wanderlust inducing travel guides and stories.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-tips/six-most-incredible-places-visit-in-dubai.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-tips/six-most-incredible-places-visit-in-dubai.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>3 Foods You HAVE to Eat While Visiting Berlin</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since we left our home and possessions behind 8 months ago, we’ve traveled to some amazing places and tried all manner of cuisine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an awesome week in Copenhagen, we decided to fly south to Berlin and spend 2 weeks really getting to know the city. Part of getting to know the city is getting to know their cuisine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to try the dishes Berlin was known for. But, instead of just googling it, we decided to ask the locals! Most everyone we came in contact with we’d ask what quintessential Berling food do &lt;em&gt;they&lt;/em&gt; think we should try?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We were given a bunch of amazing suggestions, but settled on the following three since they came the most highly recommended and, let’s face it, they sound delicious!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/2aUg7mjzbg8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;currywurst-at-curry-36&quot;&gt;Currywurst at Curry 36&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name would imply, Currywurst is a sausage doused in a sort of curry sauce, typically served with a side of fried. And while you can find Currywurst all over Berlin, Curry 36 seemed to be &lt;em&gt;the&lt;/em&gt; place to go for the best Berlin curry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And it did not disappoint!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/currywurst.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;currywurst from curry 36&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be advised, this is not a dish for the calorie sensitive. Sure, every bite was a delicious cornucopia of flavor. &lt;em&gt;That sauce knocked our socks off!&lt;/em&gt; But, when it was all over, we couldn’t help but feel deliciously bad about what we had just done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/currywurst-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;more currywurst from curry 36&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dish reminded us a bit of &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Poutine&quot;&gt;Poutine&lt;/a&gt; - a famous dish from Quebec made of fries, gravy and cheese curds. Mostly because, while it tastes absolutely amazing, it should definitely be more of an occasional treat than a regular meal!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;berliner-doughnuts&quot;&gt;Berliner Doughnuts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know a city is badass when it has a pasty named after it! The Berliner (or Pfannkuchen) is similar to a doughnut, but with no hole in the center, typically filled with marmalade or jam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/berliner.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;berliner doughnut&quot; /&gt;
Ours were filled with Plum jam, which caught us a little off guard. We had never had plum jam in a doughnut before (actually, I don’t think we’ve ever had plum jam!), so the taste wasn’t quite what we were expecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/berliner-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;plum filling&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, it was still delicious! It had a sort of apple butter taste to it and the bread was moist and fluffy. No doubt this is a taste that would grow on us if we lived in the city! Sadly, the calories would likely grow on us too :o&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re in Berlin, you’ve definitely got to give these unique little pastries a try. But we recommend getting two or three, each with different jams inside so you can find the one you like the most!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;schnitzel-at-scheers-schnitzel&quot;&gt;Schnitzel at Scheers Schnitzel&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Schnitzel may be hard to pronounce, it’s easy to devour! We found a quaint, unassuming little schnitzel place under a bridge in East Berlin called Scheers Schnitzel (try saying that 5 times fast!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re not familiar with it, a schnitzel is meat, thinned by pounding with a meat tenderizer, coated with flour, beaten eggs and bread crumbs, and then fried. Yep, it’s just as delicious as it sounds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/schnitzel.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;scheers schnitzel&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glance, we expected this hunk of meat to be dry and tough. To our surprise, we were able to cut through it like butter and it was actually perfectly moist! It was also a lot thinner than we thought it would be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dish took us back to our travels through Texas, where on multiple occasions we indulged ourselves with &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chicken_fried_steak&quot;&gt;chicken fried steak&lt;/a&gt;. Schnitzel felt like it’s slightly healthier - or at least thinner - cousin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, this was an amazing dish to end the day on. If you’re in Berlin, you can’t leave without trying the Schnitzel at Scheers Schnitzel!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are there any other must-try Berlin foods that should have made the list? Let us know in the comments section below or &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;hit us up on Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 22 May 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-guides/3-foods-you-have-to-eat-while-visiting-berlin.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel-guides/3-foods-you-have-to-eat-while-visiting-berlin.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-guides</category>
        
        <category>food</category>
        
        
        <category>travel-guides</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>9 Things You Need to Know Before Taking Your First Cruise</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thinking of booking your first cruise? Well we just finished a Royal Caribbean cruise that took us from Flordia, all the way across the Atlantic over the course of 14 days! Needless to say, we learned a hell of a lot about what &lt;em&gt;to&lt;/em&gt; do and what &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully after reading this list, you’ll be much better prepared for your swashbuckling days at sea than we were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;repositioning-cruises-are-cheap&quot;&gt;Repositioning cruises are cheap!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our cruise was one-way from Tampa, FL, to Barcelona, Spain. It took 14 days (with 8 continuous days at sea and 4 port days) and included food, entertainment and lodging, all for under $45/day. That’s only $630 total! We couldn’t have flown to Barcelona for that cheap!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only drawback to booking these cruises it that they typically run in the off season (early spring or fall) and can be too long for some people. But, if you plan on traveling for a while, these cruises are extremely affordable when you factor in the length and distance traveled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;time-of-year-and-destination-determine-the-clientele&quot;&gt;Time of year and destination determine the clientele.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always thought cruises were just drunken pool parties surrounded by buffets and endless ocean. While those cruises exist, if it’s during the school year or if the cruise is longer than a few days or a week, it’s way more likely to just be you and 2,000 senior citizens - which is exactly what happened on our transatlantic trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If nonstop partying is what you’re looking for, just make sure to stick with shorter cruises and/or go during peak months. I will say one thing about our mostly senior-citizen cruise though, they sure know how to cut a rug! Plus I didn’t feel so bad getting into my swimsuit after eating at the buffet :D&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out that day’s vlog to see our reaction to the clientel and the first day of our cruise:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7n_LLJZNXLE&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-foods-actually-pretty-darn-good&quot;&gt;The food’s actually pretty darn good.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, at least it is at first! By the 14th day of the exact same breakfast buffet, we were ready to never have runny eggs, bland coffee and flavorless fried potatoes ever again! Luckily, the lunch and dinner buffets were much more exciting and surprisingly tasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and if your cruise offers a sit down dinner option at no extra charge, definitely sign up for it! We had amazing 3 course dinners every night and those alone were worth the price of the cruise!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:37.4537037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BEmja8BMILj/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A photo posted by The Endless Adventure (@theendlessadventure)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-04-25T00:02:28+00:00&quot;&gt;Apr 24, 2016 at 5:02pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;We basically ate like kings for 14 days!&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;be-prepared-to-spend-a-lot-more-money-than-your-original-booking-fee&quot;&gt;Be prepared to spend a lot more money than your original booking fee.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any drinks other than water, black coffee, tea, and juice cost money. So if you want a latte or a soda, be prepared to pay extra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a mandatory 18% gratuity added to any bar purchase. VATs (value added taxes) can also pop up - in our case, once we got into Spanish waters, there was an additional 10% VAT tacked on to any fine dining or bar purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was also an extra $13/day gratuity added to our overall bill which ended up being quite an expensive surprise! Luckily you can opt out of the daily gratuity charge, but you may want to save up at least a little cash so you can tip your waiters and room attendant at the end of the cruise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moral here is make sure to read ALL of the fine print on your cruise material. It saved us loads of money!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bring-dramamine&quot;&gt;Bring dramamine!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you get car or motion sick, you’ll almost definitely be affected by the ship’s rocking. And, if you’re really lucky like us, you’ll have 30 mph winds and 15ft waves to toss the boat around and really make your equilibrium freak the eff out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can get prescription sea sickness patches from your doctor that supposedly work wonders, but be aware that insurance doesn’t typically cover them! You should have seen my face when I walked in to pick mine up and the pharmacist said “that’ll be $198”. Sadly, they don’t have any cheaper, over the counter patches. But dramamine and/or the off-brand version, bonine, worked really well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But careful though, dramamine can make you super sleepy! I was essentially a zombie by the second day, so in an act of desperation, I bought these goofy &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Sea-band-Original-Wristband-Adults-Pair/dp/B00DKEPFV2/ref=sr_1_3_s_it?s=hpc&amp;amp;rps=1&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1462310292&amp;amp;sr=1-3&amp;amp;keywords=sea+band&amp;amp;refinements=p_85%3A2470955011&quot;&gt;sea bands&lt;/a&gt; when we got to our first port.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To my surprise, they actually worked! Apparently there’s a pressure point on your wrist that they push against which somehow magically cures your nausea!!? Whatever voodoo magic it was, I’ll take it! I might have looked a bit silly wearing them, but at least I wasn’t dying in my room anymore!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/seabands.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sea bands&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;drink-packages-arent-worth-it-on-long-cruises---sneak-on-booze-instead&quot;&gt;Drink packages aren’t worth it on long cruises - sneak on booze instead!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most cruises offer various daily drink packages ranging from unlimited cheap beer and wine to unlimited premium cocktails, beers and wine. While it may be enticing to sign up for these, just keep in mind that you can’t purchase just one day at a time. You actually have to purchase the package for every remaining day of the cruise. In our case, if we’d signed up for just the basic drink package, it would have been an extra $650, which was more than we spent on our tickets!! If you’re only spending a few days at sea, it may be worth it, but we just couldn’t justify it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did end up buying their cheapest beer every now and then (which was a pretty good deal at 750 mL of Fosters for $7.67 including tip and tax!), but one of the best things we did for our wallets was sneak on our own liquor! &lt;a href=&quot;http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-drink-for-free-on-a-cruise.html&quot;&gt;Here’s how we did it&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dont-plan-on-having-reliable-wifi&quot;&gt;Don’t plan on having reliable wifi&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, so this &lt;a href=&quot;http://fortune.com/2015/10/15/cruise-ships-tech-wifi/&quot;&gt;isn’t necessarily true&lt;/a&gt; of all cruises nowadays, but for us, most of the time we were lucky if we could get our email to load!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of ships have upgraded their internet and we hear it’s much faster and more reliable. Just make sure to double check especially if you’re hoping to get some legitimate work done onboard. Also, some internet packages are really expensive, so you may want to hold off and chill out at an internet cafe on your port days instead of buying the ship’s package or paying their high daily rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plan-out-your-port-days-in-advance-to-make-the-most-of-your-time-on-shore&quot;&gt;Plan out your port days in advance to make the most of your time on shore.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe you’re super fancy and signed up for excursions through your cruise, in which case, ignore this tip. If you’re more thrifty (read: poor) like us, you’ll be your own tour guide. It’s certainly the more affordable option, but just make sure you research your port destinations ahead of time so you’re not wasting your morning scouring tripadvisor last-minute or walking aimlessly down random streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little preparation will ensure you get to see some cool sights and still make it back to your ship on time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:37.4537037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BEq5gYWsIKY/&quot; style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;A photo posted by The Endless Adventure (@theendlessadventure)&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2016-04-26T16:32:25+00:00&quot;&gt;Apr 26, 2016 at 9:32am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;We researched this amazing overlook in Funchal, Portugal before heading out for the day.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bring-nice-clothes&quot;&gt;Bring nice clothes!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our cruise had 3 formal nights during our two-week cruise - 3!! And you better believe we were those assholes running around in smart-casual (another dinner attire theme) while everyone else was in their floor length dresses and tuxes. Don’t offend the old people on your cruise like we did - throw a suit jacket or LBD in your bag just in case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There you have it!&lt;/strong&gt; We really hope that these tips help you when taking your first cruise. We definitely wish we would have known some of these things going in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cruised with Royal Caribbean, but we realize these details can vary a bit based on your cruise line. If you’re a cruise veteran, we’d love to know if you’ve had different experiences or if you have any tips of your own that you think we should have included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let us know in the comments below or strike up a conversation on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, consider subscribing to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribing to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/9-things-you-need-to-know-before-your-first-cruise.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/9-things-you-need-to-know-before-your-first-cruise.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>budget-travel</category>
        
        <category>cruises</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Financial Update: Are We Broke Yet?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’ve officially been traveling full-time for the last 6 months. Has it been that long already!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we started this journey, we promised to be as transparent as possible about our finances. We haven’t been doing great job of that, mostly because we’re struggling to figure out how we should go about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, rather than over thinking it, we’ve decided to write a quick update on our financial situation. If you want to see EXACTLY what we’re spending and EXACTLY what we’re making, this post is for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;travel-is-expensive&quot;&gt;Travel is expensive!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we had anticipated, the most difficult part of full-time travel is making it work financially. Traveling the world is expensive! Between currency conversion fees, plane tickets, gas prices, 3 meals a day each and the occasional beer (okay maybe the more-than-occasional beer), our bank account has been dwindling fast!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this leads us to the question: &lt;strong&gt;Are we broke yet?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, before starting this journey, we had saved up &lt;strong&gt;~$10k&lt;/strong&gt;, but the goal was never to live off of that money. It was meant to be more of a safety net. And I’m happy to say that we still haven’t had to dig into this fund yet!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In March, however, we actually came very close to dipping into our savings. Up until then I had a contract job that was paying enough for us to live, while only having to work a few hours a day. The contract ended but I was still making a little money mentoring UI design students online, around &lt;strong&gt;$700&lt;/strong&gt; per month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, before that payment came in, our bank account had officially hit zero. This was a bit of a reality check for us. It’s pretty scary not knowing how you’re going to afford to live next month!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But luckily I was able to secure a new contract job within about a week. I’ve also taken on some guest blogging gigs and have been able to make around &lt;strong&gt;$1000&lt;/strong&gt; in the last month with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might not be consistent work, but it’s at least enough to keep us going for the time being.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;getting-our-spending-under-control&quot;&gt;Getting our spending under control&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t emphasize how much of a challenge this has been. When you’re traveling in a new place, there’s nothing like going out for drinks at a local pub or trying out a local restaurant. Trouble is, if you do that enough it starts to rack up quickly. Pretty soon you’re staring at your bank account wondering what the hell happened!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On some days we’ve easily spent &lt;strong&gt;$100&lt;/strong&gt; just on food and entertainment alone! While it makes for a great time, it’s just not sustainable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/are-we-broke-yet/cc.png&quot; alt=&quot;our credit card account&quot; /&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;caption&quot;&gt;Our credit card statement after just one day of spending!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we’re trying our best to be conscious of every dollar we spend. We’ve also been stopping at grocery stores when we first arrive in a new city. This way we can stock up on a few meals and have no more excuses for eating out 3 times a day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;housing-costs&quot;&gt;Housing costs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the 16th of April, we boarded a 15 day, transatlantic cruise. Luckily we booked this well in advance (back in December), so it almost felt like we were staying for free for two weeks! We also had free meals on board and had snuck on our own booze, so we spent hardly anything those two weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But reality set back in when we landed in Barcelona, Spain on May 1st. Honestly, at this point we were glad to never eat the ship buffet again or have to sleep in our tiny cabin! But it also meant that we had to start buying our meals again and paying for housing. What a drag!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve actually been doing pretty well in this department. Here’s the breakdown of our months AirBnB costs since we arrived in Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dubrovnik, Croatia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
4 nights - $134&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copenhagen, Denmark&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
8 nights - $418&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Berlin, Germany&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
14 nights - $455&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This puts us at &lt;strong&gt;$1,007&lt;/strong&gt; spent in 26 days. Our initial budget was &lt;strong&gt;$1000&lt;/strong&gt;, which we knew was being a bit conservative. But it doesn’t look like we’ll break the budget by too much. I think for the next 30 days we’ll adjust this to maybe &lt;strong&gt;$1,250&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, housing costs fluctuate heavily depending on what country you’re visiting. Copenhagen was pretty pricy, but we stayed out of town and roomed with a few friends which brought the cost down. And don’t ask me how we got such a killer price in Berlin. I think we just got lucky on that one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, our best AirBnB deal came last month when we booked a week in Montreal for only &lt;strong&gt;$15&lt;/strong&gt; a night!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-much-money-is-coming-in&quot;&gt;How much money is coming in&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since I’m doing a mix of contract jobs, writing blog posts and mentoring, the money isn’t too steady. But here’s what we’re expecting to bring in over the next 30 days:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Guest blog posts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
$1000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short term contract job&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
$1020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ongoing contract job&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
$2000&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online mentoring&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
$700&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s $4,720 for the next 30 days. After tax it will round out to about $3,540. Not too bad!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This at least means we’re covered for the 30 days. But the reality is that this work isn’t stable. So we’re still trying as hard as we can to budget properly and be conscious of every penny we spend so that we can stretch this money as far as it can go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this moment we have &lt;strong&gt;$1000&lt;/strong&gt; in our bank account and &lt;strong&gt;$0&lt;/strong&gt; on our credit card. We’re currently in Berlin, Germany and have our AirBnB paid for up until the 29th. We’re not sure where we’ll go after this but we’ll definitely try to keep the theme of cheap housing!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that’s what our finances look like at the current moment. If you have any questions or feel like we missed any details, don’t hesitate to contact us via &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#099;&amp;#064;&amp;#116;&amp;#104;&amp;#101;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#100;&amp;#108;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#115;&amp;#097;&amp;#100;&amp;#118;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#117;&amp;#114;&amp;#101;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&quot;&gt;email&lt;/a&gt; or on &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/the_endless_a&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for reading!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, you can subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribe to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/finances/are-we-broke-yet.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/finances/are-we-broke-yet.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>finances</category>
        
        <category>budget-travel</category>
        
        
        <category>finances</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Drink for Free on a Cruise</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In case you haven’t heard, we’re big fans of using cruises as an affordable way to travel. In fact, we’re currently on a 14 day cruise from Tampa, FL, to Barcelona, Spain, with a couple friends and we only paid $600 each for the two weeks. That ends up being about $43/day for travel, accommodations, food, and entertainment, which is way below our typical daily allowance!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sadly, the only thing cruises don’t automatically include is alcohol. And there’s no way we’re spending two weeks on a boat (with 8 continuous days at sea) completely sober.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While it’s true that cruise lines often offer alcohol packages, they’re actually pretty expensive. Ours cost anywhere from $39 for the basic package to $59 for the premium package per day per person. At first that sounds like a freaking awesome deal, but the catch is that when you sign up for the drink package, you have to pay for it every remaining day. That basically means you end up literally doubling your ticket price! No bueno.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we got a little scrappy and ended up sneaking on 2 750ml bottles of liquor and 4 mini bottles and no one was the wiser. Security was a breeze. At first we were nervous they might be suspicious of our bottles, but we flew right on by!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The truth is, we totally could have snuck on 4 times the amount we did without anyone batting an eye… so that’s hopefully what we’ll inspire you to do :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heres-how-you-do-it&quot;&gt;Here’s how you do it:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;refill-wine-bottles-with-liquor&quot;&gt;Refill wine bottles with liquor!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our cruise line, and from the sound of it, most other lines, will allow you to bring some small amount of alcohol on your cruise. For us, we could bring 2 bottles of wine per room. Yep, that’s right, a whopping 2 whole bottles of wine, for 4 grownups, for 14 days. We’d literally have to skip an entire day of buffets for that amount to even give us a buzz!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what’d we do? We bought our two approved bottles of wine a few days before the cruise. Then later that same night, we drank those two bottles of wine. Then we refilled each with an entire 750ml bottle of rum. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What was our technique? Well after watching youtube tutorials and reading blog posts to figure out the best method, we ended up getting two bottles of chardonnay with tinted green glass and refilled them with golden rum which was roughly the same color as the chardonnay. This color combo made it literally impossible to tell the difference between the wine and rum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You could also get a really dark red wine bottle and try refilling it with a darker rum or alcohol of your choosing. If you’re a bit of a nervous person though, you should know that if the crew decided to take a closer look at your wine bottles, they can hold up a light to them and easily see that the contents isn’t red. But again, from our experience, no one is going to do that, so just do whatever combination you feel like! :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once our wine bottles were refilled with the rum, we flipped the corks over so that the side with the corkscrew hole was now on the bottom and just shoved it back in until it was flush with the top of the bottle. This step takes a bit of time and manipulating to get the cork back in. We found pushing it against the wall to get the stubborn last portion back inside worked really well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now that your alcohol is safely corked inside your wine bottle, the only part missing is the topper. This is where it gets really sneaky and awesome. You can actually order &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/30-Black-PVC-Shrink-Capsules/dp/B00AUJE4GM/ref=sr_1_2?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1461261946&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=pvc+wine+top&quot;&gt;wine toppers on Amazon&lt;/a&gt; that when heated, seal perfectly to your bottle! We used a hair dryer to shrink them which worked well but took a little bit of time to get it perfectly fitted. If you have access to a stove, we recommend the boiling/steaming method since it’s a bit faster and tends to create the least amount of bubbles/creases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voila! You now have two bottles of rum that look perfectly like chardonnay! We almost felt bad about how easy it was to get them through security!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out this vlog to see how we did it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/nwzotbEuuoI&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fill-travel-sized-bottles-with-liquor&quot;&gt;Fill travel-sized bottles with liquor.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Heck, fill any bottle you want with liquor! We filled a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Squeezable-Refillable-Bag-Travel-Accessories-Containers/dp/B014GLTG8U/ref=sr_1_2_a_it?rps=1&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1461262743&amp;amp;sr=8-2&amp;amp;keywords=tsa+approved+bottles&amp;amp;refinements=p_85%3A2470955011%2Cp_72%3A2661618011&quot;&gt;TSA-approved plastic bottle&lt;/a&gt; with two mini bottles of whiskey, and I also put rum in an empty Garnier Fructis conditioner bottle (which wasn’t see-through) just to better my odds in case they went through my items. We stayed super conservative with our mini bottles, because we thought for sure they’d pull out your liquids and give them a once over…but they didn’t&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/tsa-bottle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;TSA bottle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you end up refilling used bottles, make sure you properly wash them out! I did a bit of a rush job and you could still smell the conditioner when I poured in the booze. Luckily it was spiced rum that I later mixed with OJ, so any conditioner fragrance/taste that had seeped into the rum wasn’t detectable. But I hear soap doesn’t play well with your tummy, so you should probably do a better job than I did haha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fill-water-bottles-with-liquor&quot;&gt;Fill water bottles with liquor.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our friend had a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/Vapur-Element-Bottle-Water-1-Liter/dp/B007UU6JI0/ref=sr_1_3?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1461336295&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;keywords=foldable+water+bottle&quot;&gt;plastic, foldable water bottle&lt;/a&gt; that he filled with gin and got right through security on our first day without any questions. Then when we had our first port day we all brought water bottles back on the boat with us without anyone checking them at security - what a missed opportunity!! Now that we know security is always lax whether you’re first boarding or returning from a port day, we’ll definitely be bringing plenty of “water” back with us at our next stop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/nikita-water-bottle.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;water bottle of liquor&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;put-plastic-key-word-plastic-liquor-bottles-in-your-pocketsunderwearshoesbrawherever-you-want&quot;&gt;Put plastic (key word plastic) liquor bottles in your pockets/underwear/shoes/bra…wherever you want!&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You only go through metal detectors (no full body scanners) and the people running them can barely muster up what it takes to wave you through, let alone pat you down or question you. Pretty much, as long as you’re not straight up holding your mini bottles or high-fiving your friend about how much alcohol you just snuck through security, no one will ever know that that’s vodka and not a banana in your pocket ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;theres-also-free-booze-on-the-cruise-if-you-know-where-to-look&quot;&gt;There’s also free booze on the cruise if you know where to look!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;hit-up-every-champagne-event-on-the-boat&quot;&gt;Hit up every champagne event on the boat.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far there’s been at least one event per day with complimentary champagne. From the captain meet-and-greet to the art gallery showcase to the spa tour, it seems like there’s always a way to grab a free glass of bubbly. On our cruise, they usually announced which events have champagne during the morning announcements or in the daily activity flyer, so just make sure to keep an ear out. Pro tip: ALWAYS grab an extra glass or two for a “friend” ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pretend-to-be-the-it-guy&quot;&gt;Pretend to be the IT guy.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some reason our cruise ended up having an extremely large senior citizen population. (Talk about seeing things at the pool you can’t unsee…) And the only thing more confusing to them than trying to understand our vlogging and nomadic lifestyle, is the freakin internet package. Our friend, Nikita, has been working near the computer station for the past couple days and has been mistaken for the IT guy more times than we can count. Being the nice guy that he is, he always tries to help explain the wifi package and today it finally paid off in the form of a mini vodka bottle!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only is that one badass thank you gift, but it also proves my point that you can just straight up bring alcohol on in its original packaging and not even worry about getting caught!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;share-a-drink-package&quot;&gt;Share a drink package.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay so this isn’t really a free way to drink, but it does make things way more affordable! Technically you’re not allowed to share packages, but there are so many bars onboard, that you can just go from bar to bar alternating who gets drinks. Sure you run the risk of seeming like the ultimate alcoholic, but deep down you know that you’re actually just a cost-conscious, borderline alcoholic. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;–&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well now that we’ve done the research and successfully put our tricks to the test, we hope that your next cruise will end up being the ultimate, free booze cruise!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, consider subscribing to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribing to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-drink-for-free-on-a-cruise.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-drink-for-free-on-a-cruise.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>budget-travel</category>
        
        <category>cruises</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Lessons Learned Riding Amtrak From Canada to New York City</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Eric and I recently booked a trip to Montreal but needed to be in Florida for a cruise the following week. So, naturally we figured we should hit up New York on the way down since we’d be on the East Coast anyway. But the flights were expensive and we didn’t have a car, so that left us with one option: Amtrak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a little digging, we found a train route that cost $69/person and figured what the heck! So now here I am at the end of the train ride, giving you the freshest perspective of train travel across the Canadian border.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out that day’s vlog for an up close look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/TfmJYdkU1ys&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;boarding-is-surprisingly-quick-and-painless&quot;&gt;Boarding is surprisingly quick and painless&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you arrive at the Gare Centrale station in Montreal, you just head inside, get in line at the gate (it was number 19 for us and clearly marked for New York), flash your ticket as you start boarding, then choose whatever seat you want in the car they point you towards. Don’t worry about printing your ticket either, they can scan it from your phone/mobile device on the train. If you do happen to get lost or confused, the staff at the train station all seemed really nice and spoke English, so don’t hesitate to ask for help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-a-really-long-day&quot;&gt;It’s a really long day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train departs at 10:20am, but you should arrive about 30 minutes prior to that time since they start the boarding process a little before 10am. It’s scheduled to arrive in NYC a whopping 10 and a half hours later at 8:50pm. So you know going in that it’s going to be a long day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;border-patrol-is-no-joke&quot;&gt;Border Patrol is no joke&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About 2 hours into your ride (right inside the New York state line), Border Patrol boards the train to collect papers, inspect passports and question everyone. If you don’t speak English, appear to be on drugs like the guy behind us, or from aren’t the US, prepare to be asked a lot of questions by stern, highly impatient agents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re really lucky, you’ll get called to the cafe car for what I can only assume is interrogation hell. I’m not sure if this is true for all of these routes, but we literally sat still on the tracks for 2 hours during this process, which leads me to my next lesson learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-will-not-arrive-on-time&quot;&gt;You will not arrive on time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless somehow every single person on the train has their legal documents perfectly in order, someone will get called to that damn cafe car and your schedule will be shot to hell. We didn’t ended up arriving at Penn Station until 9:45pm, making the day a whopping 12 hours of fun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, don’t expect to get any sort of updates during the customs stop. You just sit there on the ugliest strip of tracks you’ll see during the day wondering where the agents took that confused, non-English-speaking, hispanic woman with all of her luggage and if she’ll ever return… Thank goodness the wifi’s working and pretty strong during that part of the trip! In case you’re wondering, the confused hispanic lady returned an hour and a half later and got right back on her tablet like nothing had happened. I have so many questions!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;theres-alcohol-in-the-cafe&quot;&gt;There’s alcohol in the cafe!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it’s not being used as an interrogation room, the cafe car sells food and beverages and has surprising nice booths to sit at. If you plan on getting work done on the train, I highly recommend hunkering down in there. You have plenty of room to spread out and there are far less distractions. We packed our own food so we didn’t end up ordering anything to eat, but we did get some cheap wine!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The menu actually seemed somewhat decent. Besides the usual pizzas, sandwiches, and hot dogs they had things like quinoa and spinach salad and even a vegan burger, how progressive! Obviously they got major points from us for serving beer, wine, and liquor :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/drunk-on-the-train.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Drunk on the train&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;avoid-the-bathrooms-later-in-the-day&quot;&gt;Avoid the bathrooms later in the day&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the first things the conductor announces when you board is “no one’s going to clean up after you unless you’re riding with your mother, and I’m not your mother”. Oh how true this is. The bathrooms were pretty smelly to begin with but by 7/8pm, the toilet paper’s gone, everyone’s apparently forgotten how to flush and aim, and the floor becomes the new trash can. Seriously, so many people left the bathroom with that embarrassing string of toilet paper stuck to their foot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously you can’t hold it for the whole journey, but just try to avoid the bathrooms as much as you can after about 4pm. And whatever you do, please don’t touch that seat with any part of your body! If things get too desperate, put those quads to use and employ the hover method!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;you-cant-get-off-the-train-until-about-6pm&quot;&gt;You can’t get off the train until about 6pm&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For smokers and people who require frequent fresh air, this might be a bit of a challenge for you, but there’s only one stop where passengers are allowed to hop off to stretch their legs and smoke. I can’t remember the exact stop, but it was around 6pm. You can ask the conductors (they were all super nice!) but it’s the station where they do the engine swap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Important note for this stop: the power goes off for about 15-20 mins while they switch the engine. For the love of everything holy people, DO NOT USE THE BATHROOM DURING THIS TIME! I didn’t think about it until mid-pee (while hovering of course) but no power = no flushing. Needless to say, I, along with about 5 other people after me either didn’t realize or just didn’t care about that fact. I shudder to think what that poor bathroom went through during that break. If you get stir crazy easily, you can always just walk through the train cars until you get to that station.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-views-are-awesome&quot;&gt;The views are awesome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I actually slept most of the way from Montreal to the US border so I can’t really comment on the first couple hours but once you get into New York, the views are amazing! You travel alongside lakes, canals and rivers pretty much the whole time and see all sorts of quaint little towns, forests and wildlife along the way. We’d always heard that upstate New York was beautiful, and it definitely did not disappoint!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/train-view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Train view&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-wifi-is-spotty-at-best&quot;&gt;The wifi is spotty at best&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in some spots, completely unusable. Also, it doesn’t kick in until you cross the border, so the first couple hours are perfect for reading, sleeping (like me!), or playing Sudoku until you can’t possibly stand looking at another number in a box ever again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rouses Point is when the wifi kicks in and you can’t miss it - it’s when they stop and let the lovely Border Patrol agents board. Oh and they say there’s no streaming, but we used spotify and Youtube… so I guess it’s more of a request than a rule?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;its-cheap&quot;&gt;It’s cheap!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For $69/person, you really can’t beat the price if you’re planning on visiting New York or Montreal! Plus, there aren’t security lines, assigned seats, baggage fees, or TSA agents to deal with!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the train is a fun, affordable experience that you should definitely try once, but probably not more than that. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, consider subscribing to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribing to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 09 Apr 2016 17:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/10-lessons-learned-riding-amtrak-from-canada-to-new-york-city.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/10-lessons-learned-riding-amtrak-from-canada-to-new-york-city.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>budget-travel</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>6 Tips to Travel the World for CHEAP!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;You ever said you had to be rich to travel the world? Here are a few tips we’ve learned that will help you travel the world for cheap!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the more visual learners among us, we also made a handy video version of these tips!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/3Ji1gd0yUP8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-1---get-a-travel-rewards-card&quot;&gt;Tip #1 - Get a travel rewards card!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We didn’t use credit cards for years and really debated getting a new one, but honestly it’s been one of the things we’ve ever done for travel!! We’ve had our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.capitalone.com/credit-cards/venture/&quot;&gt;Capital One Venture Card&lt;/a&gt; for a little over a year now and have already gotten over $3000 in free travel! Seriously, why didn’t we do this sooner?!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We pay our bills and put all of our purchases (and sometimes friend’s purchases) on our card, which racks up points super fast. So next time you’re out to dinner, pick up the tab and have everyone &lt;a href=&quot;https://venmo.com/&quot;&gt;Venmo&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.paypal.com/home&quot;&gt;PayPal&lt;/a&gt; you for their portion. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-2--book-a-cruise&quot;&gt;Tip #2- Book a cruise!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, seriously! Most people associate cruises with high-priced vacations, but you can actually find really cheap cruises on sites like &lt;a href=&quot;http://cruisesheet.com/&quot;&gt;Cruisesheet.com&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cruisedirect.com/&quot;&gt;Cruisedirect.com&lt;/a&gt;. As long as you’re somewhat flexible with dates and the general start and end locations, you can find them for as little as $35-40/day. And that includes food, entertainment, and accommodations!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you’re a boozehound like we are, you’ll find that the alcohol packages on cruises are absolutely outrageously priced! Never fear, this video will show you the best technique out there for sneaking liquor on a cruise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Bry196a99G8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-3---stop-eating-out&quot;&gt;Tip #3 - Stop eating out!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So… this tip sucks. We love eating out and struggle with this one a lot ourselves. But if you’re on the road and eating out for 2-3 meals a day, plus the cost of coffee, tea, beer or whatever other treats you sneak in there, it adds up super fast! Before you know it, you’ve spent $50-100+ on food and drinks alone for just one day!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, make a point to run by a grocery store when you first arrive at your destination. There you can snag all the essentials like coffee, booze, and easy ingredients for homemade meals. Heck, with all the money you’ll save, you might just have enough to book your next vacation!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-4---do-free-stuff&quot;&gt;Tip #4 - Do free stuff!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Big cities and small towns alike typically take a lot of pride in showing off all that the area has to offer. A quick scan of the city’s website or facebook group in addition to a search on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.tripadvisor.com/&quot;&gt;TripAdvisor&lt;/a&gt; and literally Googling “free things to do” near our location have led us to some of our most memorable and free adventures!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out this vlog of ours where we had an amazing time exploring an abandoned ghost town without spending a dime! We found this one on TripAdvisor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7WXUgzpnna0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-5---travel-to-cheaper-places&quot;&gt;Tip #5 - Travel to cheaper places!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this one’s kind of a no-brainer and we’re not saying to &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; travel to cheap places. But if you spend a week or two in New York, try offsetting the higher prices by going to a more rural area or less expensive country in general like The Philippines or Croatia. That way you can explore all sorts of countries and cities without breaking the bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We love looking at &lt;a href=&quot;https://nomadlist.com/&quot;&gt;Nomadlist.com&lt;/a&gt; to compare the living costs of different places around the world. It definitely helps keep us on budget. Check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-6---use-public-transit-and-bikes-say-no-to-uber-and-lyft&quot;&gt;Tip #6 - Use public transit and bikes, say no to Uber and Lyft!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve biked a lot of cities and always agree that it gives us such a better perspective of the area. Since you’re going at a much slower pace, you really get to soak everything in and see the city and neighborhoods up close. Plus, bike rentals typically cost $10 or less per day. Just make sure you pay attention to the time limits! Some rentals allow for free and unlimited check-outs in a 24 hour period as long as you check your bike back in every 30 minutes. If you’re not diligent with your time, you could end up paying a lot more than you bargained for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those not into biking, buses and trains are super affordable forms of transportation that also force you to jump right in and get to know the layout of a city and the people that inhabit it. Public transit might seem overwhelming at first, but take it slow, read the signs and/or maps and before you know it, you’ll be a public transit pro!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another trick we use to cut down on transportation costs is to book Airbnbs or hostels on the outskirts, but still walking distance, from the areas we’re visiting. You typically get a much cheaper rental rate and pay $0 in transit costs because you’re walking! Plus, you get some extra exercise which is pretty much always a good thing. :)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, because you’re awesome, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.airbnb.com/c/abieller?s=8&quot;&gt;here’s $35 off your first AirBnB&lt;/a&gt;. No joke!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;—&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully these tips showed you that you can still take that vacation you’ve been dreaming about without having break the bank or make too many compromises. Have any other travel tips or hacks we should know about? Leave us a comment below!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, consider subscribing to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribing to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2016 21:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/6-tips-travel-the-world-for-cheap.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/6-tips-travel-the-world-for-cheap.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>budget-travel</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>These White Sand Dunes in New Mexico Will Blow Your Mind</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever been sledding in the middle of winter and thought, jeez, this sure is super but I wish it was about 60 degrees warmer out so I wasn’t freezing my ass off and on the verge of losing my extremities to frostbite!!?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the dunes at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/whsa/index.htm&quot;&gt;White Sand National Monument&lt;/a&gt; outside of Las Cruces, NM, are your dream come true! It’s a national park with literally 275 sq miles of warm, milky-white sand dunes that you can, and are encouraged to, sled down! Sound too good to be true? Well it’s not and for only $5 you can’t afford not to check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PCoXUeY9aKw&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-to-get-there&quot;&gt;How to get there&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The park is located on Hwy 70 W outside of Alamogordo, NM, but we recommend staying in Las Cruces, NM. It’s a much bigger city with lots of cool stuff to do! As always, we recommend grabbing a room or house on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.airbnb.com/c/abieller?s=8&quot;&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt; during your stay! (FYI: if you use that link, you’ll get $20 toward your reservation, even if it’s not for a NM trip!! Seriously. What are you waiting for?! Book something already! You’re welcome, we love you!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;best-time-to-visit&quot;&gt;Best time to visit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full disclosure, if you go in the middle of summer, the temperature in the park might actually be pretty hot. Like 100+ degrees hot. But as long as you get there in the morning or late afternoon and bring plenty of water, you’re good to go! It’s the desert after all, so temperatures fluctuate dramatically from day to night. If your schedule allows, we actually recommend going in early spring or late fall. The temps are best at those times and the crowds are minimal. We went the very first day of March and it was a perfect 77 degrees out. Plus we had the dunes all to ourselves!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-and-eric-jump-dunes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;allison and eric jumping the dunes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-to-bring&quot;&gt;What to bring&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Water and lots of it!&lt;/strong&gt; There’s a gift shop when you enter the park that sells food and beverages, but unfortunately there’s no water provided past the gates. And trust us, running up and down those dunes in the sun will make you really thirsty!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sunglasses and a hat.&lt;/strong&gt; The white sand, much like white snow, is brutal on the eyes. Plus you’re in the desert, and that sun is mean to foreheads, noses and uncovered body parts. And believe me, you won’t want to be reapplying sunscreen when your hands and face are covered in sand. So just buy a cool hat like I did and only worry about finding the biggest dune to sled down instead of your face melting off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-dunes-hat.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Allison at the dunes in her hat&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The right clothing. In case you haven’t already figured it out, the park is comprised of sand. Never-ending piles of sand. Sand that can and will make its way into your eyes, hair, pants, shoes, pockets, ears, nose, etc. For that reason, I recommend wearing a tighter pair of underoos or pants to help keep the sand out of you know where. Also, only wear flip flops to get to and from the car. The sand is surprisingly cool and super soft, so set those little piggies free for the day. Plus, I don’t know about you, but I’d much rather have to wipe my feet off and shake of my sandals at the end of the day than try to get sand out of my socks and shoes. :(&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A sled and wax.&lt;/strong&gt; If you have a sled, bring it! If you don’t because you’re in the south and typically have no need for a sled, that’s no problem! You can easily buy a used one at the gift shop for around $15. You could also buy a new one for a few bucks more, but we found that the used ones worked just as well as the new ones, especially with the wax… which I also recommend buying or bringing with you. It makes your ride so much faster and smoother!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best part of about the gift shop sled is that they’ll buy it back from you for a portion of the price. Just make sure you pay attention to the gift shop hours! We got there about 5 mins after it closed and they literally slammed the door in our face and locked it. Rude! So we left NM with 3 brand new and completely useless sleds…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it. You’re officially prepared for the warmest and sunniest sledding of your life!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you want to follow along on our journey, consider subscribing to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribing to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/these-white-sand-dunes-new-mexico-will-blow-your-mind.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/these-white-sand-dunes-new-mexico-will-blow-your-mind.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>vlogs</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How to Ditch the Clutter and Travel Light</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My husband and I recently left our jobs and apartment in San Francisco to travel the world full time. Most people would agree that we’re living the dream, but full disclosure, it’s way more stressful and complicated than it sounds!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we made this decision, obviously we were super pumped up. But once that initial excitement subsided, we started thinking about what full-time travel actually entails and the reality of the situation set in: &lt;em&gt;traveling the world means living out of a small suitcase or backpack…and there’s no way in hell your entire wardrobe, shoes, home gym, straightener, lotions, hair products, and cats will fit!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/the-cats.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cats in apartment&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what do you do? First step, &lt;strong&gt;panic!!!&lt;/strong&gt; Next, take a deep breath (or many short ones into a brown paper bag) and focus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tame-the-closet&quot;&gt;Tame the Closet&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with your closet. If you’re like me, the majority of your shoes and clothing are sitting there waiting for that one perfect beach day, a birthday picnic in the park or the night when Ryan Gosling invites you to the Academy Awards because he finally realized he’s in love with you totally and eternally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically what I’m saying is, a lot of it is expendable!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So how do you go from hundreds of clothing items to just a few? By thinking practically. Traveling means a lot of walking around in new cities and airports so you’ll need comfortable and sturdy shoes that can handle the elements - dirt, rain, city streets, swelling feet, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choosing-your-footwear&quot;&gt;Choosing Your Footwear&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most people think comfortable = boring, but I disagree! For example, I went with a pair of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nike.com/us/en_us/c/innovation/free&quot;&gt;Nike Frees&lt;/a&gt; which are super lightweight, come in a bunch of different styles, and are perfect for workouts, travel days, hiking, city exploring, and lazy days working in coffee shops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-hike-nike.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Allison hiking in nikes&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Flip flops are must-haves for showers and pool days, but can also be the perfect footwear for a warm day. In addition, I also recommend a pair of nicer, lightweight shoes (like these &lt;a href=&quot;http://oldnavy.gap.com/browse/product.do?vid=1&amp;amp;pid=597731002&quot;&gt;black flats&lt;/a&gt; for gals or these basic &lt;a href=&quot;http://oldnavy.gap.com/browse/product.do?cid=37844&amp;amp;vid=1&amp;amp;pid=780357012&quot;&gt;boots&lt;/a&gt; for fellas) that can be easily dressed for the occasional nice meal out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Depending on how much space you have, a pair of rain boots is also really nice to have (as I sit here writing on a rainy day in Montreal, wearing my soaking wet tennis shoes). Weight is always a factor, but apparently rain boots are super &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bogsfootwear.ca/shop/style/71287.html&quot;&gt;lightweight&lt;/a&gt; these days! So there you have it - style, comfort, and minimalism all in one!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choosing-your-clothing&quot;&gt;Choosing Your Clothing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to clothing, think about the different climates you’ll be in and go from there. Let’s assume you’re like me and traveling indefinitely across all different climates, since that’s the hardest kind of travel to prepare for in my opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, there’s an easy secret: &lt;strong&gt;basics and layers&lt;/strong&gt;. Get a couple pairs of pants and/or jeans, shorts, and skirts that can easily be dressed up or down and don’t wrinkle easily. Match these with the majority of your tops and voila! Your bottom half is literally covered!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, I picked out all the bottoms I wanted and then grabbed tops that I could mix easily with them. For both guys and gals, solid and striped tops specifically are great because they can go with anything! If you plan on doing a lot of Instagramming while on the road and are worried about always wearing the same thing, I can assure you that people will notice a patterned top a lot faster than a basic tee. ;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To maximize warmth and minimize load, invest in a couple long-sleeved thermal tops and a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.backcountry.com/Store/catalog/search.jsp?s=u&amp;amp;q=3+in+1+jacket&quot;&gt;3-in-1 jacket&lt;/a&gt; to keep you covered in all climates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;choosing-your-accessories-and-toiletries&quot;&gt;Choosing Your Accessories and Toiletries&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Okay, now that your clothing’s settled, everything else is a piece of cake! For those who do it all - moisturize, exfoliate, tweeze, style, wax - you might have a hard time at first, but like I mentioned earlier, just think about the necessities. You can always buy things like face masks and extra razor heads on the road, so start out with small quantities and leave your bubble bath at home!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things that I highly recommend to help cut down on space are two in one shampoos/conditioners and a moisturizer that works for your face and body - I have super combination dry/oily skin and am in love with this &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/solutions-Sweet-Almond-Moisturizing-ounce/dp/B0019LVFSU/ref=sr_1_3_a_it?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1459461866&amp;amp;sr=8-3&amp;amp;keywords=almond+oil&quot;&gt;almond oil&lt;/a&gt; as a head-to-toe moisturizer. Also, I cannot say enough great things about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.drbronner.com/DBMS/category/LIQUIDSOAP.html&quot;&gt;Dr. Bronner’s Pure Castille Soap&lt;/a&gt;! It’s literally our body wash, face wash, shaving cream, &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; laundry detergent all in one, plus it’s made with ethically-sourced, certified fair trade ingredients! It’s the stuff minimalist and hipster dreams are made of!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re flying a lot and not checking a bag, an easy trick is to buy normal sized bottles of everything and then divide the contents into smaller, travel-approved bottles. Not only are you saving money by buying the regular size, but you also won’t run out of your necessities as quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to your shampoo and soap, things I highly recommend having in your bathroom pack are tweezers, nail clippers with a built in file, ibuprofen, bandaids, a small tube of antibiotic cream, ear plugs and visine for travel days. I know it sounds like a lot, but they’re all really small items that can easily be shoved in a corner, pocket, or small toiletry bag and really pay off while on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;width: 65%; margin: 0px auto;&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/ally-packed.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ally packed&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So there you have it! After 5 months of living out of a backpack, these are the tips, tricks, and essentials I’ve found that’ll take the stress out of packing without compromising on style and hygiene.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have any great packing tips or recommendations? Let us know!!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow along on our journey by subscribing to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or by &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribing to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-ditch-the-clutter-and-travel-light.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/how-to-ditch-the-clutter-and-travel-light.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>travel-tips</category>
        
        <category>minimalism</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>10 Photos from Driving 10,000 Miles Across the US in 3 Months.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When we left our home in San Francisco, we weren’t sure where the road was going to take us, but we were dying to find out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we decided officially that we wanted to sell all of our posessions and live a nomadic lifstyle, we wanted to dip our toes in the water a bit. So, we decided to take an epic 3 month roadtrip around the country so we could get a taste of what it was really like to live out of a backpack and to travel full-time!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/road-trip-map.png&quot; alt=&quot;route across the usa&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our trip took us all around this huge country of ours. We met some amazing people and had experiences that we’ll take with us forever. We shucked oysters with the locals in Mississippi, cooked ribeye steaks with bonifide cowboys in Bandera, TX, snuck into an abandoned ghost town, and peered over the edge of the greatest expanse in the world, the Grand Canyon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/ally-grand-canyon.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Ally at grand canyon&quot; /&gt;
The Grand Canyon has to be seen to be believed. Peering over the edge and looking 6000 ft down just might change your life. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=QQTUyZF_1f0&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/texas-sunset.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sunset in texas&quot; /&gt;
We spent a lot of time in Texas and the sunsets never disappointed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-eric-big-bend.png&quot; alt=&quot;Big bend&quot; /&gt;
The beauty and epicness of Big Bend is hard to put into words. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Fr3DnW5qyXE&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/allison-sutro-baths-san-francisco.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sutro baths&quot; /&gt;
These once vibrant bath houses in west San Francisco have been reduced to ruins over the years. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=omOho20_RtQ&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/on-the-road.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;empty road&quot; /&gt;
The roads seem to go on forever over in western Texas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/dunes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Sand dunes&quot; /&gt;
These huge white sand dunes in New Mexico seem to come out of nowhere! Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=PCoXUeY9aKw&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/prada-marfa.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;prada store&quot; /&gt;
This random Prada store sits outside of Marfa, TX, literally in the middle of the desert. So strange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/beads.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mardi gras beads&quot; /&gt;
The aftermath of mardi gras in Baton Rouge, LA. It was an amazing party, but you wouldn’t believe the mess these people left behind! Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iM4zqlxLzEw&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/stone-mountain.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;rock in atlanta&quot; /&gt;
This huge rock sits just outside of Atlanta, GA and offers the most incredible view of the city and surrounding areas. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=k7ajq61CuRE&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/uploads/nyc-view.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;looking out at new york view&quot; /&gt;
The island of Manhattan is so photogenic. This was taken from the base of the Statue of Liberty, which offered some of the best views. Check out &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=UMWr6azqyOw&quot;&gt;that day’s vlog&lt;/a&gt; for an up close view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our road trip might be over but the adventure is just beginning! We’re heading over to Europe for the next few months, then we’ll slowly make our way over to southeast Asia. It’s going to be an amazing year!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can follow along on our journey by subscribing to our &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/c/TheEndlessAdventure?sub_confirmation=1&quot;&gt;YouTube Channel&lt;/a&gt; or by &lt;a href=&quot;http://conversational.us6.list-manage.com/subscribe?u=f210e827b5997f97a4c359077&amp;amp;id=cbb27cac9e&quot;&gt;subscribing to our blog&lt;/a&gt;. Thanks for reading, we’ll see you on the road!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Qm7a1IA7oQ8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Mar 2016 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/5-10-photos-driving-5000-miles-across-usa-3-months.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://theendlessadventure.co/travel/5-10-photos-driving-5000-miles-across-usa-3-months.html</guid>
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
        <category>road-trip</category>
        
        <category>lists</category>
        
        
        <category>travel</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
